<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Business</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/BUSINESS/index.html?eref=rss_business</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 22:27:20 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Business</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/BUSINESS/index.html?eref=rss_business</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_business" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_business"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Apple with iPad news?</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/08/tech/mobile/apple-ipad-october-event/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_business/~3/HPfLxKP8TPQ/index.html</link>
<description>The newest iPads could make their debut later this month.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_business/~4/HPfLxKP8TPQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 07:19:05 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/08/tech/mobile/apple-ipad-october-event/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Report: Apple announcing iPad news this month
By Heather Kelly, CNN
October 8, 2013 -- Updated 2316 GMT (0716 HKT) | Filed under: Mobile
The iPad Mini, left, next to the full-size, fourth-generation iPad. Apple unveiled both devices October 2012.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Report says Apple plans October 22 iPad event
Company could unveil an iPad Mini with retina display and a thinner full-sized iPad
Apple holds press events in October to get new products out in time for the holidays
(CNN) -- The newest iPads could make their debut later this month.
Apple is planning an October 22 press event to show off the latest additions to its iPad line, according to AllThingsD's John Paczkowski , confirming an earlier report in Current Editorials .
The announcements are expected to include a redesigned, thinner iPad and a Retina display iPad Mini. The devices would likely pack in the usual incremental improvements that mark each new generation of Apple mobile devices, including better cameras and faster processors. Apple's fancy new fingerprint technology might also make an appearance in the new iPads.
Apple has held a press event every October since 2010, announcing products that ship just in time for the holiday rush. Last year, Tim Cook introduced the iPad Mini, the full sized iPad with Retina display, and some new Macs.
It would not be unusual for the company to mix in some Mac news with the iPad announcements. The new Mac operating system, OS X Mavericks, was announced in June at the Apple Worldwide Developers Conference in San Francisco. The final version of the operating system has already shipped to developers, and it's likely it will be made available to the public soon after this press event.
Other Mac news could include the latest Macbook Pro and Mac Mini updates and a release date for the all new Mac Pro.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
