<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 18:31:40 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Football: More pain for England?</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/14/sport/football-brazil-world-cup-england/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/08pKR905C8M/index.html</link>
<description>England must defeat Poland in its final qualifying game Tuesday if it is to secure a place at next year's World Cup. It sounds simple enough -- but England has been here before....and failed.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/08pKR905C8M" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 17:21:05 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/14/sport/football-brazil-world-cup-england/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>World Cup 'worry' for England ahead of crucial Wembley clash
October 14, 2013 -- Updated 2119 GMT (0519 HKT)
England fans have endured years of misery at the World Cup.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
England will qualify for the 2014 World Cup with victory over Poland
Ukraine can take top spot if it beats San Marino and England loses
World Champion Spain expected to seal qualification
Iceland can secure a playoff spot with victory in Norway
(CNN) -- Where there should be excitement there is trepidation.
Where there is hope, there is also fear.
England expects -- but what it also anticipates is a night of high drama, tension and nails being bitten until they are no longer visible to the human eye.
When Roy Hodgson's side take to the turf at the iconic Wembley Stadium, the 'Home of Football', it will attempt to secure a victory which guarantees a place at next year's World Cup.
From civil war to the football pitch
Football comes to Buckingham Palace
Qatar 2022: Too hot for football?
One win is all that separates England from challenging the world's best in Brazil and yet it still seems so far away.
Perhaps it's not difficult to understand given the country's history and that painful night 40 years ago when England faltered in such agonizing fashion.
As on Tuesday, the opponent will once again be Poland.
It was Poland and their goalkeeper, Jan Tomaszewski who was infamously labeled a 'clown' by former Nottingham Forest and Derby manager Brian Clough ahead of the qualifier on October 17 1973, who proved the scourge of the Three Lions.
Indeed, it was the Poles who had the last laugh -- claiming a 1-1 draw to progress to the 1974 World Cup finals and leave England desolated.
Forget that Poland only had two efforts on goal to England's 36 or that the home side hit the woodwork twice and had four efforts cleared off the line.
Instead, that night is remembered as one of the most depressing in the history of English football.
Read: Rio home owners already renting properties for World Cup 2014
North Korean footballer big in Japan
Sami Khedira gave Germany an early lead against the Republic of Ireland as they booked their passage to the 2014 World Cup finals.
Romelu Lukaku scored both Belgium's goals in the 2-1 away win over Croatia which ensured their qualification for Brazil 2014.
Switzerland's Michael Lang scored the crucial second goal in their 2-1 win in Albania to clinch qualification for football's global showcase.
Ukraine's Andriy Yarmolenko celebrates his crucial goal as they beat Poland 1-0 in Kharkiv to keep alive their hopes of qualification from Group H.
Wayne Rooney made the much needed breakthrough for England against Montenegro at Wembley as they remained top of Group H with a 4-1 victory.
Alexander Samedov was on target for Russia as they boosted their qualification hopes with a 4-0 victory against minnows Luxembourg.
Robin van Persie scored a hat-trick in an 8-1 thrashing of Hungary by his Dutch team who have topped Group D.
German joy
&gt;&gt;
World Cup winners and losers
Mousa Dembele (right) is a key part of the Belgium side hoping to qualify for the 2014 World Cup in Brazil.
The Red Devils are unbeaten in World Cup qualifying, having won seven of their eight group games.
Romelu Lukaku is still only 20 but has already won 20 full international caps. Arguably the jewel in Belgium's emerging crop of stars, many observers think he is Chelsea's best striker, though he is spending this season on loan at Everton. Here Lukaku, who was born in Antwerp, celebrates after scoring against Newcastle in the English Premier League.
MIdfielder Marouane Fellaini played for Standard Liege before joining Everton. He left Goodison Park in August to join Manchester United, where he linked up again with former Everton manager David Moyes.
Alongside Fellaini in Belgium's midfield is Chelsea's Eden Hazard. French club Lille was key to Hazard's development and the midfielder spent five years with the Ligue 1 team before joining Chelsea.
Aston Villa striker Christian Benteke is Belgium's first-choice striker. He has scored four league goals this season and is pictured celebrating Villa's surprise 3-1 win over Arsenal on the opening day of the campaign.
Manchester City captain Vincent Kompany also skippers the Belgium national team. He began his professional career with Brussels club Anderlecht.
Kompany made his debut for Belgium in 2004 and has gone on to win over 50 caps for his country.
Napoli forward Dries Mertens (left) is one of the Belgium players to have worked under "brain coach" Michel Bruyninckx in the early stages of his career. The 26-year-old earned a move to Italy after impressing with Dutch club PSV Eindhoven last season.
Before coming to England, Dembele, who is now with Tottenham, played in both Belgium and Holland.
His first EPL club was Fulham, where manager Martin Jol described Dembele as "probably the best player on the ball I've ever seen."
Belgium' s World Cup Red Devils
Belgium' s World Cup Red Devils
Belgium' s World Cup Red Devils
Belgium' s World Cup Red Devils
Belgium' s World Cup Red Devils
Belgium' s World Cup Red Devils
Belgium' s World Cup Red Devils
Belgium' s World Cup Red Devils
Belgium' s World Cup Red Devils
Belgium' s World Cup Red Devils
Belgium' s World Cup Red Devils
HIDE CAPTION
&gt;&gt;
Belgium' s World Cup Red Devils
Once again it is Poland, which will be roared on by more than 18,000 fans, which stands in England's way -- a proposition which is enough to make England manager Roy Hodgson slightly nervous.
"I'm a worrier. I think anyone who works in football is a worrier," Hodgson told reporters.
"It won't be my best night's sleep because at the moment all of my waking thoughts are around England versus Poland.
"On the other hand, I have great faith and trust in the players. I don't think I can be putting a stronger bunch of players, a more confident bunch of players, onto the field.
"But football is not a science. If it was a science and based on logic and science, I think we would be 99% there.
"But it's not, it's a game and things can happen in games that you don't really want to happen and that's what makes you worried.
"It's not that you are worried the team is not capable, it's just that you are worried something untoward might happen."
Read: Your country needs YOU! But which country?'
England has performed inconsistently during its qualifying campaign, holding Ukraine to draws on two occasions, while also finishing level away in Poland and Montenegro.
Until Friday's 4-1 win over Montenegro, it had only managed to defeat minnows San Marino and Moldova -- a statistic which has left Tomaszewski unimpressed with England's current generation.
"Back then they (England) were one of the world's best teams, probably even the best," Tomaszewski told AFP
A turbulent period for FIFA began in May 2010. Whilst most of the world's soccer fans were more concerned with Africa's first World Cup finals that June, FIFA was presented with official bid documents by Australia, England, Netherlands/Belgium, Japan, South Korea, Qatar, Russia, Spain/Portugal and the United States for the 2018 and 2022 tournaments. During the ceremony at its Swiss headquarters, FIFA announced dates for inspections of the bidding nations from July-September.
British newspaper Mail On Sunday reveals that English bid leader David Triesman was secretly recorded making comments about alleged attempts by Spain and Russia to bribe referees at the imminent 2010 FIFA World Cup.
Russia's Prime Minister Vladimir Putin meets the visiting FIFA inspection team in Moscow. Qatar is the last country to receive the inspectors in September.
FIFA provisionally suspends Amos Adamu, pictured, and Reynald Temarii three days after Britain's Sunday Times newspaper claimed they offered to sell their World Cup votes. Adamu, head of the West Africa Football Union, denies the charge that he asked for $800,000 to be paid to him directly so four artificial pitches could be built in his native Nigeria. "I am confident that my actions, the full and true extent of which were not detailed in the story published, will demonstrate not only my innocence and integrity, but also my commitment to football and to FIFA," the 57-year-old says in a statement.
Temarii, a former Tahiti international player, is accused of asking for $2.4 million to build a youth academy for the Oceania Football Confederation, of which he has been head since 2004.
"It is a sad day for football," FIFA president Sepp Blatter, pictured here meeting British Prime Minister David Cameron a week earlier, tells reporters in Zurich.
FIFA releases its bid inspection reports, and it's bad news for Qatar. The tournament would be held in the middle of Qatar's summer where temperatures regularly hit 50 degrees Celsius. Despite a hi-tech pitch that included state-of-the-art cooling technology to keep players and fans safe, FIFA gave one part of the bid a "high" risk rating. In the report it stated that hosting the World Cup in June and July would be "considered as a potential health risk for players, officials, the FIFA family and spectators, and requires precautions to be taken".
FIFA confirms the suspension of executive committee members Amos Adamu and Reynald Temarii, along with four additional officials. Ahead of the December 2 ballot to decide the host of the 2018 and 2022 World Cup tournaments, Adamu receives a three-year ban and $11,947 fine and Temarii a 12-month ban and a $5,973 fine. However, the organization rules that there is no evidence to support allegations of collusion between rival bid teams. Adamu plans to appeal.
Issa Hayatou from Cameroon is one of three FIFA officials -- the others Nicolas Leoz from Paraguay and Ricardo Teixeira from Brazil -- who are named in a BBC program which alleges they took bribes from the ISL marketing company who secured World Cup rights in the 1990s. All three had votes voting in the December 2 decisions on the hosts for the 2018 and 2022 World Cups.
The International Olympic Committee announces it will launch an investigation into allegations on BBC's Panorama program that Issa Hayatou, who is also an IOC member, took bribes. Hayatou says he is considering legal action against the BBC. Football world governing body FIFA says the allegations have already been investigated and the matter is closed.
The winning bids for the 2018 and 2022 World Cup finals are announced. Russia wins the bid to host the 2018 tournament, with England garnering just two votes despite a last minute meet-and-greet blitz involving UK Prime Minister David Cameron, David Beckham and Prince William. But the big shock came when Blatter announced that Qatar would host the 2022 World Cup.
After months of speculation, Asian Football Confederation chief Mohamed bin Hammam announces he is to stand against Blatter in FIFA's presidential election. Bin Hammam, a Qatari, was a key figure in ensuring that Qatar won the right to host the 2022 World Cup.
Just a few weeks before FIFA's presidential vote, former FA chairman David Triesman gives evidence at a UK parliamentary enquiry into England's failed 2018 bid. Under the cover of parliamentary privilege Triesman accused FIFA Ex Co members Warner, Nicholas Leoz, Ricardo Texeira and Worawi Makudi of trying to secure cash and privileges in return for their vote. In other evidence submitted to the committee from the Sunday Times, it was alleged that FIFA vice-president Issa Hayatou along with fellow Ex Co member Jacques Anouma has been paid $1.5 million by Qatar for their World Cup vote. All those accused strenuously deny the allegations.
FIFA announces that it will expand its corruption probe to include Sepp Blatter, after AFC president Mohammed bin Hammam claimed Blatter knew about cash payments he was accused of giving to national football association in exchange for pro-Hammam votes during Qatar's 2022 World Cup bid. Blatter maintains that the allegations are "without substance", and is subsequently exonerated by FIFA's ethics committee two days later. Blatter later holds an extraordinary press conference where he tells the world's press: "Crisis? What is a crisis?!"
But FIFA's ethics committee upholds the complaints against Bin Hammam and Warner. Hammam is effectively barred from standing in the election. Warner's football "tsunami" turns out to be an email, which Warner releases to the press, where secretary general Jerome Valcke seems to suggest that Qatar "bought" the right to host the 2022 World Cup. After initially threatening legal action, Qatar withdraws its complaint when Valcke explains he was referring to Qatar's large, and legal, campaign budget, rather than bribes. Warner will face no further action following his resignation and the presumption of his innocence will remain.
Just a few days before the vote, both Warner and Blatter's presidential rival Mohamed Bin Hammam are suspended after fellow Ex Co member Chuck Blazer submits a report alleging that the two men paid $40,000 worth of bribes to secure the support of members of the Caribbean Football Union. Both deny the claims, with Warner promising a "tsunami" of revelations to clear his name.
Despite a last minute attempt by the English FA to postpone the vote - a proposal which garnered just 17 out of the available 208 votes -Sepp Blatter is re-elected for a fourth term as president of FIFA at the 61st FIFA Congress at Hallenstadion in Zurich. He vows to learn from past mistakes and undertake a reform agenda.
Former head of the Asian Football Confederation Mohamed Bin Hammam was banned for life by FIFA after a two-day hearing into bribery allegations.
Chuck Blazer announces he will step down from his role as general secretary of CONCACAF at the end of the year. American Blazer was one of the men who voted on the location for both the 2018 and 2022 World Cups.
FIFA president Sepp Blatter announces the introduction of four new task forces and a "Committee of Good Governance" aimed at reforming the organization and repairing its reputation.
May 14, 2010
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
