<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 18:31:40 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>The rising force in world football?</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/10/sport/football/football-belgium-dembele-world-cup/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/KoOc-mIivSA/index.html</link>
<description>France's multicultural stars shone brightest at the World Cup 15 years ago -- now could it be Belgium's turn to do the same in Brazil next year?&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/KoOc-mIivSA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 07:10:48 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/10/sport/football/football-belgium-dembele-world-cup/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Belgium is considered one of the dark horses to win the World Cup in Brazil
Nation has one of the most gifted squads in football thanks to outstanding youth program
Can qualify for the 2014 tournament on Friday night with draw in Croatia
Dembele believes his side can do 'something special' next July
(CNN) -- One country, two languages -- and one dream of winning the World Cup.
If Belgium is divided by the Flemish speakers who live in the north and the French-speaking Walloons in the south, the nation's footballers are united with one goal.
And with its place at the 2014 World Cup finals almost secure, midfielder Mousa Dembele believes Belgium's multicultural array of stars can follow in the footsteps of France's 1998 winning team.
Like Les Bleus -- a team which included players of African and Caribbean heritage -- Belgium's class of 2013 has a cosmopolitan feel.
Striker Christian Benteke was born in Kinshasa, Congo, while the likes of Manchester City captain Vincent Kompany and Chelsea striker Romelu Lukaku are both of Congolese heritage.
Kompany's meteoric rise to the top
Kompany on grooming the next generation
Kompany on future ambitions
Then there is Manchester United's Marouane Fellaini, who along with Tottenham's Nacer Chadli and 17-year-old starlet Zakaria Bakkali is of Moroccan descent.
Read: Will Belgium win the World Cup?
Dembele himself was born in Belgium after his father moved from Mali -- of which he remains proud.
And while the 26-year-old considers himself Belgian, he believes the ethnic mix within the team has made his time in the national setup a more enjoyable experience.
"We get on very well, I think," Dembele told CNN ahead of Friday's trip to Croatia, where a draw will be enough to clinch Belgium's 2014 place as winner of Group A with a match to spare.
"It makes us strong. We have all kinds of players and perhaps you can compare us to the France side which won the World Cup in 1998.
"I think it's fair to say we're like them. Perhaps you could say we're also like Germany in a way.
"With Germany, you can see there's a real mix of nationalities in their team. I like that approach because I'm of mixed nationality myself."
It's a nuanced response from Dembele and contrasts sharply with the view of Arsenal midfielder Jack Wilshere, who said this week only English people should play for England.
While the Belgium players remain united, the team will often arrange separate interviews for Flemish and French speakers.
Arsenal defender Thomas Vermaelen will speak to the press in Flemish, while Zenit St. Petersburg midfielder Axel Witsel, whose father came from the Caribbean island of Martinique, will give his thoughts in French.
Vincent Kompany enjoys the lifestyle which comes with being a modern millionaire footballer. But, despite rising to the top of his sport, the Belgian remains grounded and committed to education.
Kompany made his Anderlecht debut in 2003. The defensive player had been with the club's academy since 2000 and went on to win the Belgian Championship with the team in 2004 and 2006.
Kompany made his debut for the national team in 2004 in a friendly match against France. He is pictured here tackling legendary French playmaker Zinedine Zidane.
His performances earned him a move to German club Hamburg in 2006. A serious achilles injury limited Kompany to just six appearances in his first season in Germany.
After just two seasons with Hamburg, Kompany made the move to Manchester City in 2008.
Kompany was consistently excellent for the Abu Dhabi-owned club and was one of the team's standout performers as they beat Stoke City 1-0 to win the FA Cup in 2011.
The highlight of Kompany's career to date arrived in May 2012. A goal from Sergio Aguero deep into injury time gave City a 3-2 win over Queens Park Rangers and secured the team a first league title in 44 years. As captain, Kompany was the man who lifted the trophy.
Manuel Pellegrini was appointed as City manager in May following the sacking of Roberto Mancini. The Chilean is the third different manager Kompany has worked under during five years in Manchester.
In good Kompany
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
