<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 19:13:44 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Spears' new album gets a title</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/10/15/showbiz/music/britney-spears-new-album-ew/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/1NYj1QHqD3c/index.html</link>
<description>Britney Spears has revealed that her new album, which will be out December 3, is called "Britney Jean."&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/1NYj1QHqD3c" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 12:29:34 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/10/15/showbiz/music/britney-spears-new-album-ew/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Britney Spears' new album gets a title
By Kyle Anderson, EW.com
October 15, 2013 -- Updated 1626 GMT (0026 HKT)
Britney Spears is releasing her next album, "Britney Jean," on December 3.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Britney Spears' new album will be called "Britney Jean"
"Jean" is Spears' real middle name, and her family calls her "Britney Jean"
Spears: "It's a personal album ... and I wanted to share that with my fans"
"Britney Jean" is due to arrive December 3
( EW.com ) -- Perhaps it's just the nature of the cycles of pop music, but doesn't it seem like Britney Spears has been gone for a while?
Her last album, "Femme Fatale," came out in 2011, but for some reason it seems like she's been missing in action for twice that time.
Regardless, Brit is back with a vengeance. Her new album's first single and video, "Work B***h," has already dropped, and yesterday she revealed that the new collection, which will be out December 3, is called "Britney Jean."
Before you go assuming that she's making some sort of awesome meta-allusion to Michael Jackson's "Billie Jean," just know that "Jean" is actually Spears' given middle name.
Is Britney Spears too sexy for a mom?
Check out Britney Spears' racy video
Call the governor, Britney Spears lives fancy in 'Work B***h'
"It's a personal album, and all my family, they all call me Britney Jean, it's like a term of endearment, and I just wanted to share that with my fans," she told London's Capital FM yesterday.
Other details are relatively scarce, though we do know that Will.i.am is serving as executive producer and that "Work B***h" doesn't necessarily represent the album as a whole.
Is Britney Spears' 'Work B***h' video too sexual? Director weighs in
"That song is a reflection of Britney moreso than the album," Will told Billboard. "The album is what the album is, but we felt that song needed to come out to keep the foundation on what Britney represents. But it shouldn't reflect the album—an album is a body of work as a collective. If we had to pick a song like, 'Oh, what song fits every color of the record,' you shouldn't do that... We felt that song represents 'Piece of Me,' that Britney oomph."
CLICK HERE to Try 2 RISK FREE issues of Entertainment Weekly
© 2011 Entertainment Weekly and Time Inc. All rights reserved.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
