<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2015 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 21:04:52 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 21:04:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Airbus patent detaches cabin from plane</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4bdb6354/sc/15/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A150C110C270Ceurope0Cairbus0Edetachable0Ecabin0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Itech/story01.htm</link>
<description>Plane manufacturers have come up with some interesting ideas. The latest: Turn cabins -- the part where you sit -- into detachable modules separate from the planes. Then mix and match 'em, and you save all kinds of time and money, Airbus says.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159882598/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bdb6354/sc/15/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159882598/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bdb6354/sc/15/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159882598/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bdb6354/sc/15/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159882598/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bdb6354/sc/15/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159882598/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bdb6354/sc/15/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159882598/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bdb6354/sc/15/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/244159882598/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bdb6354/sc/15/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/244159882598/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bdb6354/sc/15/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/244159882598/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bdb6354/sc/15/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/244159882598/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bdb6354/sc/15/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/244159882598/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bdb6354/sc/15/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/244159882598/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bdb6354/sc/15/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4bdb6354/sc/15/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 15:57:41 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2015/11/27/europe/airbus-detachable-cabin/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/151127055126-airbus-detachable-cabin-separate-plane-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/151127055126-airbus-detachable-cabin-separate-plane-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>If the cabin is detached, the plane can be used for other things during boarding
Airports would have to be redesigned to adapt to the model
(CNN)
Squeezing out a net profit is tough in the airline business. And while straining to do so, plane manufacturers have come up with some interesting ideas.
The latest: Turn cabins -- the part of the plane where you sit -- into detachable modules separate from the planes. Then mix 'em and match 'em, and you save all kinds of time and money, says Airbus, which got a U.S. patent on the idea this week.
But first, back to those profits. With the peppery price of a plane ticket, you don't believe it, eh?
Currently, airlines pocket an average of $8.27 per passenger, said the International Air Transport Association. And that's a recent improvement, thanks to falling fuel prices and a rebounding economy.
Airplane manufacturer Airbus has patented a modular system, where the cabin is detached from the plane during boarding.
Weird, uncomfortable seats
Read More
Remember the recent weird patents for cramped plane seats ? Bicycle-style stools, passenger seats piled on top of each other, dividers that you lean against instead of sitting on? Those patents pinch pennies by cramming more passengers into a cabin.
But the new detachable cabin model and its potential accomplishments are much more complex, Airbus said in its new patent filing, which was entered in February but granted this week. A report about it was first published in Wired.
Here's how the idea works.
Instead of boarding a whole plane, passengers climb into the detached cabin, which is suspended in a dock at the gate on crane-like arms.
6 photos: Aircraft manufacturers have some wild inventions in the works
Windowless cockpits, Airbus – Last year, Airbus filed a patent that totally reimagines the concept of the cockpit. For starters, the cockpit would move away from a window. Instead, the patent floats the idea of the cockpit being stored underneath the cabin or at the back of the plane. This would allow the nose of the plane to be longer, pointier, and hence more aerodynamic. Pilots would glimpse the world outside using a digital display.
Hide Caption
1 of 6
6 photos: Aircraft manufacturers have some wild inventions in the works
Smart windows, Airbus – According to a patent filed in March , passengers may one day be able to use their window as an interactive touchscreen. Theoretically, fliers could pull up information on a major landmark as they pass over it, or maybe even prompt access to a complimentary media library -- fly over the Empire State building while watching "Sleepless in Seattle" perhaps?
Hide Caption
2 of 6
6 photos: Aircraft manufacturers have some wild inventions in the works
Flying donut, Airbus – Evoking Candy Land, Airbus filed a patent last year for this confectionery-shaped aircraft -- complete with a hole in the middle. Though unusual-looking, the ring shape actually makes good sense. According to the patent application, it allows for more passengers than traditional, tube-shaped aircrafts can fit in, and distributes cabin pressure more evenly, ultimately decreasing stress to the structure.
Hide Caption
3 of 6
6 photos: Aircraft manufacturers have some wild inventions in the works
Virtual reality IFE, Airbus – In-flight entertainment may soon evolve from glitchy headphones and seatback screens. If a patent Airbus filed last August is anything to go by, we may all find ourselves fully immersed in the movie (or video game, or concert) with the help of virtual reality helmets (that patent even hints there may be an olfactory function). The patent states the helmets would provide "sensorial isolation," thereby reducing stress for nervous flyers.
Hide Caption
4 of 6
6 photos: Aircraft manufacturers have some wild inventions in the works
Terrorist trap door, Airbus – In 2002, Airbus filed a patent for a trap door positioned outside of the cockpit. Theoretically, should a terrorist or hijacker try to force their way into the cockpit, a trap door would open and send them into a security cell underneath the cabin floor.
Hide Caption
5 of 6
6 photos: Aircraft manufacturers have some wild inventions in the works
Force field, Boeing – In 2012, USPTO granted Boeing a patent for what is basically a force field (think Star Trek deflector shields). The device, according to the patent, would detect the shockwave from a nearby explosion and create what is essentially a plasma field to protect against the oncoming blast.
Hide Caption
6 of 6
The whole time people are heaving carry-ons and shimmying into seats, the rest of the plane can be away from the gate, getting more fuel or a mechanical check. It's not stuck waiting for passengers to get settled.
And stepping aboard would be a breeze for passengers, since the cabin floor would be flush with a floor at the gate.
"Transfer of passengers, luggage or freight can thus be accomplished optimally, and in particular without using a staircase or a lift or elevator," the patent filing read.
Then, there's reality
Waiting areas at gates would hardly be necessary anymore, since people would directly seat themselves in the modules. That would also save boarding time, and security checks could be run incrementally, as passengers arrived at the cabin.
Cabin modules could also be customized to hold freight, so the underlying planes could be used to transport both people and product.
The cockpit would be solidly attached to the plane part, rather than the cabin module, so pilots could steer the plane around on the ground as needed.
JUST WATCHED
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
