<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2015 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 21:04:52 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 21:04:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Russia, the Internet and new way to wage war?</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4b13cdb8/sc/28/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A150C10A0C280Copinions0Crushkoff0Einternet0Ecables0Erussia0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Itech/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/243659530372/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4b13cdb8/sc/28/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/243659530372/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4b13cdb8/sc/28/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/243659530372/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4b13cdb8/sc/28/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/243659530372/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4b13cdb8/sc/28/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/243659530372/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4b13cdb8/sc/28/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/243659530372/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4b13cdb8/sc/28/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/243659530372/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4b13cdb8/sc/28/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/243659530372/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4b13cdb8/sc/28/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/243659530372/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4b13cdb8/sc/28/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/243659530372/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4b13cdb8/sc/28/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/243659530372/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4b13cdb8/sc/28/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/243659530372/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4b13cdb8/sc/28/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4b13cdb8/sc/28/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 17:43:26 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2015/10/28/opinions/rushkoff-internet-cables-russia/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/151007151454-russian-missile-ship-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/151007151454-russian-missile-ship-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Facebook Twitter Instagram
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ad_bnr_atf_01" class="ad-ad_bnr_atf_01 ad-refresh-adbanner"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Russia, the Internet and a new way to wage war?
By Douglas Rushkoff
Updated 0133 GMT (0933 HKT) October 29, 2015
JUST WATCHED
Russians hovering near Internet cables? 02:09
Story highlights
Douglas Rushkoff: NYT report on Russian ships operating over deep-sea Internet cables raises issue of new ways nations can wage "war"
He says Russian economy needs Internet as much as the West, and we need new rules on use and abuse of world's shared resources
Douglas Rushkoff, a media theorist and professor of media studies at the City University of New York's Queens College, writes a regular column for CNN.com. He is the author of the book "Present Shock: When Everything Happens Now," and of the forthcoming book "Throwing Rocks at the Google Bus: How Growth Became the Enemy of Prosperity" (March 2016, Penguin). The opinions expressed are solely those of the author.
(CNN)
According to a report in The New York Times this week , the presence of Russian spy ships near important trans-Atlantic data cables is causing consternation among American military and intelligence officials. What, if anything, are the Russians planning to do? Are they trying to see how easily they could cut the cables if war broke out?
Douglas Rushkoff
All anybody knows for sure is that the game theory that we used to plot out provocations and responses during the Cold War is obsolete in a digital age.
On the one hand, concerns about acts of digital sabotage in wartime are silly. If war broke out between the United States and Russia, we'd have much bigger problems on our hands than spotty connectivity over the Internet. Sure, it would put a serious dent in Internet-based communications, international banking and a host of other rather essential digital traffic. But unless an enemy shot our satellites out of the sky, the military could maintain basic command and control without the Internet.
JUST WATCHED
MUST WATCH
Will Russia adopt China's 'Internet sovereignty' rule? 01:10
On the other hand, the genuine threat here is that the Internet offers a new way for superpowers to, in theory, wage war without blowing up the whole planet. Tactically, an offensive against a Western data pipeline would be more like an extreme embargo. It would be nasty and debilitating, but it doesn't necessarily call for nuclear retaliation.
It's a way to cause pain without bombing cities or launching the kinds of assaults that demand an escalation of violence. Like the recent hack of U.S. government employee files, presumably by China , it's a meaningful attack but in a virtual realm, making it hard to gauge an appropriate response.
Read More
That's why this alleged saber rattling (or actually wire-cutter rattling) makes us nervous. It suggests a whole new range of potential engagements for which we need to establish new protocols. And fast.
21 photos: Cult of Putin
While his nation waded deeper into the Syrian civil war, Russian President Vladimir Putin, right, spent his 63rd birthday on the ice Wednesday, October 7, playing hockey with NHL stars and various Russian officials and tycoons in Sochi.  For years, Russia's leader has cultivated a populist image in the Russian media.
Hide Caption
1 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin holds a cat as he inspects housing built for victims of wildfires in the village of Krasnopolye, in a region in southeastern Siberia, Russia, on Friday, September 4.
Hide Caption
2 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin, left, and Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev jokingly toast at a lunch during a meeting at the Black Sea resort in Sochi, Russia, on Sunday, August 30.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin exercises during his meeting with Medvedev on  August 30.
Hide Caption
4 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin sits in a bathyscaphe as it plunges into the Black Sea along the coast of Sevastopol, Crimea, on Tuesday, August 18. Putin went underwater to see the wreckage of an ancient merchant ship that was found in the end of May.
Hide Caption
5 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin holds a Persian leopard cub in February 2014 at a breeding and rehabilitation center in the Black Sea resort of Sochi. Perhaps the most important vote in Russia's public selection of a new Olympic mascot was cast when Putin said he wanted a funky leopard to represent the 2014 Sochi Winter Games.
Hide Caption
6 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin holds a pike he caught in the Siberian Tuva region of Russia on July 20, 2013.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin enjoys some fishing during his vacation to the Tuva region on July 20, 2013.
Hide Caption
8 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin submerges on board Sea Explorer 5 bathyscaphe near the isle of Gogland in the Gulf of Finland on July 15, 2013.
Hide Caption
9 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin studies a crane during an experiment called Flight of Hope on September 5, 2012, in which he piloted a hang glider, aiming to lead the birds into flight. It's part of a project to save the rare species of crane.
Hide Caption
10 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin takes part in a training session for young ice hockey players before the "Golden Puck" youth tournament final in Moscow on April 15, 2011.
Hide Caption
11 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin rides a Harley-Davidson to an international biker convention in southern Ukraine on July 14, 2010.
Hide Caption
12 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
The Russian president aims at a whale with an arbalest (crossbow) to take a piece of its skin for analysis at Olga Bay on August 25, 2010.
Hide Caption
13 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
A wetsuit-clad Putin embarks on a dive to an underwater archaeological site at Phanagoria on the Taman Peninsula on August 10, 2011.
Hide Caption
14 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Famed for his love of martial arts, Putin throws a competitor in a judo session at an athletics school in St. Petersburg on December 18, 2009.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin during his vacation in southern Siberia on August 3, 2009.
Hide Caption
16 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin swims the butterfly during his vacation outside the town of Kyzyl in southern Siberia on August 3, 2009.
Hide Caption
17 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Assisted by a Russian scientist, Putin fixes a satellite transmitter to a tiger during his visit to the Ussuriysky forest reserve of the Russian Academy of Sciences in the Far East on August 31, 2008.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin carries a hunting rifle in the Republic of Tuva on September 3, 2007.
Hide Caption
19 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
A shirtless Putin fishing in the headwaters of the Yenisei River in the Republic of Tuva on August 13, 2007.
Hide Caption
20 of 21
21 photos: Cult of Putin
Putin in the cockpit of a Tupolev Tu-160 strategic bomber jet at a military airport on August 16, 2005, before his supersonic flight.
Hide Caption
21 of 21
What makes this difficult is that -- at least from our point of view -- an attack on the Internet wouldn't really be an attack on America so much as an attack on the free world. Europe's objections to National Security Agency and corporate surveillance notwithstanding, the Internet wires us all together in one big family of Western corporate media companies, free expression and democratic governance.
From the perspective of a downsized Russia attempting to reassert its former nationalist and hierarchical glory, the Internet is just an extension of American imperialism. Google, Facebook, Twitter, Yahoo, Apple, and Intel are all essentially American companies, and their platforms and devices are embedded with the values of free market capitalism.
Russia's oligarchy may not realistically want to restore the entirety of the former Soviet Union, but it does want to maintain an entirely less open and fluid order -- one it sees threatened by the spread of the Western market, ideology and, yes, Internet, through Europe and beyond.
JUST WATCHED
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
