<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Post Politics: Breaking Politics News, Political Analysis &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics?wprss=rss_politics</link>
<description>Post Politics from The Washington Post is the source for political news headlines, in-depth politics coverage and political opinion, plus breaking news on the Obama administration and White House, Congress, the Supreme Court, elections and more.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 04:18:55 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 04:18:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Post Politics: Breaking Politics News, Political Analysis &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics?wprss=rss_politics</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>National Digest: 63 Ohio patrol officers receive suspensions</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636655/s/32807165/sc/11/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cpolitics0Cnational0Edigest0E630Eohio0Epatrol0Eofficers0Ereceive0Esuspensions0C20A130C10A0C150C7fe9bebe0E35d60E11e30Ebe860E6aeaa439845b0Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Ipolitics/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;OHIO&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;63 patrol officers&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;receive suspensions&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A review of a deadly police chase in Cleveland nearly a year ago has led to suspensions for 63 patrol officers who violated orders and department rules, the city’s police chief said Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/national-digest-63-ohio-patrol-officers-receive-suspensions/2013/10/15/7fe9bebe-35d6-11e3-be86-6aeaa439845b_story.html?wprss=rss_politics"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636655/s/32807165/sc/11/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;div class='mf-viral'&gt;&lt;table border='0'&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td valign='middle'&gt;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/twitter/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fpolitics%2Fnational-digest-63-ohio-patrol-officers-receive-suspensions%2F2013%2F10%2F15%2F7fe9bebe-35d6-11e3-be86-6aeaa439845b_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_politics&amp;t=National+Digest%3A+63+Ohio+patrol+officers+receive+suspensions" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/twitter.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/facebook/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fpolitics%2Fnational-digest-63-ohio-patrol-officers-receive-suspensions%2F2013%2F10%2F15%2F7fe9bebe-35d6-11e3-be86-6aeaa439845b_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_politics&amp;t=National+Digest%3A+63+Ohio+patrol+officers+receive+suspensions" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/facebook.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/linkedin/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fpolitics%2Fnational-digest-63-ohio-patrol-officers-receive-suspensions%2F2013%2F10%2F15%2F7fe9bebe-35d6-11e3-be86-6aeaa439845b_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_politics&amp;t=National+Digest%3A+63+Ohio+patrol+officers+receive+suspensions" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/linkedin.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/gplus/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fpolitics%2Fnational-digest-63-ohio-patrol-officers-receive-suspensions%2F2013%2F10%2F15%2F7fe9bebe-35d6-11e3-be86-6aeaa439845b_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_politics&amp;t=National+Digest%3A+63+Ohio+patrol+officers+receive+suspensions" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/googleplus.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/email/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fpolitics%2Fnational-digest-63-ohio-patrol-officers-receive-suspensions%2F2013%2F10%2F15%2F7fe9bebe-35d6-11e3-be86-6aeaa439845b_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_politics&amp;t=National+Digest%3A+63+Ohio+patrol+officers+receive+suspensions" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/email.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965912814/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/32807165/sc/11/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965912814/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/32807165/sc/11/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965912814/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/32807165/sc/11/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965912814/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/32807165/sc/11/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965912814/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/32807165/sc/11/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965912814/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/32807165/sc/11/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965912814/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/32807165/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965912814/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/32807165/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/176965912814/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/32807165/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description>
<category domain="">Facebook</category>
<category domain="">Nancy A. Michael</category>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 23:44:32 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/national-digest-63-ohio-patrol-officers-receive-suspensions/2013/10/15/7fe9bebe-35d6-11e3-be86-6aeaa439845b_story.html?wprss=rss_politics</guid>
<dc:creator/>
<ExtractedText>National Digest: 63 Ohio patrol officers receive suspensions
OHIO
63 patrol officers
receive suspensions
A review of a deadly police chase in Cleveland nearly a year ago has led to suspensions for 63 patrol officers who violated orders and department rules, the city’s police chief said Tuesday.
A fleeing driver and passenger were killed when officers fired 137 shots at them in the
23-minute chase that involved five dozen cruisers and wove through residential neighborhoods before ending in gunfire.
An initial review of the chase found 75 patrol officers violated orders, but the disciplinary hearings reduced that number to 64 officers. All but one received a suspension, with the longest being 10 days, Police Chief Michael McGrath said.
Police previously announced punishments for 12 supervisors stemming from the chase. One sergeant was fired. A captain and lieutenant were demoted, and nine sergeants were suspended.
— Associated Press
FLORIDA
Facebook post leads to arrest of two girls
Two Florida girls who were primarily responsible for bullying a 12-year-old girl who killed herself were arrested after one of them acknowledged the harassment online, police said Tuesday.
Police in central Florida have been investigating the death of 12-year-old Rebecca Sedwick, who climbed a tower at an abandoned concrete plant Sept. 9 and hurled herself to her death. Authorities said as many as 15 girls may have bullied Rebecca, and the investigation was continuing.
Polk County Sheriff Grady Judd said the arrests of the girls, ages 14 and 12, were hastened when the older girl posted Saturday on Facebook, saying she bullied Rebecca but she didn’t care.
The 14-year-old girl was accused of threatening to beat up Rebecca while they were sixth-graders at Crystal Lake Middle Schoo in Lakeland, telling her “to drink bleach and die” and saying she should kill herself, the sheriff said.
Both girls were charged as juveniles with third-degree felony aggravated stalking.
— Associated Press
TEXAS
Student fatally shoots self at his high school
A Texas high school student shot himself to death in the courtyard of his public school during the lunch hour on Tuesday, school officials said.
The student, whose name and age were not released, died at 12:04 p.m. local time after shooting himself at Lanier High School in Austin, a spokeswoman for the Austin Independent School District said.
No other students were harmed, officials said.
The school was placed on lockdown briefly following the incident, and students were released for the day soon afterward, she said.
Officials declined to say how the student obtained the gun and was able to bring it onto campus. Many Austin schools were built in the 1970s, and most of the structures are not equipped with metal detectors, Young said.
— Reuters
NEW YORK
Police union wants end to specific law
New York City’s biggest police union asked a court Tuesday to nix a law that would make it easier for people to bring racial profiling lawsuits, saying it would cast a cloud of doubt over officers’ conduct.
The measure is too vague, “leaves officers to guess” what’s allowed and threatens to taint the entire New York Police Department with a brush of discrimination, the Patrolmen’s Benevolent Association said in the lawsuit filed against the City Council.
The City Council said it would vigorously fight the suit, which furthers a debate that moved quickly from City Hall to court after lawmakers’ August vote to override Mayor Michael Bloomberg’s veto. Bloomberg filed his own suit against the law last month; the Sergeants Benevolent Association, which represents 13,000 NYPD supervisors, is seeking court permission to join that lawsuit on the mayor’s side.
The law, set to take effect late next month, eases some legal standards for claims that stop and frisk and other techniques were used in a biased way. Such lawsuits can seek policy changes but not money.
— Associated Press
Labor dispute suspected in LAX dry-ice blasts: Police believe two dry ice explosions at Los Angeles International Airport were triggered by a disgruntled employee and were not an act of terror. Deputy Chief Michael Downing said the bombs made by putting dry ice in 20-ounce bottles could have caused serious injury to anyone in close proximity, though no one was hurt. Police have no specific suspect yet but believe the explosions were part of a labor dispute. One device exploded in an employee men’s room Sunday. An exploded bottle was found that night on the tarmac near the international terminal, but an employee threw it away. The same employee found an unexploded bottle Monday evening and then reported his earlier find.
— Associated Press
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
