<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 18:31:40 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Football: World Cup joy for Bosnia </title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/15/sport/world-cup-football-brazil/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/Cl2eGdv9eaw/index.html</link>
<description>Bosnia-Herzegovina makes history Tuesday after qualifying for the World Cup for the first time in the nation's history.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/Cl2eGdv9eaw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 18:29:56 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/15/sport/world-cup-football-brazil/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>World Cup joy for Bosnia as fairytale ending comes true
October 15, 2013 -- Updated 2245 GMT (0645 HKT)
Bosnian football fans celebrated their team's heroics by partying in Sarajevo.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Bosnia-Herzegovina reaches World Cup finals for first time in country's history
England makes it through following home victory over Poland
Spain, Russia, Romania all seal place at next year's tournament
France, Portugal, Iceland all qualify for playoff stage
(CNN) -- Bosnia-Herzegovina made history Tuesday after qualifying for the World Cup for the first time in the nation's history.
Vedad Ibisevic's strike gave his country a 1-0 win over Lithuania in Kaunas to ensure his team will compete at next year's tournament in Brazil.
It was in 1995 that Bosnia played its first match as an independent nation following the break up of Yugoslavia.
Twice it has come close to reaching major tournaments, losing out to Portugal on both occasions in the 2010 World Cup and 2012 European Championship playoffs.
"I congratulate these guys for their great work in the last four years, and it would have been real injustice if we had failed to win the group and qualify for the World Cup," coach Safet Susic told Bosnia media.
From civil war to the football pitch
The business behind the World Cup
Qatar 2022: Too hot for football?
The victory sparked wild scenes of jubilation in Sarajevo where fans celebrated with fireworks and chanting following the result.
Manchester City striker Edin Dzeko said: "I wish to send my regards to Brazil and say that we will show how mighty Bosnia is."
Elsewhere, England booked its place in Brazil with an impressive 2-0 victory over Poland at Wembley.
Wayne Rooney and Steven Gerrard were both on target in an entertaining affair.
Already qualified for 2014 World Cup
Brazil (hosts)
England
Spain
It means Ukraine will have to negotiate the playoffs with England able to relax -- much to the relief of manager Roy Hodgson.
"I'm greatly satisfied," Hodgson told ITV.
"It was a tough group, both Montenegro and Poland showed themselves to be great opponents both home and away.
"We played some sensational football in the first half and we dug in very well and controlled them in the second.
"We always said that if we could get to the last two games, we'd be stronger and have players coming back.
"We've found a winger in Andros Townsend who looks as though he's been playing there (international football) all his life. He's going to be under a lot of pressure now but he's a level headed young man and he'll deal with it.
"We've been working together for 18 months and the way we play has changed. We're getting better all the time and hopefully will get better still. The players really are a group and they trust each other."
Read: Quartet on their way to World Cup finals
Manchester United midfielder Michael Carrick was given a place in the starting line up in place of Frank Lampard and played a key role in his side's success.
"We did everything we wanted to in the first half. Second half, they came out and created chances straight away," he told the BBC.
"We stayed strong and saw it through. At 1-0, sometimes you get caught in between getting another goal and holding on.
Eto'o: Money doesn't motivate me
Sami Khedira gave Germany an early lead against the Republic of Ireland as they booked their passage to the 2014 World Cup finals.
Romelu Lukaku scored both Belgium's goals in the 2-1 away win over Croatia which ensured their qualification for Brazil 2014.
Switzerland's Michael Lang scored the crucial second goal in their 2-1 win in Albania to clinch qualification for football's global showcase.
Ukraine's Andriy Yarmolenko celebrates his crucial goal as they beat Poland 1-0 in Kharkiv to keep alive their hopes of qualification from Group H.
Wayne Rooney made the much needed breakthrough for England against Montenegro at Wembley as they remained top of Group H with a 4-1 victory.
Alexander Samedov was on target for Russia as they boosted their qualification hopes with a 4-0 victory against minnows Luxembourg.
Robin van Persie scored a hat-trick in an 8-1 thrashing of Hungary by his Dutch team who have topped Group D.
German joy
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
