<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Business</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/BUSINESS/index.html?eref=rss_business</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 09:41:57 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Business</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/BUSINESS/index.html?eref=rss_business</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_business" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_business"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>10 best countries to start a business</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/01/business/10-best-places-to-start/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_business/~3/1F4Ct7up15o/index.html</link>
<description>New Zealand tops the list as the easiest place to start a small and medium-sized enterprise, according to the World Bank's most recent report.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_business/~4/1F4Ct7up15o" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 05:16:50 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/01/business/10-best-places-to-start/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>10 best places to start a business
By Vanessa Ko, for CNN
October 4, 2013 -- Updated 1252 GMT (2052 HKT)
This is the second consecutive year that New Zealand has come first in the World Bank ranking. After registering a company name online, entrepreneurs can apply for tax-related accounts and incorporate the company at the same time.
Australia made starting a business cheaper a few years ago by lowering the registration fee. It now costs 426 Australian dollars (US$390).
Starting a business in Canada takes one online application, and five days for the company to receive the business number, according to the report.
One of the three steps of starting a business in Singapore is the traditional requirement of making a company seal, an ink stamp used as a signature on numerous documents.
Over the past five years, Macedonia has simplified the process of establishing a business by lowering capital requirements, reducing application procedures and time, and improving its online one-stop shop.
In addition to registering the company and creating a rubber stamp, Hong Kong requires companies to sign up for an insurance policy and for the local pension fund.
Georgia has removed layers of red tape in recent years, now requiring registration and opening a new bank account, which are expected to take two days.
Although it is not particularly easy to do business in Rwanda overall, it is relatively simple to start a company. The only requirement is to registering the business, which is free of charge if it is done online, and the certificate is ready in one to three days.
Launching a business in Belarus takes five days, about a third of the average time in Eastern Europe and Central Asia. It also does not require entrepreneurs put in a minimum capital.
The first step in opening a business in Ireland is for a company founder to swear that the company has complied with relevant laws.
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
