<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 15:23:46 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 15:23:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>NFL Commissioner Roger Goodell says ‘game is safer and more exciting today than ever’</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/32081f1e/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Cnfl0Ecommissioner0Eroger0Egoodell0Esays0Egame0Eis0Esafer0Eand0Emore0Eexciting0Etoday0Ethan0Eever0C20A130C10A0C0A30C1f0A0A30A70A0E2c7a0E11e30E8ade0Ea1f23cda135e0Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The e-mails began landing in inboxes early Thursday morning, the latest message of progress and change from NFL Commissioner Roger Goodell. “The NFL season is off to another exciting and competitive start,” the more than 1,000-word letter began. “I want to thank you and all NFL fans for your passionate support.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/nfl-commissioner-roger-goodell-says-game-is-safer-and-more-exciting-today-than-ever/2013/10/03/1f003070-2c7a-11e3-8ade-a1f23cda135e_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/32081f1e/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;div class='mf-viral'&gt;&lt;table border='0'&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td valign='middle'&gt;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/twitter/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fnfl-commissioner-roger-goodell-says-game-is-safer-and-more-exciting-today-than-ever%2F2013%2F10%2F03%2F1f003070-2c7a-11e3-8ade-a1f23cda135e_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=NFL+Commissioner+Roger+Goodell+says+%E2%80%98game+is+safer+and+more+exciting+today+than+ever%E2%80%99" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/twitter.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/facebook/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fnfl-commissioner-roger-goodell-says-game-is-safer-and-more-exciting-today-than-ever%2F2013%2F10%2F03%2F1f003070-2c7a-11e3-8ade-a1f23cda135e_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=NFL+Commissioner+Roger+Goodell+says+%E2%80%98game+is+safer+and+more+exciting+today+than+ever%E2%80%99" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/facebook.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/linkedin/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fnfl-commissioner-roger-goodell-says-game-is-safer-and-more-exciting-today-than-ever%2F2013%2F10%2F03%2F1f003070-2c7a-11e3-8ade-a1f23cda135e_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=NFL+Commissioner+Roger+Goodell+says+%E2%80%98game+is+safer+and+more+exciting+today+than+ever%E2%80%99" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/linkedin.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/gplus/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fnfl-commissioner-roger-goodell-says-game-is-safer-and-more-exciting-today-than-ever%2F2013%2F10%2F03%2F1f003070-2c7a-11e3-8ade-a1f23cda135e_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=NFL+Commissioner+Roger+Goodell+says+%E2%80%98game+is+safer+and+more+exciting+today+than+ever%E2%80%99" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/googleplus.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/email/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fnfl-commissioner-roger-goodell-says-game-is-safer-and-more-exciting-today-than-ever%2F2013%2F10%2F03%2F1f003070-2c7a-11e3-8ade-a1f23cda135e_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=NFL+Commissioner+Roger+Goodell+says+%E2%80%98game+is+safer+and+more+exciting+today+than+ever%E2%80%99" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/email.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965282542/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/32081f1e/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965282542/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/32081f1e/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965282542/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/32081f1e/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965282542/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/32081f1e/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965282542/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/32081f1e/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965282542/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/32081f1e/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965282542/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/32081f1e/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965282542/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/32081f1e/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/176965282542/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/32081f1e/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 01:58:08 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/nfl-commissioner-roger-goodell-says-game-is-safer-and-more-exciting-today-than-ever/2013/10/03/1f003070-2c7a-11e3-8ade-a1f23cda135e_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Kent Babband Mark Maske</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>Explore real-time news, visually
NFL Commissioner Roger Goodell says ‘game is safer and more exciting today than ever’
Nam Y. Huh/Associated Press - In a letter distributed Thursday, NFL Commissioner Roger Goodell claimed “the game is safer and more exciting today than ever [and] we are committed to pursuing a path that ensures the rewards of playing football continue to far outweigh the risks.”
E-mail the writers
The e-mails began landing in inboxes early Thursday morning, the latest message of progress and change from NFL Commissioner Roger Goodell. “The NFL season is off to another exciting and competitive start,” the more than 1,000-word letter began. “I want to thank you and all NFL fans for your passionate support.”
Goodell went on, his remarks evolving more into a reminder of the league’s focus on player safety, the reduction of head injuries and what can be done to make the NFL safer in the future. But was it an innocent and unprovoked state-of-the-league notice to supporters or merely a timely move to soften reaction to a pair of approaching threats to the NFL brand?
Video
The Post Sports Live crew debates whether the defense's impressive performance in the Redskins' win over the Oakland Raiders is a reason to be optimistic for the rest of the season.
More Redskins coverage
Kent Babb and Mark Maske
Amid mounting safety concerns, NFL commissioner says ‘game is safer and more exciting today than ever.’
Griffin progressing as a pocket passer
Mark Bullock
Robert Griffin III has been described this season as not the same player he was as a rookie. The Outsider shows how that’s true -- he’s actually improved in the pocket.
Morris: No excuses for DB struggles
Mike Jones
The secondary has taken its lumps partially because of injury and partially because of inexperience. But their position coach said he still expects them to make plays.
Griffin showing growth, maturity
Mike Jones
Quarterback's re-acclimation process remains in ongoing, but he showed more signs of progress on Sunday, according to his coaches.
Haslett: Cofield is best NT in game
Mike Jones
Now in his third season as the centerpiece of the Redskins’ 3-4 defensive front, nose tackle has gotten off to a strong start.
Stop concussions in youth football
Sally Jenkins
Don’t play tackle until your body matures. That’s what the Manning brothers and Tom Brady did.
Complete coverage
“League of Denial: The NFL, Concussions, and the Battle for Truth,” a book written by two ESPN investigative reporters, is expected to detail how the league not only ignored a scientific link between football and brain injuries decades ago but used its power to discredit supporting studies. The book will be released Tuesday, the same day PBS will air a corresponding and similarly titled “Frontline” documentary.
On Thursday, it was easy to make the connection that Goodell’s letter, sent to 10 million subscribers on the NFL’s mailing list, was a preemptive measure five days before the next wave of criticism.
“The issue of player health and player safety is something that has grown and is something the NFL doesn’t want to react to. It’s something they want to get out in front of,” said John Ourand, a media reporter for the Sports Business Journal. “This is an issue that they know they can’t put their hands over their eyes and hope it goes away. They have to deal with this, and I think this is all part of trying to do that.”
Greg Aiello, a spokesman in the league office, said Goodell’s open letter — the 11th note sent to supporters since 2011 — was “planned independently” of the forthcoming projects and compelled by no outside factor. “It is part of regular communication that the commissioner has with fans,” Aiello wrote in an e-mail.
Still, suspicions exist, particularly after ESPN announced in August it was ending a collaborative agreement with PBS to produce and market the “League of Denial” documentary. The sudden announcement prompted speculation that ESPN was pressured to distance itself from the project by the NFL, the sports giant’s most powerful broadcast partner. League officials have denied asking ESPN to back out of the project.
That was part of a late-summer two-step performed by the NFL, which also in late August agreed to a $765 million settlement after thousands of retired players sued the league for exposing them to concussion-related brain injuries.
In Thursday’s letter, Goodell emphasized the league’s commitment to change, ranging from eliminating the “head slap” in the 1970s to outlawing the “horse-collar” tackle in the 2000s. Goodell wrote that a recent emphasis on penalizing hits using the crown of the helmet is part of the league’s focus on evolving the game.
“We are proud that the game is safer and more exciting today than ever, but we are never satisfied,” the letter stated. “In keeping with our history, we are committed to pursuing a path that ensures the rewards of playing football continue to far outweigh the risks.”
Continued
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
