<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Business</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/BUSINESS/index.html?eref=rss_business</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 09:41:57 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Business</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/BUSINESS/index.html?eref=rss_business</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_business" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_business"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Serbian company's sweet success</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/04/business/serbia-bambi-biscuit-eu-accession/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_business/~3/vfqrhHKS-qU/index.html</link>
<description>Serbia's economy might be in the doldrums, but one company is tasting sweet success as the country readies itself for entry into the European Union.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_business/~4/vfqrhHKS-qU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 06:27:55 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/04/business/serbia-bambi-biscuit-eu-accession/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Read more: Rule one for television field producers: Expect the unexpected
The factory visited by CNN churns out 40 tonnes of Bambi's best-selling biscuit, the Plazma, each day. The company is investing $13 million in more production lines next year. Boehi told CNN he expected joining the EU would increase demand for products and open new markets.
"New opportunities might open up, mostly with surrounding markets like Romania, Bulgaria, Greece and Croatia," he said.
Boehi added: "We don't see actually countries like Germany, Switzerland [and] the UK as a real opportunity for us... these markets are saturated."
While Serbia aspires to EU membership, such a move will also provide challenges.
Watch more: Can Italy improve competitiveness
Serbia's minimum wage, at $1.36 an hour, is one of the lowest in Europe, and comes in below China, Malaysia and the Philippines. The country is also struggling with its rising unemployment levels. Entry into the EU has raised fears the country's educated youth will flee to better economies within Europe.
"Wage costs will go up, this is clear, but the way we will deal with that is not laying off people. It is by simply organizing ourselves in a better way," Boehi told CNN.
"We are paying more than others and the competition will slowly, slowly need to ...adjust to that and come up to the same level. So, it will go up but that is part of life."
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
