<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 11:55:42 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Vettel reveals Red Bull 'secret'</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/03/sport/motorsport/sebastian-vettel-red-bull-alonso-f1-motorsport/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/LIK_L_QMlqQ/index.html</link>
<description>Sebastian Vettel has at times made his domination of Formula One look effortless, but the triple world champion insists his supremacy is the result of tireless work from his all-conquering Red Bull team.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/LIK_L_QMlqQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 14:39:10 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/03/sport/motorsport/sebastian-vettel-red-bull-alonso-f1-motorsport/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Sebastian Vettel lauds Red Bull's hard work
October 4, 2013 -- Updated 1641 GMT (0041 HKT)
Sebastian Vettel is looking to steer his Red Bull to a fourth consecutive grand prix win in Singapore.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Sebastian Vettel says Red Bull's F1 dominance is down to hard work
The German is top of the drivers' standings ahead of the Korean Grand Prix
Vettel is unconcerned by the boos he consistently receives from fans
Ferrari's Ferando Alonso is refusing to give up on the 2013 title
(CNN) -- Sebastian Vettel has at times made his domination of Formula One look effortless, but the triple world champion insists his supremacy is the result of tireless work from his all-conquering Red Bull team.
The German has taken the checkered flag at each of the last three grands prix, extending his lead at the top of the drivers' championship to 60 points with just six races of the 2013 season remaining.
With a fourth consecutive world title all but in the bag, Vettel has paid tribute to the team which have powered his RB9 car to the front of the grid.
"I have very little information about what others are doing, but I can say that we're one of the hardest working teams and thus deserve to be where we are right now," the 26-year-old told F1's official website.
"This is not only a question of quantity -- how many more hours you put in -- but very much about quality."
What's behind Vettel's winning streak?
Niki Lauda on F1's most dangerous years
Will Ferrari's drivers deliver success?
Vettel's occupation of the podium has led to a backlash from some fans, with the former Toro Rosso driver consistently booed by fans during the season.
He was most recently jeered after winning the Singapore Grand Prix.
Vettel is unmoved by the negativity, putting it down to fans who are disappointed with him consistently finishing ahead of their favorite drivers.
"I am relaxed about it," he said. "I think the media exaggerate this matter. It is not that hordes of people boo -- it is only a small percentage.
"And isn't it so that every fan has the right to cheer for his own team and show disappointment when the others win? I think those who booed were Ferrari fans who obviously were disappointed that we again finished ahead of them.
"No big deal for us. The thing that matters is to know that we again did everything right -- that you can be satisfied with your performance."
Paul di Resta's Italian ancestry
A promotional image for the new Formula One film "Rush." Australian actor Chris Hemsworth plays the hedonistic James Hunt (left) while Daniel Bruhl plays his on-track nemesis Niki Lauda.
Lauda (left) and Hunt seen here during their heyday in the 1970s. Their battle during the 1976 season is one of motorsport's most compelling dramas and has now been dramatized in "Rush" -- which was released this September.
McLaren driver Hunt poses before the 1976 British Grand Prix at Brands Hatch. The Briton, who died of a heart attack in 1993 aged 45, was one of F1's great characters. He earned the nickname "Hunt the Shunt" for his habit of crashing into fellow competitors.
By contrast, Austrian Lauda had a meticulous nature on and off the racetrack. The clash of personalities made for a compelling rivalry on and off the track during the 1976 season.
Lauda's crash at the Nurburgring at the beginning of August was the defining moment of the 1976 season. He suffered horrific burns and nearly lost his life but somehow found the courage to return to the track at Monza just 43 days later. The Ferrari driver conquered his fears and finished fourth to the amazement of everyone and the delight of the Tifosi.
Lauda attends the world premiere of "Rush" at London's Leicester Square. "I was happy to stay alive," he says of the crash at the Nurburgring. "Normally you get killed in this kind of accident. Then it was clear that the challenge now is to see can you ever comeback ... So I fought my way back five weeks later in Monza. I only had Hunt as a target and make sure he will not win the championship."
Lauda's return to the racetrack at Monza took "courage in its rawest form," says "Rush" director Ron Howard. "Both (Hunt and Lauda) were so truthful and so competitive. They just did things their way. And they would have scars of some of those decisions but they also got to own their own triumphs. You have to admire that. To me, that's the nobility of the story."
Current McLaren driver Jenson Button also attended the London premiere. Lauda's comeback was "amazing," the 2009 world champion said. "It's obvious how tough he found it ... You are going to be (scared) after a massive, scary incident. Things have changed in terms of safety over the last 40 years but there are still dangers involved. We understand that as drivers. As soon as you step into the cockpit you know that."
Hunt's son Tom attended the premiere. He said it was "surreal" watching the film for the first time. "There were so many different emotions. For me, it's easy in one way because I know it's not Dad up there and it's a Hollywood film. Ron and his team have done a fantastic job."
'Rush' the movie
Bitter rivals, best of friends
The playboy
'Rush' world premiere, London: Niki Lauda
Ron Howard
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
