<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 19:32:22 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>On a wild night, things finally break 'Bad's' way</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/09/22/showbiz/tv/2013-emmy-awards/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/uCxA-fyCTbU/index.html</link>
<description>On a wild night of upsets at the 65th Primetime Emmy Awards, virtually nothing seemed to be going "Breaking Bad's" way.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/uCxA-fyCTbU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 18:18:08 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/09/22/showbiz/tv/2013-emmy-awards/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Photos: 2013 Emmy winners
Julia Louis-Dreyfus on 'Enough Said'
"Breaking Bad" stars Aaron Paul, left, and Bryan Cranston. AMC's "Breaking Bad" took home the Emmys' top honor for outstanding drama series.
Morena Baccarin of "Homeland" was nominated in the outstanding supporting actress in a drama series. She ended up losing out to "Breaking Bad's" Anna Gunn. "The thing about being a loser is (you're) in great company," Baccarin tweeted.
"New Girl" star Zooey Deschanel didn't take home a trophy, but she did have on plenty of bling.
Jeff Daniels, winner of outstanding lead actor in a drama series for "The Newsroom," appeared shocked to win. "Well crap ... didn't expect this," Daniels said as he accepted the Emmy for his role as anchor Will McAvoy.
"Portlandia" stars Fred Armisen, left, and Carrie Brownstein and director-writer Jonathan Krisel
"Modern Family" star Eric Stonestreet likely gave a thumbs up after the ceremony. His series once again won the best comedy Emmy.
Laura Dern was a nominee for best actress in a comedy series for "Enlightened."
Allison Holker of "Dancing With the Stars" was nominated in the choreography category along with Derek Hough.
"The Mindy Project" star Mindy Kaling was one of the evening's presenters.
"30 Rock" star Alec Baldwin with his daughter Ireland. Baldwin was a presenter and a nominee for best actor in a comedy series.
"Mad Men" star January Jones wears a pale pink, floor-length Givenchy gown.
"Saturday Night Live" star and soon-to-be "Late Night" host Seth Meyers and his wife, Alexi Ashe, are eager to show off their rings.
"Downton Abbey" star Michelle Dockery was nominated for outstanding lead actress in a drama. The Emmy went to "Homeland's" Claire Danes.
Malin Akerman of "Trophy Wife" was one of the night's presenters.
"Arrested Development" star Will Arnett was also an Emmy presenter.
"Modern Family" star Sofía Vergara looks stunning in a red dress.
Julianne Hough with brother Derek Hough, who won an Emmy for outstanding choreography for "Dancing With the Stars."
"Breaking Bad" actress Betsy Brandt is also a star of "The Michael J. Fox Show."
Claire Danes, who won for outstanding lead actress in a drama for her portrayal of Carrie Mathison in "Homeland," told CNN backstage she's a bit "shy" about the Emmy recognition.
Al Pacino with girlfriend Lucila Sola. Pacino was nominated as outstanding lead actor in a TV miniseries or movie for "Phil Spector."
"Bates Motel" star Vera Farmiga makes a daring fashion choice for the Emmys. She was nominated for outstanding lead actress in a drama series.
Stephen Colbert with his wife, Evelyn. "The Colbert Report" took home Emmys for outstanding variety series and writing for a variety series.
"House of Cards" star Kate Mara makes a striking figure in a dress with sheer paneling.
The newly bearded "Mad Men" star Jon Hamm was one of the evening's presenters.
Actress Leslie Mann with her husband, writer-director Judd Apatow.
Kerry Washington was nominated for outstanding lead actress in a drama series for her portrayal of Olivia Pope on "Scandal."
"Arrested Development" star Jason Bateman with his wife, Amanda Anka. He was nominated for outstanding lead actor in a comedy series.
"Game of Thrones" star Peter Dinklage with his wife, Erica Schmidt. He received a nod as outstanding supporting actor in a drama series.
"The Big Bang Theory" star Jim Parsons took home the Emmy for outstanding lead actor in a comedy series. It was his third Emmy win in four years for his role as Sheldon Cooper.
Tina Fey, winner of outstanding writing for a comedy series for "30 Rock." Fey shared the award with Tracey Wigfield.
"30 Rock's" Jane Krakowski complements co-star Fey in a floor-length blue hue.
Lena Dunham, creator and star of "Girls"
"Behind the Candelabra" stars Michael Douglas, Matt Damon and Damon's wife, Luciana Barroso. The HBO biopic on Liberace won the Emmy for outstanding miniseries or TV movie, and Douglas received the top actor award in a miniseries or TV movie for his performance as the pianist.
"Breaking Bad" star Dean Norris
"Breaking Bad" star Jonathan Banks and wife Gennera
Kristen Connolly of "House of Cards"
Lily Rabe of "American Horror Story"
"House of Cards" star Kevin Spacey
"30 Rock's" Keith Powell and fiancée Jill Knox
"Game of Thrones" star Lena Headey
Carla Gugino of "New Girl"
"Episodes" star Matt LeBlanc and girlfriend Andrea Anders
Emmy presenter Blair Underwood stars in a new version of "Ironside."
Constance Zimmer of "The Newsroom"
"Modern Famly" star Ty Burrell
Heidi Klum of "Project Runway"
"Modern Family" star Ed O'Neill
"Mad Men" star Jessica Pare
Allison Janney
"Downton Abbey" writer Julian Fellowes and his wife, Emma
Alyson Hannigan of "How I Met Your Mother"
"NCIS: Los Angeles" star and Emmy presenter LL Cool J
Comedian Sarah Silverman
"Castle" star Nathan Fillion and Mikaela Hoover
Dylan McDermott of "American Horror Story"
E!'s Giuliana Rancic
"Modern Family" star Jesse Tyler Ferguson, right, and husband Justin Mikita
Kiernan Shipka of "Mad Men"
"The Big Bang Theory" star Mayim Bialik
"The Big Bang Theory's" Kunal Nayyar
"Modern Family's" Nolan Gould
Ariel Winter of "Modern Family"
Matt Prokop and "Modern Family" star Sarah Hyland
"Arrow" actor Jamey Sheridan
Anna Gunn, who won an Emmy for outstanding supporting actress in a drama series for "Breaking Bad"
"Game of Thrones" executive producer David Benioff and his wife, actress Amanda Peet
"House of Cards" star Robin Wright was nominated as outstanding lead actress in a drama series.
"Mad Men's" Elisabeth Moss wasn't nominated for the '60s-era show this time around but rather as best actress in a miniseries or TV movie for "Top of the Lake."
"Homeland" actress Morgan Saylor wears a striking black-and-white gown.
"Mad Men" actress Linda Cardellini was nominated for outstanding guest actress in a drama series. She lost to "The Good Wife's" Carrie Preston.
"Orange Is the New Black" actress Taylor Schilling wears an eye-catching white gown.
"Glee" actress Jane Lynch wore several hats at the Emmys. In addition to being nominated for outstanding supporting actress in a comedy, Lynch also participated in the opening number and gave a tribute to the late Cory Monteith.
"Nashville's" Connie Britton, left, shares a red carpet moment with "Mad Men's" Jon Hamm and "Modern Family's" Julie Bowen.
Oscar winner Jessica Lange was nominated as outstanding lead actress in a TV miniseries or movie for "American Horror Story: Asylum."
Carrie Underwood covered the Beatles' "Yesterday" at the Emmys.
"House of Cards" actress Sandrine Holt will next be seen in the new fall show "Hostages."
"The Big Bang Theory's" Kaley Cuoco wears a burgundy Vera Wang.
Actress Allison Williams was among the "Girls" cast members who showed up to support the show's outstanding comedy series nomination. "Girls" lost to "Modern Family."
Damian Lewis with his wife, Helen McCrory. He was nominated for outstanding lead actor in a drama series for "Homeland" but lost to "The Newsroom's" Jeff Daniels.
Amy Poehler, left, with Tina Fey. The two added a little extra levity to Emmy host Neil Patrick Harris' opening number.
"How I Met Your Mother" actress Cobie Smulders wears a backless gown.
Anna Faris, star of the new CBS sitcom "Mom," is hard to miss in a bright yellow frock.
Julia Louis-Dreyfus won the Emmy for outstanding lead actress in a comedy for "Veep." The actress even channeled her character while accepting the award.
"Parks and Recreation" actress Aubrey Plaza opts for a covered-up look.
"Mad Men" actress Christina Hendricks was nominated as outstanding supporting actress in a drama.
"Girls" star Zosia Mamet joins her co-stars at the Emmys in a unique gown.
"Extra!" host Mario Lopez
"Access Hollywood's" Shaun Robinson rocks in a chic, sleek black dress.
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys:The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
Emmys 2013: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: Stars on the red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: Stars on the red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
2013 Emmys: The red carpet
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
