<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 19:32:22 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Kimmel vs. Kanye: New celebrity feud</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/09/27/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/kimmel-kanye-feud/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/0PS4dmEa04Q/index.html</link>
<description>&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/0PS4dmEa04Q" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 18:23:53 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/09/27/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/kimmel-kanye-feud/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Kimmel vs. Kanye: The latest celebrity feud
September 27, 2013 -- Updated 1401 GMT (2201 HKT)
Kanye West has given Jimmy Kimmel the rap feud he's always wanted. After Kimmel poked fun at West's interview with the BBC -- in which the entertainer called himself the No. 1 rock star on the planet -- West went to Twitter to air his profane grievances (in all caps, of course). West wants a public apology, but in the meantime, check out these other epic celebrity feuds:
Rapper Kendrick Lamar not only set Twitter on fire with his guest verses on Big Sean's song "Control," but he also stoked the flames of a bit of a hip-hop beef. Lamar called out his fellow lyricists to step up their game, which irritated some and led to rapper Joell Ortiz recording a rebuttal.
After her heart attack in 2012, Rosie O'Donnell received support from an unlikely source: Donald Trump. The two engaged in a pretty high-profile feud in the past with her calling him a "snake-oil salesman" and Trump retorting that she was a "loser."
Onetime friends Denise Richards and Heather Locklear hit a major impasse after the former started dating the latter's ex, Bon Jovi's Richie Sambora. In interviews, Richards denied that she and Locklear were still friends at the time she began seeing Sambora.
As a teen star, Hilary Duff reportedly dated heartthrob Aaron Carter before he broke up with her to get with Lohan -- and then tossed Lohan aside to win back Duff. The actress told People magazine in 2007 that she and Lohan had made peace.
Yah, we couldn't believe it either. MC Hammer reportedly took offense to Jay-Z guest-rapping in a Kanye West song ("So Appalled") that "Hammer went broke so you know I'm more focused/I lost 30 mill so I spent another 30/Cuz unlike Hammer 30 mill can't hurt me." Hammer took it to where all celebs take their beefs now, Twitter, and released a diss track, "Better Run Run."
Kanye West and Taylor Swift had one of the greatest celeb feuds of all time. The rapper famously grabbed the singer's mic at the 2009 MTV Video Music Awards. He later apologized, and she seemed to accept his apology via her song "Innocent."
It appears that rapper Lil' Kim has not taken too kindly to what she views as newercomer Nicki Minaj's lack of respect and similar style with the colored wigs and sexually explicit lyrics. The pair have traded insults all over the media.
It's a case of he said/she said/he said. Eminem set it off after he claimed to have had a torrid dating relationship with singer Mariah Carey, who denied it. Her husband, Nick Cannon, even offered to defend her honor by meeting the rapper in the ring.
This pair of wild-child socialites helped to coin the term "frenemies" after their very public bust-up in 2004. The former "Simple Life" co-stars went on to make up two years later.
Oprah Winfrey was reportedly annoyed by David Letterman's constant joking references to her name when he hosted the Academy Awards in 1995. The late-night talk-show host told "The Daily Show's" Jon Stewart he had also once played a practical joke on Wnfrey, convincing a waiter that she had agreed to pick up his tab. They have since made peace.
The gossip blogger claimed Will.i.am and his security guards attacked him at an awards show over some unkind words he had written about the musician's Black Eyed Peas bandmate Fergie. Will.i.am denied he had anything to do with it.
Superstar Tom Cruise got on Brooke Shields' bad side by decrying her use of medication to treat postpartum depression. Shields responded with an op-ed in The New York Times, and Cruise later apologized for his remarks.
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
