<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 19:32:22 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>'Will &amp; Grace': Where are they now?</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/09/20/showbiz/tv/will-and-grace-where-are-they-now/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/5D4PqwJ7fHg/index.html</link>
<description>&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/5D4PqwJ7fHg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 18:37:09 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/09/20/showbiz/tv/will-and-grace-where-are-they-now/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>'Will &amp; Grace': Where are they now?
By Lisa Respers France, CNN
September 20, 2013 -- Updated 1801 GMT (0201 HKT)
It's been 15 years since "Will &amp; Grace" premiered on NBC, and September 21, 1998 truly changed the television landscape . Some have even credited the comedy for changing America's views about the gay community and same-sex marriage. But what has the cast been up to since the series ended?
For some fans, Debra Messing will always be Grace Adler, despite the actress working fairly steadily since the series ended in 2006. She starred in two now-canceled series, "The Starter Wife" and, most recently, "Smash."
Eric McCormack was everyone's favorite BFF as Will Truman. He has done some voice work on shows like "American Dad" and currently stars in the TNT series "Perception."
Some of the best lines of the show went to Sean Hayes as Jack McFarland, Will's other best friend. In 2010, Hayes confirmed that he is gay. His new series "Sean Saves The World" premieres on NBC this fall and is about a gay father raising his teen daughter.
Megan Mullally went for laughs as the frequently boozing and pill popping Karen Walker, Grace's wealthy, somewhat-helpful assistant. She briefly hosted her own talk show from 2006 to 2007, has guest starred on several shows including husband Nick Offerman's "Parks and Recreation" and co-stars on the Adult Swim series "Children's Hospital."
Shelley Morrison appears as Karen's long suffering maid, Rosario Salazar. Morrison most recently provided the voice for Mrs. Portillo in the animated Disney series "Handy Manny."
Fans cheered when Grace finally found love with Leo Markus, portrayed by singer/actor Harry Connick Jr. He recently signed on as a new judge for "American Idol."
Bobby Cannavale was Will's love, Vince D'Angelo, and has worked steadily on both the big and small screen in the years since. He's appeared on several series including "Boardwalk Empire" and gotten some nice reviews for his work in Woody Allen's "Blue Jasmine."
HIDE CAPTION
Where are they now: 'Will &amp; Grace'
&lt;&lt;
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
