<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2015 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 21:04:52 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 21:04:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>'Star Wars Battlefront' goes deep into a galaxy far, far away</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4ba380b2/sc/28/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A150C110C180Ctech0Cstar0Ewars0Ebattlefront0Efeat0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Itech/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244158938418/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4ba380b2/sc/28/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244158938418/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4ba380b2/sc/28/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244158938418/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4ba380b2/sc/28/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244158938418/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4ba380b2/sc/28/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244158938418/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4ba380b2/sc/28/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244158938418/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4ba380b2/sc/28/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/244158938418/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4ba380b2/sc/28/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/244158938418/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4ba380b2/sc/28/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/244158938418/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4ba380b2/sc/28/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/244158938418/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4ba380b2/sc/28/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/244158938418/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4ba380b2/sc/28/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/244158938418/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4ba380b2/sc/28/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4ba380b2/sc/28/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 17:29:22 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2015/11/18/tech/star-wars-battlefront-feat/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/151113131949-star-wars-battlefront-03-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/151113131949-star-wars-battlefront-03-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>The "Star Wars Battlefront" designers had access to "Star Wars" archives
The game is hugely detailed, using minor references as starting points for game play
(CNN)
"Who are you?"
"I'm no one."
Those six words kicked off the latest wave of excitement, anticipation and intrigue as the official trailer for "Star Wars: The Force Awakens" swept across the globe recently. It features new characters, old favorites and the continuation of a story that has captivated audiences for many, many years.
The movie blends nostalgia with the promise of something new. Lucasfilm and game developer EA Digital Illusions CE wanted to capture those emotions in a video game and worked for three years in an unprecedented collaboration to create "Star Wars Battlefront."
"This is the deepest we've every opened up our archives to any partner," said Ada Duan, vice president of Lucasfilm Digital Business and Franchise Management.
Read More
'We wanted to honor the memory of the movies'
The team from Digital Illusions (known as DICE) wanted to make a game that all "Star Wars" fans have dreamed of playing. To make that a reality, artists, designers and developers traveled to the Lucas Cultural Arts Museum at Skywalker Ranch near San Francisco and were allowed access to the props, costumes and artwork that created the original trilogy of "Star Wars" movies.
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
The cast of "Star Wars: Episode VII" -- or should we say "Star Wars: The Force Awakens" -- unites well-known names with some up-and-coming actors.John Boyega is best known for the 2011 sci-fi action comedy "Attack the Block," but now he's known as the guy who steals the spotlight in the "Star Wars: The Force Awakens" trailer. Boyega was long rumored to be a top choice for the lead role.
Hide Caption
1 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
Daisy Ridley portrays the female lead of the movie, Rey, who is often accompanied by her droid BB-8, an early fan favorite.
Hide Caption
2 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
Actors Pip Andersen, left, and Crystal Clarke were picked from an open casting call to join the movie. Andersen is skilled in the training discipline parkour, and "The Force Awakens" will be one of Clarke's first feature films.
Hide Caption
3 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
The rumors about Academy Award-winning actress Lupita Nyong'o joining the cast turned out to be true. In May, she was announced as the newest actress to join the saga. Nyong'o won the best supporting actress Oscar for her breakthrough role in "12 Years a Slave."
Hide Caption
4 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
Gwendoline Christie, currently known as Brienne of Tarth on HBO's "Game of Thrones," has also joined "Star Wars." She will co-star in "The Hunger Games: Mockingjay - Part 2" as Commander Lyme.
Hide Caption
5 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
Adam Driver is a multifaceted actor who'll presumably get to show more of his range in "The Force Awakens." While he's best known for playing a quirky love interest on "Girls," Driver has also appeared in feature films "J. Edgar," "Lincoln," "Frances Ha" and "Inside Llewyn Davis."
Hide Caption
6 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
Oscar Isaac had a breakthrough role in 2013 as the cranky singer-songwriter Llewyn Davis in the drama "Inside Llewyn Davis." We can't imagine his work in "The Force Awakens" will require him to sing, but it would be awesome if it did; Isaac has proved he's got a great set of pipes.
Hide Caption
7 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
Andy Serkis is setting himself up to have a busy few years. The celebrated actor recently appeared in "Dawn of the Planet of the Apes," which will be followed by "The Force Awakens." After that, he's expected to appear in another "Tintin" movie, "The Adventures of Tintin: Prisoners of the Sun."
Hide Caption
8 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
Does the name Domhnall Gleeson sound familiar? That might be because you remember him as Bill Weasley in the last two movies of the "Harry Potter" franchise. But Gleeson has established himself with a host of other projects, including 2010's "Never Let Me Go" and 2013's "About Time." Suffice to say that if you don't know Gleeson by now, you will after "Star Wars: Episode VII."
Hide Caption
9 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
When we learned that the latest "Star Wars" installment is supposed to take place 30 years after "Return of the Jedi" and feature a trio of newbies alongside some familiar faces, we were ready to bet the house that Mark Hamill's Luke Skywalker would be one of the recognizable stars. It was an easy guess to make, though; Hamill has long been considered an unspoken done deal.
Hide Caption
10 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
Carrie Fisher was one of the original "Star Wars" cast members who initially said she was on board for the new movie, only for her rep to backtrack and say the actress was kidding. But Abrams' announcement is no joke: The former Princess Leia has returned.
Hide Caption
11 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
After playing coy with the press for months, Harrison Ford was finally officially announced as part of the "Force Awakens" cast. The actor will reprise his role of Han Solo.
Hide Caption
12 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
We can't be the only ones who are supremely relieved to see that Anthony Daniels, the voice of C-3PO, will be back in action.
Hide Caption
13 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
Obviously, you can't have Daniels' C-3PO without Kenny Baker's R2-D2. Just the thought of splitting up the droids is heartbreaking!
Hide Caption
14 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
Peter Mayhew is probably somewhere warming up his voice for that famous Chewbacca roar. The actor was rumored to be reprising the character in "The Force Awakens," but it wasn't official until Abrams' announcement.
Hide Caption
15 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
Max von Sydow is one of the veteran actors joining the upcoming "Star Wars" movie. It isn't clear what the wide-ranging thespian will do in Abrams' picture, but we can rest assured that he'll bring his respected acting chops to the part.
Hide Caption
16 of 17
17 photos: Meet the faces of the new 'Star Wars'
"Star Wars" veteran Warwick Davis is set to return too. He's played multiple roles, but he's best known as Wicket the lead Ewok from "Return of the Jedi," so we suspect he may reprise that role.
Hide Caption
17 of 17
"We wanted to honor the memory of the movies," said Sigurlina Ingvarsdottir, senior producer for "Star Wars Battlefront." "We were invited by our partners at Lucasfilm to go to Skywalker Ranch to walk around and soak up the atmosphere. But then (we were allowed) to go to the archives and actually get to see the props and to figure out to what extent we could use them."
The DICE team took many photographs and measurements and looked in-depth through the archives to study each piece so it could be as perfectly represented in the game as it was in the movie. However, Ingvarsdottir realized it is more about fan perception than historical accuracy.
"The movies were videocaptured the late '70s and early '80s," she said. "A lot has happened in terms of bringing rich visuals, but I think that when you see them, this is how you see the movie in your mind's eye."
The artistic crews also traveled to Iceland and Muir Woods, California, for inspiration in re-creating the environments of a few of the planets in the game.
DICE and Lucasfilm knew they would have to work together more closely to bring the original trilogy to life in the video game in a way that fans would appreciate and desire.
"They were able to take a lot of photos and use those as actual reference as the most authentic representation of those props, whether for weapons or for a planet," Duan said, adding that even original reference artwork was available. "We really opened up all of our archives, not only reference from the original films but just a lot of material that we have here available to them."
The game takes players through many adventures from "Episode IV: A New Hope" on Tatooine, "Episode V: The Empire Strikes Back" on Hoth and "Episode VI: Return of the Jedi" on Endor. Though some missions are pulled straight from the scripts, there are others that use the movies as a backdrop to provide challenges for would-be rebels or Stormtroopers.
But the story doesn't end after the explosion of the second Death Star. The game also travels to previously undiscovered planets, like Sullust, a lava planet. Sullust isn't something dreamed up by the designers; it is mentioned, but never seen, in "Return of the Jedi."
Tie-ins and X-Wings
It also directly ties into the upcoming movie, "The Force Awakens," by letting players engage in the battle of Jakku starting December 1. This desert planet was the battleground of a fierce conflict between the New Republic and Imperial holdouts 29 years before the events in the movie.
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
Force Friday marks the unveiling of many new "Star Wars" products, in addition to the merch already available in anticipation of the December release of "Star Wars: The Force Awakens." "Disney Infinity 3.0," the massive game with Disney characters, just added "Star Wars" characters, making it that much cooler.
Hide Caption
1 of 21
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
You can compete for the "most glamorous woman in the galaxy" crown with new "Star Wars" Cover Girl cosmetics.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
A hungry Jedi can enjoy Campbell's "Star Wars"-themed soups.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
The villainous Kylo Ren will be a highly sought-after action figure on Force Friday.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
Captain Phasma, a rare female villain, is already a favorite character.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
This figure is the heroic pilot Poe.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
Chewbacca is back to represent the Wookiees.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
Finn, one of the main characters of "Star Wars: The Force Awakens."
Hide Caption
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
Fans will be just as excited to collect droid BB-8 as they will Rey.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
The stormtroopers have a new look.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
Poe is here with his redesigned X-Wing.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
The massive Star Destroyers are back.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
"Star Wars" bladebuilders allow fans, young and old, to create their own lightsabers.
Hide Caption
21 photos: Force Friday: The world of 'Star Wars' merchandise
Here's a bladebuilder breakdown.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
