<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 11:46:31 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>15 Libyan soldiers killed in attack</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/05/world/africa/libya-attack/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/05/world/africa/libya-attack/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>At least 15 Libyan soldiers were killed and five others wounded in an attack on a military post Saturday morning on a road between Bani Walid and Tarhuna, Libya's state news agency, LANA, reported.</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 11:44:12 EDT</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>15 Libyan soldiers killed in attack on military post -- reports
By CNN Staff
October 5, 2013 -- Updated 1552 GMT (2352 HKT)
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
At least 15 Libyan soldiers are killed and five more injured in an attack, state media report
Gunmen reportedly targeted a military post on the road between Bani Walid and Tarhuna
Bani Walid was seen as a stronghold of supporters of late leader Moammar Gadhafi
(CNN) -- At least 15 Libyan soldiers were killed and five others wounded in an attack on a military post Saturday morning on a road between Bani Walid and Tarhuna, Libya's state news agency, LANA, reported.
Military forces completely blocked off the area following the attack, which was carried out by a group of unidentified gunmen, LANA said.
Bani Walid was known as one of the last strongholds of former leader Moammar Gadhafi's regime.
The town, in the desert southwest of Misrata, was the focus of a month-long siege a year ago by the Libyan army and pro-government militias, in which dozens reportedly died.
Gadhafi was captured and killed in October 2011 after more than 40 years in power.
The country has struggled since then to reimpose order and the rule of law.
CNN's Hamdi Alkhshali contributed to this report.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
