<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 11:46:31 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Italy shipwreck</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/05/world/europe/italy-migrant-boat-sinks/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/05/world/europe/italy-migrant-boat-sinks/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>No more survivors will be found, rescuers say, after a migrant boat sank off Lampedusa, with the loss of at least 111 people.</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 11:59:29 EDT</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>STORY HIGHLIGHTS
NEW: Survivors' accounts indicate 518 people were on the boat, a lawmaker says
NEW: Migrants tell lawmakers how a fire on the boat started a panic before it capsized
Rough weather prevents divers descending to the wreck, where many bodies are trapped
Fisherman tells how he pulled survivors and bodies from the water
Lampedusa, Italy (CNN) -- Hope faded Saturday that any more survivors would be found two days after a packed migrant boat sank half a mile off the shores of Italy's tiny Lampedusa island, with the loss of at least 111 people.
Some 155 survivors were pulled from the water after the boat capsized Thursday morning. But rescue teams now say they have given up hope of finding anyone else alive.
Italian authorities fear more than 200 bodies may lie entombed in the vessel on the sea bed, some 47 meters (150 feet) below the surface of the Mediterranean.
Dozens dead in Italian boat accident
A diver who made it down to the wreck said that dozens of corpses were wedged inside its lower deck, in a scene of horror.
Gusty winds and rough waters Saturday prevented divers from reaching the wreckage to carry on the grisly recovery operation, but they are determined to carry on their efforts.
"We will continue all day and all night until we are able to bury these bodies," said Adm. Felicio Angrisano of the coast guard.
Rescue crews are patrolling the area of the disaster from above by airplane and helicopter.
Survivors mourn those lost
A small, private memorial service is scheduled for Saturday at the island's airport, where the bodies of the 111 people who died are being kept. Some of the survivors of the wreck -- who have been held in Lampedusa's migrant detention center since they were rescued -- will attend.
A delegation of Italian lawmakers, headed by the president of the Italian parliament, Laura Boldrini, visited the detention center Saturday to speak to the survivors. Conditions in the center are said to be cramped, since it was built to hold 250 people but currently houses more than 1,200.
The U.N. refugee agency said Friday that all but one of the survivors were from Eritrea, in the Horn of Africa. The other was Tunisian. The boat is also believed to have been carrying migrants from Somalia.
After visiting the detention center, the lawmakers held a news conference in the local city hall, where tensions rose as some angry residents accused the politicians of leaving their island to carry the burden of a constant flow of newly arriving migrants.
Many of the island's 6,000 or so full-time residents took part in a candlelit vigil Friday evening to remember the many lives lost.
Since Lampedusa, south of Sicily and the closest Italian island to Africa, has become a destination for tens of thousands of refugees seeking to enter European Union countries, shipwrecks off its shores have become all too common.
An ill-fated journey
One lawmaker, Mario Marazziti, said an estimated 518 migrants were on the boat that capsized Thursday, based on survivors' accounts.
Marazziti also gave more details of the migrants' ill-fated journey. None of the migrants on the boat had cell phones, he said, since they were made to leave them behind when they left Libya bound for Italy.
At dawn on Thursday they arrived near Lampedusa. They switched off the engine and hoped that someone would come to rescue them, he said. They saw a fishing boat in the distance, but it didn't stop, he said, although it may not have seen them.
Then the migrants lit a blanket, hoping to be spotted. But tragedy followed, as a large fire started and many of the migrants crowded to one side of the boat -- causing it to capsize.
The first help to reach the site, by chance, came in the shape of two fishing boats, he said.
'It was just my duty'
Lampedusa fisherman Domenico Colapinto told CNN on Friday how he spotted people in the water soon after 7 a.m. as he returned from a night at sea. Frantically, he pulled 20 people on board his boat -- two of them dead.
"It was very difficult to get them out because they were covered in gasoline, they were nearly naked and slippery," he said. "Then they just hugged me and said, thank you, thank you."
Colapinto, who injured his arm pulling a woman to safety, said it had been his duty to try to save as many people as possible.
"I don't feel a hero or anything; it was just my duty. I'm sorry that they were slippery, otherwise we would have been quicker," he said.
He also cast doubt on the idea that any fishermen would have ignored the migrants in their hour of need, saying there is "a lot of humanity" in Lampedusa. More likely, he said, the boat wasn't spotted because it was still dark or other vessels were not listening to the emergency radio channel.
Mayor: No delay by coast guard
Italian authorities are investigating why they were not alerted to the boat, which had engine problems, sooner -- which might have allowed for more lives to be saved before it sank.
Lampedusa Mayor Giusi Cappello told the news conference there was no delay in the coast guard's rescue operation once it had been alerted by the fishermen.
Boldrini, president of the Italian parliament and a former U.N. refugee agency representative in Italy, said that a group of survivors will be taken to identify the bodies.
When the bodies will be moved from the island is not yet clear.
Four children were among the dead, alongside 49 women and 58 men, coast guard spokesman Filippo Marini said.
'Wake-up call'
Despite the dangers of taking to the sea in boats that are often barely seaworthy, thousands of migrants and asylum seekers depart North Africa's shores every year in search of a better life.
Just under 115 kilometers (70 miles) from Tunisia, Lampedusa has been the first point of entry to Europe for more than 200,000 refugees and irregular migrants who have passed through the island since 1999.
According to the U.N. refugee agency, some 15,000 migrants and asylum-seekers reached Italy and Malta last year, while almost 500 people were reported dead or missing at sea.
In the first six months of 2013, the agency recorded 40 deaths -- a figure based on interviews with survivors of the crossing -- but the total for this year will be pushed up sharply by the latest deaths off Lampedusa.
U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees Antonio Guterres said the tragedy "should serve as a wake-up call" to the world. It shows how important it is for refugees "to have legal channels to access territories where they can find protection," he said.
Maurizio Albahari, assistant professor of anthropology at the University of Notre Dame, said it was time for Europe to enact new policies rather than simply shed tears for those who died -- or blame the traffickers.
"To solve the problem, it is vital to understand what it is that routinely brings thousands of migrants to trust smugglers, face exorbitant costs and risk their lives on unseaworthy vessels," he said. "It's quite simple. It is legally impossible for them to travel safely on planes and ferries."
CNN's Matthew Chance and Livia Borghese reported from Lampedusa and Laura Smith-Spark wrote in London.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
