<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 11:46:31 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Afghanistan: Did airstrike kill civilians?</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/05/world/asia/afghanistan-nato-strike/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/05/world/asia/afghanistan-nato-strike/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>International forces in Afghanistan are investigating reports that civilians were killed in air strikes in the eastern province of Nangarhar, a spokesman for the NATO-led International Security Assistance Force said Saturday.</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 11:43:38 EDT</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Afghanistan: NATO forces probe claim of civilian airstrike deaths
By Ahmed Bukhari, for CNN
October 5, 2013 -- Updated 1552 GMT (2352 HKT)
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
NATO-led forces investigate reports of civilian casualties in airstrikes in Nangahar
An initial investigation has not confirmed any casualties, an ISAF spokesman says
A spokesman for the Nangarhar provincial governor says at least 5 people were killed
Kabul (CNN) -- International forces in Afghanistan are investigating reports that civilians were killed in air strikes in the eastern province of Nangarhar, a spokesman for the NATO-led International Security Assistance Force said Saturday.
The strikes Friday in Behsud District targeted five enemy combatants but an initial investigation did not confirm any casualties, Tech. Sgt. Peter Dean said.
A spokesman for the governor of Nangarhar province said at least five people were killed following a NATO airstrike late Friday in Jalalabad.
The victims were sitting outside in their garden enjoying some relief from the heat when a helicopter came overhead and killed all five of them, spokesman Ahmed Zia Abdulzai said.
He could not confirm if those killed were civilians or insurgents.
The incident sparked a demonstration Saturday in Jalalabad to protest NATO's action, Abdulzai said.
CNN's Christabelle Fombu contributed to this report.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
