<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 19:32:22 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Fall Preview 2013: Movies</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/09/03/showbiz/movies/fall-preview-movies-gallery/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/93e7amVlkK8/index.html</link>
<description>&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/93e7amVlkK8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 10:17:54 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/09/03/showbiz/movies/fall-preview-movies-gallery/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>By Todd Leopold, CNN
September 3, 2013 -- Updated 1415 GMT (2215 HKT)
Don't miss our fall preview of albums , books and TV shows to watch for. Want to see everything at once? Here's a complete guide to Fall Entertainment 2013 . But as for movies, check out "Rush": Ron Howard's new film, "Rush," tells the story of Formula One auto racing rivals James Hunt (Chris Hemsworth) and Niki Lauda (Daniel Bruhl). Olivia Wilde plays Hunt's wife, Suzy Miller, who gets to dress in what E! calls Gucci's "chic" '70s outfits. Will Howard's auto-racing movie turn out to be as exciting as 1966's "Grand Prix," or will it be as dull as 1990's "Days of Thunder"? (September 27)
"Gravity": George Clooney and Sandra Bullock star in "Gravity," the new film from Alfonso Cuaron ("Children of Men"), about two astronauts who have to find a way to survive in space after a damaging accident. "Gravity" debuted at the Venice Film Festival and has received glowing reviews. "Should inspire awe among critics and audiences worldwide," wrote Variety's Justin Chang in a typical rave. (October 4)
"Captain Phillips": Tom Hanks -- who's trying out some new looks here, and new accents in "Saving Mr. Banks" -- plays the real-life captain of the MV Maersk Alabama, who was kidnapped by Somali pirates in 2009, in "Captain Phillips." Paul Greengrass' direction -- he also made two Matt Damon "Bourne" movies and "United 93" -- may make the difference between the film being a mundane rescue-on-the-high-seas adventure and something a little deeper. (October 11)
"The Fifth Estate": Benedict Cumberbatch bleached his hair to play WikiLeaks mastermind Julian Assange in "The Fifth Estate," directed by Bill Condon ("Gods and Monsters," "Kinsey"). Anthony Mackie, Stanley Tucci and Laura Linney also have roles -- and so does the suddenly busy Daniel Bruhl. Has financial success with the "Twilight" movies spoiled Condon? Or given him more freedom? The cast is certainly promising. (October 11)
"The Counselor": Ridley Scott's latest, "The Counselor," stars Michael Fassbender, Brad Pitt, Penelope Cruz and Cameron Diaz. Oh, and a wild-haired Javier Bardem, which is only appropriate, since this tale of drug trafficking was written by "No Country for Old Men" author Cormac McCarthy. Watch out for sudden violence and creepy villains -- and, perhaps, a sense of honor. OK, friend-o? (October 25)
"All Is Lost": Robert Redford is pretty much a one-man show as a sailor adrift on the Indian Ocean in "All Is Lost," directed by "Margin Call's" J.C. Chandor. The actor is already being touted for honors: "Redford, who can't avoid exuding charisma, plays this role with utter naturalism and lack of histrionics or self-regard," said The Hollywood Reporter. (October 25)
"Ender's Game": Orson Scott Card's much-honored 1985 novel, "Ender's Game," finally comes to the screen with Asa Butterfield as military prodigy Ender Wiggin, who is trained as a child to take on the Earth-threatening "Buggers," an alien species. Harrison Ford plays his minder and Ben Kingsley is a famed soldier of the alien wars. Sci-fi fans have been waiting for this for years, but controversy surrounding Card may not help in drawing wider audiences. (November 1)
"Thor: The Dark World": The latest from the Marvel factory stars Chris Hemsworth, once again, as the Nordic god with the powerful hammer. This time he has to save the universe from a dastardly villain. Natalie Portman co-stars. (November 8)
"The Wolf of Wall Street": Martin Scorsese and Leonardo DiCaprio team up for the fifth time in "The Wolf of Wall Street," a biographical story of the conniving trader Jordan Belfort, who lived a life of greed and excess before becoming ensnared in his own traps. An interesting cast, including Jonah Hill, Matthew McConaughey, Kyle Chandler, Rob Reiner, Spike Jonze and Joanna Lumley, lend their talents. Script by Terence Winter ("Boardwalk Empire," "The Sopranos"). (November 15)
"The Hunger Games: Catching Fire": Part 2 of the "Hunger Games" trilogy finds Katniss (Jennifer Lawrence), now famous, on a victory tour of Panem. But she's still a pawn in the Capitol's game, which has expanded to a new competition that pits her and Peeta against previous Hunger Games winners. Members of the first movie's cast, including Donald Sutherland, Lenny Kravitz and Stanley Tucci, are back in "The Hunger Games: Catching Fire," joined by Philip Seymour Hoffman and Jeffrey Wright. May the odds be in its favor. (November 22)
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
