<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 19:32:22 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Ex-wife: Docs competed to give Jackson meds</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/08/14/showbiz/jackson-death-trial/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/wmlwGvFDbPI/index.html</link>
<description>Two German doctors treated Michael Jackson's insomnia with propofol 12 years before he died from an overdose of the surgical anesthetic, his former wife testified Wednesday.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/wmlwGvFDbPI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 18:08:59 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/08/14/showbiz/jackson-death-trial/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Doctors competed to give Michael Jackson painkillers, ex-wife Debbie Rowe says
By Alan Duke, CNN
August 14, 2013 -- Updated 2339 GMT (0739 HKT)
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
NEW: Debbie Rowe describes 2 instances when Jackson used propofol for sleep
"Doctors took advantage" of Michael Jackson because of his pain, Rowe testifies
Rowe is the mother of Jackson's two oldest children
AEG Live contends Jackson secretly used propofol for years to treat his insomnia
Los Angeles (CNN) -- Two German doctors treated Michael Jackson's insomnia with propofol 12 years before he died from an overdose of the surgical anesthetic, his former wife testified Wednesday.
Debbie Rowe , who is the mother of Jackson's two oldest children, is being forced to testify about the singer's drug use by lawyers for AEG Live, the concert promoter being sued by members of Jackson's family, who say the promoter is responsible for his death.
Doctors "would try to outbid" each other on who could give Michael Jackson "the better drug" for his pain, Rowe testified Wednesday.
Jackson family matriarch Katherine Jackson sat Wednesday morning in the front row of the small courtroom, where she has spent much of the past 16 weeks watching the trial.
Dr. Allen Metzger -- Jackson's general practitioner in the United States -- arranged for the German anesthesiologists to infuse the singer with propofol in a Munich hotel in July 1997 after sedatives failed to help him sleep between concerts, Rowe testified.
"I think they tried it and it hadn't worked and if he couldn't sleep, he couldn't perform," she testified. Jackson "was at the end of his rope; he didn't know what else to do."
He "felt better" after eight hours of propofol-induced sleep and decided to get a second treatment after his second Munich show, she said.
Metzger testified at the criminal trial of Dr. Conrad Murray that he was never involved in giving propofol treatments for Jackson and was not aware of the drug until much later.
Rowe, who met Jackson when she worked as a nurse in the Beverly Hills office of Dr. Arnold Klein, backed away from her previous statement at her deposition in which she said doctors also gave Jackson propofol infusions in hotels in France during the HIStory tour.
AEG Live contends that Jackson used propofol for years to treat his insomnia, including when Rowe was traveling with him in Europe in the 1990s.
The coroner ruled Jackson died on June 25, 2009, from a propofol overdose administered by Murray, who is serving a prison sentence for involuntary manslaughter.
Rowe testified that Jackson underwent surgery in 1993 to repair burns suffered years earlier.
His doctors "couldn't get a grip of the pain" and that two doctors "were having a pissing contest over who gave him the better drug."
"Michael had a very low pain tolerance, and his fear of pain was incredible," Rowe testified. "And I think that doctors took advantage of him that way."
Katherine Jackson is the matriarch of the Jackson family. Here she attends the hand and footprint ceremony for son Michael at Grauman's Chinese Theatre in January 2012 in Los Angeles.
Joseph Walker "Joe" Jackson is the patriarch of the Jackson family. He's pictured at a March 2011 press conference in Madrid, Spain.
Maureen Reillette "Rebbie" Jackson is Joe and Katherine's oldest child. She scored a hit in the 1980s with the song "Centipede." She has three children: Stacee, Yashi and Austin "Auggie" Brown. Here she attends the world premiere of "Michael Jackson: The Life of an Icon" in London in November 2011.
Yashi Brown, Rebbie Jackson's second child, is a poet and advocate on mental health issues.
Rebbie Jackson's youngest, Austin "Auggie" Brown, is a musician. He's pictured at a December 2012 benefit in Hollywood.
Sigmund Esco "Jackie" Jackson, center, is the second of Joe and Katherine's children. He has two children with Enid Spann: Sigmund Esco "Siggy" Jackson Jr. and Brandi Jackson. Here he performs with brothers Tito, left, and Marlon Jackson in Los Angeles in July 2012.
Toriano Adaryll "Tito" Jackson, the third of the Jackson children, has three sons: Toriano Adaryll "Taj"Jackson Jr., Taryll Adren Jackson and Tito Joe "TJ" Jackson, who are members of the group 3T. Tito Jackson performs in Liverpool, England, in 2009.
Toriano Adaryll "Taj" Jackson Jr., Tito Jackson's oldest son, is part of the group 3T. Here he performs in Cardiff, Wales, in October 2011.
Taryll Adren Jackson, Tito Jackson's middle son, performs with his bothers in memory of his uncle, Michael, in 2011.
Tito Joe "TJ" Jackson performs in honor of his uncle, Michael.
Jermaine La Jaune Jackson is the fourth of Joe and Katherine's children. He has seven children. With Hazel Gordy, Jackson had three children: Jermaine Lu Juane Jr., Autumn Joy and Jaimy. He had two children with Margaret Maldonado: Jeremy and Jourdynn. His two youngest children, Jaffar and Jermajesty, were born to Alejandra Oaziaza. He has no children with his current wife, Halima Rashid. Jackson and Rashid are pictured at the Royal Festival Hall in London in October 2010.
La Toya Yvonne Jackson, the fifth of Joe and Katherine Jackson's children, attends the world premiere of "Dancing In Jaffa" at the Tribeca Film Festival in New York in April. She is one of the film's executive producers.
Marlon David Jackson was born a year before brother Michael Jackson. He has three children with Carol Parker: Valencia, Brittany and Marlon David Jr.
Pop superstar Michael Jackson, the most famous of Joe and Katherine's children, had three kids. He fathered his first two, Prince Michael Joseph Jackson Jr. and Paris Katherine Jackson, with Deborah Jeanne Rowe. His youngest, Prince Michael Joseph "Blanket" Jackson II, was born to an unidentified woman. The singer died in 2009.
Prince Michael Joseph Jackson Jr. attends a baseball game in August 2012 during a visit to his late father's hometown of Gary, Indiana.
Paris Jackson attends a party at the Regent Beverly Wilshire Hotel in Beverly Hills, California, in October 2012.
Prince Michael Joseph "Blanket" Jackson attends the Las Vegas premiere of "Michael Jackson: The Immortal World" by Cirque du Soleil in December 2011. He is Michael Jackson's youngest son.
Steven Randall "Randy" Jackson is the second-youngest of Joe and Katherine Jackson's children. He has four children: Steveanna, Genevieve, Donte and Steven Randall Jr. Alejandra Oaziaza is the mother of the latter three. She later married and had two children with Randy's brother Jermaine.
Genevieve Jackson, pictured in November 2011, is Randy Jackson's second child.
Janet Damita Jo Jackson is the youngest of Joe and Katherine Jackson's children. The pop star has no children. She was briefly married to singer James DeBarge before secretly marrying dancer Rene Elizondo in 1991. The couple divorced in 2000, and she married businessman Wissam Al Mana in 2012. She's pictured performing at the Sydney Opera House in 2011 in Australia.
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
All in the Jackson family
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
