<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 14:23:48 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Halle Berry welcomes baby boy</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/10/06/showbiz/halle-berry-birth/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/KnEFKS5XxKg/index.html</link>
<description>Actress Halle Berry and husband, Olivier Martinez, welcomed their first son Saturday.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/KnEFKS5XxKg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 06:41:27 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/10/06/showbiz/halle-berry-birth/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Halle Berry gives birth to a son
By Alan Duke, CNN
October 7, 2013 -- Updated 1041 GMT (1841 HKT)
Halle Berry and husband Olivier Martinez walk hand-in-hand in California this summer. The child is the second for the Ocar-winning actress.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Berry's rep gave few details about the new son
The actress married the boy's father in July
Berry revealed in April that she was expecting a baby with the French actor
The Oscar-winner has a 5-year-old daughter with ex-boyfriend Gabriel Aubry
Los Angeles (CNN) -- Actress Halle Berry and husband, Olivier Martinez, welcomed the birth of their first son Saturday.
A representative for Berry would not share any other details about the boy -- Berry's second child -- including where he was born or his name.
The Oscar-winner has a 5-year-old daughter with ex-boyfriend Gabriel Aubry.
Berry, 47, married Martinez, 47, in a private ceremony in France in July. It is the third marriage for the Berry, who revealed in April that she was expecting a baby with the French actor.
Berry and Kors fight world hunger
Berry and Martinez began their relationship last year after meeting on the set of the film "Dark Tide."
Martinez was by her side through the last months of her bitter custody battle with Aubry, the Canadian model who fathered daughter Nahla.
They reached "an amicable agreement" over custody in November, a week after a Thanksgiving Day fistfight in Berry's Hollywood driveway between Martinez and Aubry.
Berry was previously married to former pro baseball player David Justice -- from 1993 until 1996 -- and singer Eric Benet -- from 2001 to 2004.
"This has been the biggest surprise of my life, to tell you the truth," Berry told CNN when discussing her pregnancy in April. "I thought I was kind of past the point where this could be a reality for me. So it's been a big surprise and the most wonderful."
CNN's Topher Gauk-Roger contributed to this report.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
