<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2015 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 21:04:52 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 21:04:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Pigeons, the next great cancer detector?</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4baed207/sc/32/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A150C110C190Chealth0Cpigeons0Eas0Ecancer0Edetectors0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Itech/story01.htm</link>
<description>Scientists have discovered you can teach one of the most maligned of birds how to identify cancer.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159077632/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4baed207/sc/32/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159077632/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4baed207/sc/32/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159077632/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4baed207/sc/32/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159077632/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4baed207/sc/32/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159077632/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4baed207/sc/32/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159077632/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4baed207/sc/32/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/244159077632/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4baed207/sc/32/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/244159077632/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4baed207/sc/32/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/244159077632/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4baed207/sc/32/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/244159077632/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4baed207/sc/32/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/244159077632/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4baed207/sc/32/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/244159077632/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4baed207/sc/32/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4baed207/sc/32/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 09:40:18 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2015/11/19/health/pigeons-as-cancer-detectors/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/151118155210-pigeon-cancer-detector-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/151118155210-pigeon-cancer-detector-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Facebook Twitter Instagram
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Pigeons, the next great cancer detector?
Updated 1512 GMT (2312 HKT) November 20, 2015
Pigeons were trained to read samples of breast tissue to look for cancer.
Story highlights
Pigeons' vision is as good as that of humans, if not better
Scientists trained pigeons to distinguish between malignant and benign pathology
Pigeons got it right at least 85% of the time
(CNN)
Scientists have discovered you can teach one of the most maligned of birds how to identify cancer.
It turns out pigeons may make great cancer detectives.
It's unlikely that you'll see a "Pigeons at Work" sign at the hospital radiology or pathology department anytime soon, but the authors of a new study in the journal PLOS ONE think the birds offer great potential as testers of cancer detection technology and as a help in doctor training.
Related: Pigeon caught flying drug into prison
Evolutionarily speaking, birds' and humans' last common ancestor lived about 310 million years ago , but pigeons' vision is as effective as that of humans, if not better. The birds can see more wavelengths of light than we can, including ultraviolet light. And that's impressive when you know that their brains are about one-thousandth the size of ours.
Read More
Earlier studies have shown pigeons can use visual cues to put objects into categories , they can differentiate between letters of the alphabet, and they can recognize you even if you change clothes. (Maybe it really is personal if your car, or head, is a target for droppings.)
JUST WATCHED
MUST WATCH
Pigeon refuses to leave football game 02:12
Hearing about this amazing visual recall on a radio segment, Dr. Richard Levenson wondered, out of a kind of "intellectual playfulness," if he could harness that pigeon power for good. Levenson is a professor and vice chair for strategic technologies in the department of medical pathology and laboratory medicine at University of California-Davis Medical Center. He wondered "if they could actually do pathology, which is all about visual recall," Levenson said.
In other words, would the proverbial "rat with wings" make a good lab rat with wings? Did the birds have enough of an eagle -- er, pigeon eye to detect cancer in tissue samples?
He got in touch with Dr. Ed Wasserman , a professor of experimental psychology at the University of Iowa. He is also one of the guys scientists flock to when they want to play with pigeon vision.
The collaboration was a success. "It worked spectacularly well," Levenson said. "In fact, Ed (Wasserman) said that the pigeons responded to this visual challenge as well, or better than many other tests."
For the experiment, eight birds were placed in a high-tech box in which they were shown an image a scientist would see under the microscope, along with two boxes. The slides showed relatively straightforward images of cancer cells, and cells that are not cancerous, from actual breast tissue samples. The scientists trained the birds to peck at one box if the sample was malignant, the other if it was benign. The birds trained with 144 images at different magnifications and each got a pellet when it pecked at the box with the right answer.
Over 15 training days the birds were able to tell the difference, even with images they hadn't seen before. The pigeons showed "remarkable" success, getting the right answer 85% of the time. The birds did better with color images than black and white, but when the birds did a little "flocksourcing" and worked together to identify the images, their accuracy rose significantly.
The birds didn't do as well classifying suspicious mammographic densities or masses. In that case birds mostly memorized and weren't as successful identifying the novel cases. Inexperienced human students may also struggle with these same images.
Related: Key to racing pigeons is motivation
The difficulty does not surprise Dr. Debra Monticciolo, chairwoman of the American College of Radiology Breast Imaging Commission. "Unlike looking at the heart or lungs, which look pretty much the same (in all patients), what makes this field incredibly difficult is that every woman's breast looks different based on different patterns of fat and density patterns," Monticciolo said. "That's why it takes many years' experience to do this kind of work and why people get better at it the more images they study."
JUST WATCHED
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
