<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Post Politics: Breaking Politics News, Political Analysis &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics?wprss=rss_politics</link>
<description>Post Politics from The Washington Post is the source for political news headlines, in-depth politics coverage and political opinion, plus breaking news on the Obama administration and White House, Congress, the Supreme Court, elections and more.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 15:48:14 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 15:48:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Post Politics: Breaking Politics News, Political Analysis &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics?wprss=rss_politics</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>GOP, Democrats slow to budge on strategies to overcome shutdown</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636655/s/321249f2/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cpolitics0Cgop0Edemocrats0Eslow0Eto0Ebudge0Eon0Estrategies0Eto0Eovercome0Eshutdown0C20A130C10A0C0A40C4c136d0A60E2d110E11e30Eb1390E0A29811dbb57f0Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Ipolitics/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A group of leading House Republicans donned lab coats this week and took to a Capitol Hill news conference to plead for passage of a bill that would restore funding for the National Institutes of Health amid the government shutdown.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/gop-democrats-slow-to-budge-on-strategies-to-overcome-shutdown/2013/10/04/4c136d06-2d11-11e3-b139-029811dbb57f_story.html?wprss=rss_politics"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636655/s/321249f2/sc/7/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;div class='mf-viral'&gt;&lt;table border='0'&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td valign='middle'&gt;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/twitter/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fpolitics%2Fgop-democrats-slow-to-budge-on-strategies-to-overcome-shutdown%2F2013%2F10%2F04%2F4c136d06-2d11-11e3-b139-029811dbb57f_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_politics&amp;t=GOP%2C+Democrats+slow+to+budge+on+strategies+to+overcome+shutdown" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/twitter.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/facebook/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fpolitics%2Fgop-democrats-slow-to-budge-on-strategies-to-overcome-shutdown%2F2013%2F10%2F04%2F4c136d06-2d11-11e3-b139-029811dbb57f_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_politics&amp;t=GOP%2C+Democrats+slow+to+budge+on+strategies+to+overcome+shutdown" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/facebook.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/linkedin/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fpolitics%2Fgop-democrats-slow-to-budge-on-strategies-to-overcome-shutdown%2F2013%2F10%2F04%2F4c136d06-2d11-11e3-b139-029811dbb57f_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_politics&amp;t=GOP%2C+Democrats+slow+to+budge+on+strategies+to+overcome+shutdown" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/linkedin.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/gplus/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fpolitics%2Fgop-democrats-slow-to-budge-on-strategies-to-overcome-shutdown%2F2013%2F10%2F04%2F4c136d06-2d11-11e3-b139-029811dbb57f_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_politics&amp;t=GOP%2C+Democrats+slow+to+budge+on+strategies+to+overcome+shutdown" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/googleplus.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/email/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fpolitics%2Fgop-democrats-slow-to-budge-on-strategies-to-overcome-shutdown%2F2013%2F10%2F04%2F4c136d06-2d11-11e3-b139-029811dbb57f_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_politics&amp;t=GOP%2C+Democrats+slow+to+budge+on+strategies+to+overcome+shutdown" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/email.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965338061/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/321249f2/sc/7/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965338061/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/321249f2/sc/7/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965338061/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/321249f2/sc/7/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965338061/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/321249f2/sc/7/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965338061/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/321249f2/sc/7/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965338061/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/321249f2/sc/7/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965338061/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/321249f2/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/176965338061/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/321249f2/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/176965338061/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/321249f2/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:35:47 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/gop-democrats-slow-to-budge-on-strategies-to-overcome-shutdown/2013/10/04/4c136d06-2d11-11e3-b139-029811dbb57f_story.html?wprss=rss_politics</guid>
<dc:creator>Zachary A. Goldfarb</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>Explore real-time news, visually
GOP, Democrats slow to budge on strategies to overcome shutdown
Video: Republican members of Congress held a news conference Thursday urging the Senate to pass a measure to restore funding to the National Institute of Health.
By Zachary A. Goldfarb , E-mail the writer
A group of leading House Republicans donned lab coats this week and took to a Capitol Hill news conference to plead for passage of a bill that would restore funding for the National Institutes of Health amid the government shutdown.
“Whether it’s pediatric cancer research, diabetes, so many other cures and treatments that are being developed — we don’t want to put them on hold,” Rep. Cathy McMorris Rodgers (Wash.) said Thursday. “We want America to continue to be the leader.”
Graphic
Paul Kane and Josh Hicks
Speaker Boehner has vowed to prevent a first-ever default; his ally says “big bipartisan deal” is needed.
Karen Tumulty and Paul Kane
Republicans’ prospects for retaking the Senate may be hurt by House-driven government shutdown.
For Obama, domestic politics make foreign policy that much harder
Juliet Eilperin
Obama's canceled Asia trip shows how hard it is for him to pursue foreign policy when facing domestic problems.
Sign up for ‘The Showdown’ newsletter
Get the latest news on the budget fight and a possible government shutdown in this daily newsletter.
Yet three days earlier, McMorris Rodgers joined other Republicans in deciding to shut down NIH and other parts of the government after President Obama refused to curtail his health-care law.
McMorris Rodgers, who has a child with Down syndrome, “has always supported the critical medical research at NIH, especially because she has a personal connection to the difference it can make in the lives of millions of families and children with disabilities,” a spokesman said.
In ways big and small, Republicans and Democrats are trying — and often struggling — to square their strategy for overcoming the ongoing government shutdown with their prior positions.
The challenge has been greatest for Republicans, who forced the partial government closure at midnight Monday by refusing to pass a funding bill unless Obama agreed to defund or delay the new health-care law. Many Republicans spent the remainder of the week bemoaning programs that had been closed and trying to restore funding to individual agencies through piecemeal legislation.
Democrats, meanwhile, have faced the challenge of standing unified against the GOP strategy, refusing to agree to open agencies that they generally support. Dozens of Democrats have broken ranks, however, voting with Republicans in favor of restoring funding for the District and for veterans programs.
The net effect is a sort of political cognitive dissonance: Republicans demand to reopen some agencies but not the whole government, while Democrats oppose relief unless everything is restored.
Rep. Randy Neugebauer (Tex.) illustrated the risks of the GOP approach this week when he publicly railed against a National Park Service ranger working at the National World War II Memorial on the Mall. The monument was closed when the government shut down.
In a moment captured on a widely viewed video, Neugebauer stood by a group of veterans and asked the female ranger, “How do you look at them and deny them access?”
The ranger responded, “It’s difficult.” Then the congressman said: “The Park Service should be ashamed of themselves.”
Veterans at the memorial started to defend the ranger by shouting at Neugebauer, “This woman is doing her job,” and telling him to do his.
The congressman’s Facebook page was later inundated with critical messages , including some from the veterans he was aiming to support.
A spokeswoman for Neugebauer did not respond to an e-mail seeking comment.
Other Republican lawmakers have faced criticism for accepting salaries while federal workers aren’t getting paychecks. Rep. Renee L. Ellmers (N.C.), who supported the shutdown, told radio station WTVD in Raleigh that she could not afford to give up her $174,000 salary.
Continued
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
