<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2015 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 21:04:52 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 21:04:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Albert Einstein's special mark on universe</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4bd7656a/sc/32/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A150C110C250Copinions0Cbennett0Eeinstein0Etheory0Eof0Erelativity0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Itech/story01.htm</link>
<description>It has been 100 years since Albert Einstein presented his theory of general relativity to an audience of scientists. Virtually everyone has heard of Einstein and his theory, but few have any idea of what the theory actually is.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159851361/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bd7656a/sc/32/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159851361/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bd7656a/sc/32/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159851361/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bd7656a/sc/32/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159851361/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bd7656a/sc/32/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159851361/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bd7656a/sc/32/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/244159851361/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bd7656a/sc/32/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/244159851361/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bd7656a/sc/32/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/244159851361/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bd7656a/sc/32/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/244159851361/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bd7656a/sc/32/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/244159851361/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bd7656a/sc/32/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/244159851361/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bd7656a/sc/32/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/244159851361/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4bd7656a/sc/32/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4bd7656a/sc/32/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 20:14:50 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2015/11/25/opinions/bennett-einstein-theory-of-relativity/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/111104074239-albert-einstein-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/111104074239-albert-einstein-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Facebook Twitter Instagram
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Albert Einstein's special mark on the universe
By Jeffrey Bennett
Updated 1910 GMT (0310 HKT) November 25, 2015
10 photos: Albert Einstein's theory of general relativity
Albert Einstein's theory of general relativity completely overturned our understanding of the nature of gravity, space and time.
Hide Caption
1 of 10
10 photos: Albert Einstein's theory of general relativity
Scientists had thought the universe would slow down its expansion because of gravity, but a newly discovered phenomenon called dark energy is causing the expansion to speed up.
Hide Caption
2 of 10
10 photos: Albert Einstein's theory of general relativity
Einstein's ideas about gravity have led to predictions of black holes, which occur when the mass of an entire star is compressed into a tiny volume.
Hide Caption
3 of 10
10 photos: Albert Einstein's theory of general relativity
How will the universe end? Will it expand forever or collapse back into a point? With the discovery of dark energy, the answer seems clear -- the universe will expand forever at an ever-increasing rate.
Hide Caption
4 of 10
10 photos: Albert Einstein's theory of general relativity
The Dark Energy Survey experiment is situated high on a mountaintop in Chile.  It uses the 4-meter wide Victor Blanco Telescope to image galaxies and supernovae billions of light years away to understand the expansion history of the universe and to predict its future.
Hide Caption
5 of 10
10 photos: Albert Einstein's theory of general relativity
The camera for the Dark Energy Survey consists of 570 million pixels and is designed to be able to see galaxies located far from the Earth.  Astronomers will use data taken over five years to study the shape of the universe and how that shape changes over time.
Hide Caption
6 of 10
10 photos: Albert Einstein's theory of general relativity
The universe is made of three distinct substances. Familiar kinds of matter takes up 4.6%.  A mysterious substance called dark matter makes up 24%. And dark energy, which acts like a repulsive form of gravity, accounts for about 71.4%.
Hide Caption
7 of 10
10 photos: Albert Einstein's theory of general relativity
Einstein's theory of relativity reveals that gravity is a bending of space.  One of the predictions of the theory is that two closely orbiting astronomical bodies will lose energy by a phenomenon called gravitational waves.
Hide Caption
8 of 10
10 photos: Albert Einstein's theory of general relativity
The Laser Interferometer Gravitational-Wave Observatory is designed to measure ripples in space called gravitational waves.  Along with its sister facility in Louisiana, this detector in Hanford, Washington, can detect a pair of orbiting black holes up to 620 million light years away.
Hide Caption
9 of 10
10 photos: Albert Einstein's theory of general relativity
The GPS in modern cars or phones is a practical application of Einstein's ideas. The system relies on a constellation of 24 satellites orbiting the Earth.  Without Einstein's theory, in a single day, the system would tell you that you were in a location six miles away from where you actually are.
Hide Caption
10 of 10
Story highlights
It has been 100 years since Albert Einstein presented his theory of general relativity to the world
Jeffrey Bennett: Relativity is necessary to comprehend the universe as we know it; we should all know it
Jeffrey Bennett is the author of "What is Relativity? An Intuitive Introduction to Einstein's Ideas, and Why They Matter" (Columbia University Press, 2014). His 2015 Relativity Tour has taken him to 25 cities to an audience of 10,000 people. He is  the author of six children's books that are being read by astronauts aboard the International Space Station for the Story Time From Space program. The opinions expressed in this commentary are solely those of the author.
(CNN)
It has been exactly 100 years since Albert Einstein presented his theory of general relativity to an audience of scientists on November 25, 1915. While virtually everyone has heard of Einstein and his theory, very few people have any idea of what the theory actually is.
This is a shame, not only because there is a great public thirst for understanding of it, but also because relativity is important, for at least four major reasons.
Jeffrey Bennett
General relativity provides our modern understanding of space, time and gravity -- which means it's crucial to almost everything we do in physics and astronomy. For example, you cannot understand black holes, the expansion of the universe or the Big Bang without first understanding the basic ideas of relativity. Though few people realize it, Einstein's famous equation E = mc2 is actually part of the theory of relativity, which means that relativity also explains how the sun shines and how nuclear power works.
A second reason everyone should know about relativity lies in the way it changes our perception of reality. Relativity tells us that our ordinary perceptions of time and space are not universally valid. Instead, space and time are intertwined as four-dimensional space-time.
In our ordinary lives, we perceive only three dimensions—length, width and depth—and we assume that this perception reflects reality. However, in space-time, the four directions of possible motion are length, width, depth and time. (Note that time is not "the" fourth dimension; it is simply one of the four.)
Read More
Although we cannot picture all four dimensions of space-time at once, we can imagine what things would look like if we could. In addition to the three spatial dimensions of space-time that we ordinarily see, every object would be stretched out through time. Objects that we see as three-dimensional in our ordinary lives would appear as four-dimensional objects in space-time. If we could see in four dimensions, we could look through time just as easily as we look to our left or right. If we looked at a person, we could see every event in that person's life. If we wondered what really happened during some historical event, we'd simply look to find the answer.
To see why this is so revolutionary, imagine that you met someone today who deeply believed that Earth is the center of the universe. You would probably feel sorry for this person, knowing that his or her entire world view is based on an idea disproven more than 400 years ago.
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Can we solve the mysteries of the universe? – Deep in the Kitakami Mountains of Japan, a group of impassioned scientists are working on proposals for a revolutionary project: a machine that will hunt for dark matter. The aim of the International Linear Collider (ILC) is to shed light on the mystery of what makes up most of the universe. This problem has been pursued for millennia, but could this machine hold the key? Here, we take a closer look at the ILC and go on a journey through time to look at some of the inventions that led to the most significant breakthroughs in scientific history. Gallery by Monique Rivalland
Hide Caption
1 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Atom smasher – The machine is colossal. Once built, it will consist of two opposing tunnels that run underground for 31km -- over 10 times bigger than the current largest linear particle accelerator in the world. But what is a particle accelerator? Think of it as an atom smasher,  a device that propels particles -- in this case electrons and positrons -- towards each other at extremely high speeds (almost the speed of light) so that they collide and create a myriad of other subatomic particles that otherwise might not exist or that we might not be able to see. Observing these particles could teach us critical things about our origins and even uncover entirely new dimensions.
Hide Caption
2 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
What the experts say – Scientists estimate that we remain in the dark about a mind-boggling 96% of the universe. Brian Foster, European Regional Director of the International Collider Collaboration and former professor of physics at Oxford University explained to CNN how the ILC would "recreate the conditions fractions of a second after the Big Bang that created our universe." "If we are lucky," he added, "the ILC will detect a whole new family of particles that might help us to realize Einstein's dream of uniting all the theories of physics into one overarching theory." Decisions on the multi-billion dollar machine looks likely to start by 2015 and construction would take 8-10 years.
Hide Caption
3 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Boson breakthrough – Plans for the ILC follow the recent discovery of the elusive Higgs Boson, which resulted in professors Peter Higgs and Francois Englert winning the Nobel Prize in Physics last month. The Higgs Boson, a subatomic particle that may help us understand why other particles have mass, was proposed by the two winners (and Robert Brout) back in 1964 but only proved last year by use of a circular particle accelerator called the Large Hadron Collider (pictured) at CERN.
Hide Caption
4 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Super HILAC 1972 – Two scientists show the scale of an earlier accelerator at the U.S. Department of Energy's Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory. The Super HILAC (Super Heavy Ion Linear Accelerator) was one of the first accelerators that could accelerate the ions of all known natural elements to energies where they could be smashed apart. The lab is aptly named after Ernest Lawrence who invented the first circular accelerator at the University of California, Berkeley, back in 1929.
Hide Caption
5 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Bubble chamber 1970 – It looks like a prop from a sci-film but in fact it's a research vessel called a bubble chamber. The bubble chamber was first used back in 1970 to detect subatomic particles called neutrinos. By filling the device with super hot liquid hydrogen scientists were able to watch particles interact. This 15-foot version was installed in the Bubble Chamber Building at U.S. research center Fermilab in 1971. Now obsolete, the chamber has been on public display since 2004.
Hide Caption
6 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Discovery of quarks 1968 – Up, Down, Strange, Charm, Bottom and Top. These are the six 'flavors' of quarks. But you can't taste them -- they're the elementary particles that make up bigger particles such as neutrons and protons. Quarks exist only fleetingly outside of these particles and thus only be detected by their behaviour in high-energy collisions, which is precisely what happened back in 1968 at the Stanford Linear Accelerator Center (pictured), when scientists observed Up and Down quarks. Initially proposed by Murray Gell-Mann and George Zweig in 1964, the discovery of quarks gave further credence to the "Standard Model" of physics and prior to the discovery of a Higgs Boson was widely regarded as the most significant advancement in physics of the last 50 years.
Hide Caption
7 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Nuclear chain reactor 1942 – In the throes of World War II, an important letter arrived for President Franklin D. Roosevelt. Written by Hungarian scientist Léo Szilárd and signed by Albert Einstein, the letter warned the President that Germany may be working on a powerful bomb. For the previous 10 years Szilárd, along with Italian scientist Enrico Fermi, had been experimenting with nuclear chain reactions and had filed a patent for a simple nuclear chain reactor. Finally, on December 2, 1942, the first artificial nuclear chain reaction took place in a racquets court at the University of Chicago (artist's impression). This launched the Manhattan Project and three years later the U.S. produced the first atomic bomb.
Hide Caption
8 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Electron microscope 1933 – Szilárd was a canny young scientist who also filed a patent for the electron microscope back in 1928. However, it was Ernst Ruska in 1933 who managed to build the first electron microscope that exceeded the resolution of a standard light microscope. His invention, today an everyday piece of research equipment, used electron beams to illuminate tiny specimens and produce a magnified image of their structure.
Hide Caption
9 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
The Geiger counter 1932 – This very instrument was used by the scientist Sir James Chadwick, who discovered the neutron. As a young man he studied radiation in Germany under the creator of the counter, Hans Geiger. The Geiger counter detects the emission of nuclear radiation and is perhaps one of the world's best known radiation instruments. Still in Germany when WW1 broke out, Chadwick spent a few years in a detention camp west of Berlin, but after the war went on to be knighted for his achievements in physics.
Hide Caption
10 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Einstein's theory of relativity 1916 – The most famous equation ever written by arguably the most famous scientist ever to live, Einstein's greatest tool was his brain. This is the earliest and longest manuscript on relativity that he ever wrote. In it he negates many assumptions made in earlier physical theories and redefines concepts of space, time, matter, energy, and gravity. While the equation denotes his theory of special relativity, which is concerned with light, Einstein's theory of general relativity helps us to understand planetary dynamics and the evolution of the universe.
Hide Caption
11 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Cathode used to discover electron 1897 – This apparatus was used to discover the electron. In 1896, in Cambridge, Joseph John Thomson began experiments on cathode rays. Thomson showed that the cathode rays were particles with a negative charge and much smaller than an atom. They were later named electrons and in 1906 Thomson was awarded the Nobel Prize in physics for discovering one of the fundamental building blocks of matter.
Hide Caption
12 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Ionisation chamber 1896 – This device was developed by French physicist Pierre Curie and used by him and his wife, Marie Curie, in radioactivity investigations. Both were awarded the Nobel Prize in physics alongside Henri Becquerel in 1903 for their pioneering work in spontaneous radioactivity -- a term that Marie coined. Marie Curie went on to use her knowledge of radioactivity extensively in medicine, for example to treat tumors. With it, she also discovered the elements polonium and radium.
Hide Caption
13 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Faraday ring 1831 – It may not look very complicated, but when Michael Faraday spent 10 days winding two long pieces of copper wire around an iron ring, he may not have realized the magnitude of his what he was doing. When he passed an electric current through one coiled wire, it induced electricity in the other -- he had created the first electric transformer. Today, transformers are crucial to mass supply of electricity to towns and cities as they reduce high-voltage electricity generated by power stations to a lower, safer voltage.
Hide Caption
14 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Glass prism 1800 – This is the glass prism used by Sir William Herschel to discover infrared radiation. He discovered this invisible type of radiation by studying the area just past red on the color spectrum. To his surprise, it was hotter than all the rest. He was the first person to discover forms of light that are not visible to the human eye. Oh yes, and he also discovered Uranus and wrote 24 symphonies.
Hide Caption
15 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Isaac Newton's apple tree 1687 – Could this really be the tree under which Sir Isaac Newton sat and conceived the universal theory of gravity as an apple conked him on the head? Well, we're pretty sure it isn't, considering the story itself is widely considered to be apocryphal. But, according to the Isaac Newton Institute for Mathematical Sciences at the University of Cambridge, where Newton was a fellow, it was taken as a cutting from the alleged tree at Newton's birthplace in Woolsthorpe Manor, UK. Other alleged cuttings have been replanted as far as Nebraska, Vancouver, and Tokyo.
Hide Caption
16 of 17
17 photos: A journey of discovery: the inventions that taught us everything we know
Galileo's telescope circa 1640 – Here are two of the telescopes belonging to Italian astronomer Galileo Galilei, who was famous for the improvements he made to the instrument. With his advancements in observational astronomy he was the first to see craters on the moon and confirmed the four largest satellites of Jupiter.
Hide Caption
17 of 17
Now imagine that you met someone who still believed that time and space are independent and absolute -- which, of course, describes almost everyone -- even though we've known that's not the case for a century now. Shouldn't we feel equally sorry for all who hold this modern misconception?
It seems especially unfortunate once you realize that the ideas of relativity are not particularly difficult to understand. Indeed, I believe we could begin teaching relativity in elementary school in much the same way that we teach young children about the existence of atoms, even though few will ever study quantum mechanics.
My third reason for believing relativity is important lies in what Einstein's discovery tells us about human potential. The science of relativity may seem disconnected from most other human endeavors, but I believe Einstein himself proved otherwise. Throughout his life, Einstein argued eloquently for human rights, human dignity and a world of peace and shared prosperity. His belief in underlying human goodness is all the more striking when you consider that he lived through both World Wars, that he was driven out of Germany by the rise of the Nazis, that he witnessed the Holocaust that wiped out more than six million of his fellow Jews, and that he saw his own discoveries put to use in atomic bombs.
Albert Einstein's colossal mistake (Opinion)
No one can say for sure how he maintained his optimism in the face of such tragedies, but I see a connection to his discovery of relativity. Einstein surely recognized that a theory that so challenged our perceptions of reality might have been dismissed out of hand at other times in history, but that we now live in a time when, thanks to the process that we call science, the abundant evidence for relativity allowed for its acceptance.
This willingness to make judgments based on evidence shows that we are growing up as a species. We have not yet reached the point where we always show the same willingness in all our other endeavors, but the fact that we've done it for science suggests we have the potential.
Finally, on a philosophical level, relativity is profound. Only about a month before his death in 1955, Einstein wrote: "Death signifies nothing ... the distinction between past, present and future is only a stubbornly persistent illusion." As this suggests, relativity raises interesting questions about what the passage of time really means.
Because these are philosophical questions, they do not have definitive answers, and you will have to decide for yourself what these questions mean to you. But I believe that one thing is clear. Einstein showed that even though space and time can independently differ for different observers, the four-dimensional space-time reality is the same for everyone.
This implies that events in space-time have a permanence to them that cannot be taken away. Once an event occurs, in essence it becomes part of the fabric of our universe. Every human life is a series of events, and this means that when we put them all together, each of us is creating our own, indelible mark on the universe. Perhaps if everyone understood that, we might all be a little more careful to make sure that the mark we leave is one that we are proud of.
So there you have it. Relativity is necessary to comprehend the universe as we know it, it helps us understand the potential we all share when we put our brains to work for the common good, and if we all understood it we might treat each other a little more kindly.
Isn't it time that everyone discerns Albert Einstein's amazing ideas?
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
An artist's illustration shows a binary black hole found in the quasar at the center of the Markarian 231 galaxy. Astronomers using NASA's Hubble Space Telescope discovered the galaxy being powered by two black holes "furiously whirling about each other," the space agency said in a news release.
Hide Caption
1 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
An artist's impression of what a black hole might look like. In February, researchers in China said they had spotted a super-massive black hole 12 billion times the size of the sun.
Hide Caption
2 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
Are there are oceans on any of Jupiter's moons? The Juice probe shown in this artist's impression aims to find out. Picture courtesy of ESA/AOES
Hide Caption
3 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
Astronomers have discovered powerful auroras on a brown dwarf that is 20 light-years away. This is an artist's concept of the phenomenon.
Hide Caption
4 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
Venus, bottom, and Jupiter shine brightly above Matthews, North Carolina, on Monday, June 29. The apparent close encounter, called a conjunction, has been giving a dazzling display in the summer sky. Although the two planets appear to be close together, in reality they are millions of miles apart.
Hide Caption
5 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
Jupiter's icy moon Europa may be the best place in the solar system to look for extraterrestrial life, according to NASA. The moon is about the size of Earth's moon, and there is evidence it has an ocean beneath its frozen crust that may hold twice as much water as Earth. NASA's 2016 budget includes a request for $30 million to plan a mission to investigate Europa. The image above was taken by the Galileo spacecraft on November 25, 1999. It's a 12-frame mosaic and is considered the the best image yet of the side of Europa that faces Jupiter.
Hide Caption
6 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
This nebula, or cloud of gas and dust, is called RCW 34 or Gum 19. The brightest areas you can see are where the gas is being heated by young stars. Eventually the gas burst outward like champagne after a bottle is uncorked. Scientists call this champagne flow. This new image of the nebula was captured by the European Space Organization's Very Large Telescope in Chile. RCW 34 is in the constellation Vela in the southern sky. The name means "sails of a ship" in Latin.
Hide Caption
7 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
The Hubble Space Telescope captured images of Jupiter's three great moons -- Io, Callisto, and Europa -- passing by at once.
Hide Caption
8 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
A massive galaxy cluster known as SDSS J1038+4849 looks like a smiley face in an image captured by the Hubble Telescope. The two glowing eyes are actually two distant galaxies. And what of the smile and the round face? That's a result of what astronomers call "strong gravitational lensing." That happens because the gravitational pull between the two galaxy clusters is so strong it distorts time and space around them.
Hide Caption
9 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
Using powerful optics, astronomers have found a planet-like body, J1407b, with rings 200 times the size of Saturn's. This is an artist's depiction of the rings of planet J1407b, which are eclipsing a star.
Hide Caption
10 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
A patch of stars appears to be missing in this image from the La Silla Observatory in Chile. But the stars are actually still there behind a cloud of gas and dust called Lynds Dark Nebula 483. The cloud is about 700 light years from Earth in the constellation Serpens (The Serpent).
Hide Caption
11 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
This is the largest Hubble Space Telescope image ever assembled. It's a portion of the galaxy next door, Andromeda (M31).
Hide Caption
12 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
NASA has captured a stunning new image of the so-called "Pillars of Creation," one of the space agency's most iconic discoveries. The giant columns of cold gas, in a small region of the Eagle Nebula, were popularized by a similar image taken by the Hubble Space Telescope in 1995.
Hide Caption
13 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
Astronomers using the Hubble Space pieced together this picture that shows a small section of space in the southern-hemisphere constellation Fornax. Within this deep-space image are 10,000 galaxies, going back in time as far as a few hundred million years after the Big Bang.
Hide Caption
14 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
Planetary nebula Abell 33 appears ring-like in this image, taken using the European Southern Observatory's Very Large Telescope. The blue bubble was created when an aging star shed its outer layers and a star in the foreground happened to align with it to create a "diamond engagement ring" effect.
Hide Caption
15 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
This long-exposure image from the Hubble Telescope is the deepest-ever picture taken of a cluster of galaxies. The cluster, called Abell 2744, contains several hundred galaxies as they looked 3.5 billion years ago; the more distant galaxies appear as they did more than 12 billion years ago, not long after the Big Bang.
Hide Caption
16 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
NASA's NuSTAR telescope array generated the first map of radioactivity in the remnants of an exploding star, or supernova. Blue in this image of Cassiopeia A represents radioactive material.
Hide Caption
17 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
A supernova was spotted on January 21 in Messier 82, one of the nearest big galaxies. This wide view image was taken on January 22.
Hide Caption
18 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
The M82 supernova, seen here, has been designated SN2014J because it is the 10th supernova detected in 2014. At 11.4 million light years from Earth, it is the closest Type Ia supernova recorded since systematic studies with telescopes began in the 1930s.
Hide Caption
19 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
Is that a giant hand waving at us? Actually, it's what's left of a star that died and exploded a long time ago. Astronomers nicknamed it the "Hand of God." NASA's Nuclear Spectroscopic Telescope Array, or NuSTAR , took this image in high-energy X-rays, shown in blue. The image was combined with images from another space telescope, the Chandra X-ray Observatory.
Hide Caption
20 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
The Hubble Space Telescope captured this image of the Southern Pinwheel Galaxy, one of the largest and closest galaxies of its kind. The center of the galaxy is mysterious , researchers say, because it has a double nucleus -- a supermassive black hole that may be ringed by a lopsided disc of stars, giving it the appearance of a dual core.
Hide Caption
21 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
Hubble scientists say this is the best-ever view of the Tarantula Nebula, which is located in one of our closest galactic neighbors, the Large Magellanic Cloud.
Hide Caption
22 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
Those spots on our sun appear small, but even a moderate-sized spot is about as big as Earth . They occur when strong magnetic fields poke through the sun's surface and let the area cool in comparison to the surrounding area.
Hide Caption
23 of 24
24 photos: Wonders of the universe
This Hubble image looks a floating marble or a maybe a giant, disembodied eye. But it's actually a nebula with a giant star at its center. Scientists think the star used to be 20 times more massive than our sun, but it's dying and is destined to go supernova.
Hide Caption
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
