<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 02:50:25 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Soccer: Thorir takes over at Inter Milan</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/15/sport/football/erick-thorir-inter-milan-football/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/15/sport/football/erick-thorir-inter-milan-football/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>One of European football's grandest clubs has a new owner, with an Indonesian billionaire shaking up the established order in Italy's Serie A.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 12:37:14 EDT</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Indonesian Erick Thorir takes over at Inter Milan
October 15, 2013 -- Updated 1635 GMT (0035 HKT)
Inter Milan fans will see a foreign owner at the San Siro for the first time in the club's history.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Inter Milan purchased by Indonesian billionaire Erick Thorir
Thorir also owns stakes in the Philadelphia 69ers and soccer's DC United
Inter become just the second Italian team to come under foreign ownership
A U.S. consortium purchased a controlling stake in Roma in 2011
(CNN) -- One of European football's grandest clubs has a new owner, with an Indonesian billionaire shaking up the established order in Italy's Serie A.
Tycoon Erick Thorir is only the second foreign owner in the Italian first division after acquiring a 70% stake in three-time European champions Inter Milan.
He has added Inter to what is fast become a comprehensive sporting profile after becoming the first Asian to own a stake in an NBA team as part of a consortium which purchased the Philadelphia 76ers in 2011.
Sami Khedira gave Germany an early lead against the Republic of Ireland as they booked their passage to the 2014 World Cup finals.
Romelu Lukaku scored both Belgium's goals in the 2-1 away win over Croatia which ensured their qualification for Brazil 2014.
Switzerland's Michael Lang scored the crucial second goal in their 2-1 win in Albania to clinch qualification for football's global showcase.
Ukraine's Andriy Yarmolenko celebrates his crucial goal as they beat Poland 1-0 in Kharkiv to keep alive their hopes of qualification from Group H.
Wayne Rooney made the much needed breakthrough for England against Montenegro at Wembley as they remained top of Group H with a 4-1 victory.
Alexander Samedov was on target for Russia as they boosted their qualification hopes with a 4-0 victory against minnows Luxembourg.
Robin van Persie scored a hat-trick in an 8-1 thrashing of Hungary by his Dutch team who have topped Group D.
German joy
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
