<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 02:50:25 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>What next for royal artist?</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/15/sport/frankel-queen-levine-portrait-horse-racing/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/15/sport/frankel-queen-levine-portrait-horse-racing/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>Never work with children or animals they say.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 10:12:40 EDT</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>&gt;&gt;
Australian super horse Black Caviar retires
"This beautiful creature is a divine creation ... Life is a pretty miraculous phenomenon that we're all part of, it's an unfolding miracle. An animal like Frankel, if you contemplate it, is a divine creation."
Read: Racing but not as you know it
Levine's striking portrait of the Queen -- entitled "Lightness of Being" -- was unveiled in 2004 and the photographer suggests sport's foremost thoroughbred shares a magisterial quality with the world's most famous monarch.
The artist depicted the Queen in full white regalia with her eyes closed almost as if she was inhaling the essence of power.
"They're supreme beings with iconic status," Levine told CNN. "We were really interested in shooting icons, they don't necessarily have to be human icons.
"I saw it when I looked at (Frankel's) head shot, you could see that this really was a great being.
"For some reason it made me think of emperors on a coin, you get a profile shot of a head of state, somehow it was aligning with that contextually."
While Queen Elizabeth's reign is very much ongoing, Frankel ended his two-year racing career with a perfect 14-0 winning record.
He is now enjoying a lucrative retirement with trainers paying £125,000 ($199,000) to breed their mares with ahorse
"Frankel is a superstar," explained Levine. "He's got a huge following. It was a real challenge, to take it somewhere different in the land of equine images, portraiture and art.
"I wanted to do something that portrayed Frankel as extraordinary. He really is an octave about greatness. I wanted to convey the extremity of what he is."
British colt Frankel powers home to take the Champion Stakes at Ascot -- his 14th consecutive win.
Queen Elizabeth II presents Frankel's jockey Tom Queally with the Champion Stakes trophy at Ascot.
Australian mare Black Caviar, pictured with trainer Peter Moody, remains unbeaten in 22 races.
Frankel has even been immortalised in a surrealist painting. Artist Michael Kirkbride's "Armchair Ride" was inspired by a poem about Frankel demolishing the field in last year's 2000 Guineas race.
Under the stewardship of jockey Queally, the four-year-old Frankel has brought home winnings of just over $4 million for his owners.
Trainer Henry Cecil has put his all into schooling Frankel and even installed a closed circuit TV system in the horse's stable to ensure he is safe at night.
Both Black Caviar and Frankel have spawned a micro marketing industry. Frankel flags were the order of the day at Glorious Goodwood this year. There is also an impressive line in Frankel fleeces, mugs and hats available online.
The Australian High Commission in the UK had to hold a ballot for Ascot tickets, such was the demand from the expat community to see Black Caviar on British soil. She also has an online store with cufflinks selling for $42.
Frankel and Black Caviar even have their own Twitter handles. "Goodbye UK, and thank you for your hospitality Your Majesty," tweeted @blackcaviar2006 after coming to Britain. "I enjoyed my time in Newmarket and racing at Royal Ascot xx."
In Frankel's new life as a stud, the in-demand colt is expected to command a fee of $160,000 each time he sires a foal.
Super stud
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
