<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 02:50:25 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Is it Berlusconi's final farewell?</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/15/world/europe/silvio-berlusconi-goodbye-nina-dos-santos/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/15/world/europe/silvio-berlusconi-goodbye-nina-dos-santos/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>Some Italians realize their former leader is no longer good for them.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 14:14:48 EDT</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Silvio Berlusconi, so long! But we might not see you again soon
By Nina dos Santos, CNN
October 15, 2013 -- Updated 1445 GMT (2245 HKT)
Silvio Berlusconi gestures as he takes part at a People of Freedom meeting in Rome on September 9, 2009. Italy's three-time former prime minister received a four-year sentence for tax fraud -- and although he may only serve one year, his political future has been thrown into doubt.
Berlusconi delivers a speech during a rally of his party 'Il Popolo della liberta' (People of the Freedom - PDL) in Rome on February 7, 2013.
In Italy's February elections, the former prime minister appealed to Italian voters by denouncing the unpopular austerity policies of technocrat Mario Monti.
Former President George W. Bush and Berlusconi share a moment during a South Lawn arrival ceremony at the White House on October 13, 2008.
The late Moammar Gadhafi attends a meeting with Berlusconi in Rome on June 10, 2009.
President Barack Obama and first lady Michelle Obama welcome Berlusconi to the G20 dinner in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, on September 24, 2009.
Berlusconi waves to journalists as he leaves San Raffaele hospital in Milan on December 17, 2009. Berlusconi suffered severe facial wounds in a violent attack.
Russian Prime Minister Vladimir Putin and Berlusconi attend a press conference in Lesmo, Italy, on April 26, 2010.
Berlusconi listens during a debate at the Senate on December 13, 2010, in Rome, Italy.
Berlusconi reacts during the presentation of politician Antonio Razzi's book "Le mie mani pulite" (My clean hands) at the Italian parliament in Rome on February 1, 2012.
An official visit to Villa Madama on January 18, 2011. A Milan court sentenced the flamboyant politician to four years in prison for tax evasion, but he appealed the decision.
Berlusconi arrives at the Chancellery to meet with German Chancellor Angela Merkel on January 12, 2011 in Berlin, Germany.
Berlusconi passes by Carabinieri guards prior a meeting with Russia's President at Villa Madama palace in Rome on February 16, 2011.
AC Milan players and AC Milan chairman Berlusconi celebrate after winning the Luigi Berlusconi Trophy at Giuseppe Meazza Stadium on August 21, 2011, in Milan, Italy.
HIDE CAPTION
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Silvio Berlusconi, Italy's ultimate comeback king, might finally be out of politics for good
Nina dos Santos says the political message is now more than just goodbye -- this time it's good riddance
For all his pantomime charades however, he did earn some respect for staying the course
But Italians appear to have finally realized he is no longer good for the country
Editor's note: Nina dos Santos is a London-based news anchor and correspondent. She is the host of CNN International's twice-daily global business show World Business Today and regularly presents various feature shows including CNN Marketplace Europe. Follow her on Twitter.
London (CNN) -- Latin goodbyes sometimes lack the finality of Anglo-Saxon ones.
In Italian, for instance, the expression "arrivederci" doesn't mean a definite adieu but rather "until we meet again."
Yet even in Italy there are occasions when people want their farewells to be lasting, as the country's ultimate comeback king may finally have to concede.
After being convicted for tax fraud and facing more legal woes for cavorting with an underage call girl , Silvio Berlusconi will likely be banned from public office soon.
A desperate attempt by the three-time prime minister to thwart a vote on his exclusion backfired in spectacular fashion, when even his anointed heir refused to follow orders and torpedo the government.
The message to Berlusconi this time was not just "goodbye," but "good riddance."
Silvio Berlusconi's last stand?
Still, as lifelong opponents prepare to raise a glass to a fresh era, one can't help but wonder what this new Italy will look like without its familiar Silvio sideshow.
READ MORE: Monti says Berlusconi will not be part of Italian parliament again
What's next for Berlusconi?
If the 77-year-old's antics were a welcome distraction from the country's slide down the world league tables, then what vision -- if any -- will this disparate bunch of successors have?
Why didn't Berlusconi witness testify?
Since rising to prominence during the power vacuum that followed Italy's corruption scandals in the 1990s, Berlusconi has dominated the political and business arena for more than two decades.
His detractors will say he has done countless damage to their nation's reputation and taken a wrecking ball to its economy -- leaving generations to come with a hefty price to pay.
Furthermore, Berlusconi has undermined the rule of law by pursuing a personal vendetta against the judiciary and used parliament to pass bills that protected his interests.
Berlusconi's confidence and swagger were contagious
Nina dos Santos
But for all his pantomime charades at home and abroad, one has to acknowledge the ex-premier has earned some quiet respect for at least staying the course.
He may have been a polarizing figure but that cheeky charisma and flagrant disregard for the rules left no one unaware of who he was.
Sly old Silvio, for all his schoolboy jokes, held together some of the longest-serving governments in the history of the Italian Republic and though his agenda today may not tally with that of a serious country, his party's latest incarnation won a third of the vote at the last elections.
Amanpour explains: Berlusconi
In Italy, one quickly learns that few actually admit to supporting Berlusconi yet each time the country votes his followers flock to the ballot box in droves.
Disfunctional govt. the norm in Italy
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
