<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 02:50:25 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Massive quake kills 107, many missing</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/16/world/asia/philippines-earthquake/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/16/world/asia/philippines-earthquake/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>The death toll from the magnitude-7.1 earthquake in the central Philippines rose to 107 on Wednesday, authorities said. </description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 02:24:54 EDT</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Earthquake strikes Tuesday on a national holiday in the Philippines
It was centered near a town in Bohol province
Dozens of people are still missing
(CNN) -- The death toll from the magnitude-7.1 earthquake in the central Philippines rose to 107 on Wednesday, authorities said.
The quake, which struck Tuesday, injured 276 people and rattled many celebrating a religious holiday.
The bulk of the casualties were in Bohol province.
Dozens of people are missing, and authorities are checking into reports of people trapped in collapsed buildings, the Philippines News Agency reported.
7.1 earthquake rocks Philippines
The quake was centered about 620 kilometers (385 miles) south-southeast of Manila, near Catigbian, and its depth was 20 kilometers (12 miles), according to the U.S. Geological Survey. The Philippines disaster council gave the temblor a slightly higher rating, 7.2 magnitude.
iReport: 'Our building is not safe'
Tuesday was a national holiday, the beginning of the Muslim festival of Eid al-Adha.
There was no widespread threat of a tsunami, the Pacific Tsunami Warning Center said. It warned that earthquakes this large can sometimes cause tsunamis within 100 kilometers of the epicenter.
The earthquake-hit province of Bohol, Philippines. (Credit: Nokia)
Tourist Robert Michael Poole said he was riding a bike in Bohol when the earthquake struck and cracked the road in front of him.
"It was very strong," Poole said. "I live in Tokyo. I am used to earthquakes. But this one was very strong. It shocked a lot of people here."
Poole said he was able to move around and document some of the destruction, including a giant church that was decimated.
"Lucky thing is that it is a holiday here today and it happened at a time when nobody was in the church," Poole said.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
