<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 02:50:25 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Arrest made over LA dry ice explosions </title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/16/travel/los-angeles-airport-dry-ice-arrest/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/16/travel/los-angeles-airport-dry-ice-arrest/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>A suspect was arrested in connection with one of the dry ice explosions at Los Angeles International Airport, police said Tuesday.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 01:44:47 EDT</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Police: Arrest made in Los Angeles airport dry ice explosion
From Dave Alsup, CNN
October 16, 2013 -- Updated 0615 GMT (1415 HKT)
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
There were two dry ice explosions at the airport
One of the incidents occurred Sunday, the other Monday
A suspect is being held on $1 million bond
(CNN) -- A suspect was arrested in connection with one of the dry ice explosions at Los Angeles International Airport, police said Tuesday.
The arrest come on the heels of two incidents at that airport on Sunday and Monday. The suspect, identifed as Dicarlo Bennett, 28, was accused of the Sunday incident, according to a Los Angeles Police Department statement.
He is being held on a $1 million bond and faces a charge of possession of a explosive or destructive device near an aircraft.
Police did not release any information on the suspect or a possible motive.
On Sunday, dry ice in a plastic bottle exploded in an employee restroom at the airport, causing a brief shutdown of Terminal 2, the FBI said. No injuries were reported, and the terminal resumed operations after a brief evacuation.
The other incident occurred Monday at about 8:30 p.m. at the Tom Bradley International Terminal, airport police said,
Three plastic bottles containing dry ice were found, but only one had exploded, police said.
CNN affiliate KCAL said the blast took place in an employee restroom, inaccessible to nonemployees. Nobody was injured in that incident.
Dry ice, which is carbon dioxide in solid form, is used as a refrigerant for meats and ice cream, especially when shipped in a box. When dry ice becomes warm, it transforms into vapor.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
