<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 02:50:25 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Typhoon batters Tokyo area, 14 dead</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/16/world/asia/japan-typhoon-deaths/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/16/world/asia/japan-typhoon-deaths/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>At least 14 people have died and hundreds of flights have been canceled as Typhoon Wipha pummeled the Tokyo area on Wednesday.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 02:29:05 EDT</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Typhoon Wipha hits Tokyo area, killing at least 14
By Yoko Wakatsuki, Junko Ogura and Katie Hunt, CNN
October 16, 2013 -- Updated 0539 GMT (1339 HKT)
Japanese businessmen walk against strong wind and rain as Typhoon Wipha reached Tokyo on Wednesday.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
At least 14 people have died as Typhoon Wipha hits the Tokyo area
Oshima, a small island south of Tokyo, has been hardest hit
More than 500 domestic and international flights were canceled
The typhoon is moving north along the Pacific coast of Japan
Tokyo (CNN) -- At least 14 people have died and hundreds of flights have been canceled as Typhoon Wipha pummeled the Tokyo area on Wednesday.
A local government official in Oshima, a small island 120 km (75 miles) south of Tokyo, said that 13 people died after heavy rain triggered flooding and landslides that blocked roads and crushed houses.
Rescuers were unable to reach about 50 people in the area hit by landslides.
One other woman was confirmed dead after being rescued from a river in Machida, western Tokyo.
More than 500 domestic and international flights were canceled at Tokyo's Narita and Haneda airports and the national rail operator halted bullet train services in central and northern Japan.
The typhoon is moving north along the Pacific coast of Japan and is expected to reach the northernmost island of Hokkaido by late Wednesday.
Tokyo Electric Power Company (TEPCO), the main electricity supplier in Tokyo and central Japan, said blackouts affected more than 56,000 households.
TEPCO, which has been struggling to deal with a series of leaks at its Fukushima Daiichi nuclear plant , said workers at the plant were "on vigil" and accumulated rainwater had been released from storage tanks.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
