<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 19:32:22 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Brangelina's kids: Then and now</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/09/06/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/angelina-jolie-kids-brad-pitt/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/lbKAmJHCG2g/index.html</link>
<description>&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/lbKAmJHCG2g" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 18:31:22 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/09/06/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/angelina-jolie-kids-brad-pitt/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Brangelina's kids: Then and now
September 6, 2013 -- Updated 2042 GMT (0442 HKT)
When we saw this photo of Brad Pitt and Angelina Jolie's brood -- sans father Pitt -- at the Sydney Airport in Australia, we were struck by how much the six Jolie-Pitts have grown. We can remember when ...
Maddox was small enough to fit into this little toy car. The first addition to the Jolie-Pitt family, Maddox was born in Cambodia and adopted by Jolie in 2002, when the actress was still married to Billy Bob Thornton.
In March 2013, a soon-to-be 12-year-old Maddox played soccer with friends in a park.
Zahara Marley was born in Ethiopia and adopted by Jolie in 2005. That same year, Jolie's eventual fiance, Brad Pitt, petitioned to adopt both Zahara and Maddox.
In 2006, Angelina Jolie and Brad Pitt welcomed their daughter Shiloh Nouvel, who was born in Namibia. After her arrival, they confirmed to the media that they were focusing on their growing family and didn't have plans to marry.
Now 7, Shiloh Jolie-Pitt has caught the eye of photographers for her independent sense of style. The middle Jolie-Pitt's preference for short hair has made her a regular feature in celebrity magazines .
Pax Thien was born in Vietnam in 2003, and was adopted into the Jolie-Pitt brood at age 3 in 2007, becoming kid No. 4.
Now 9, Pax was spotted out with his parents and older brother, Maddox, at his dad Pitt's "World War Z" movie premiere in London on June 2, 2013.
Born in Nice, France in 2008, Vivienne (left) and Knox are the youngest Jolie-Pitts -- for now, anyway. The duo have the distinction of appearing at Cannes before they were even born -- their mom famously walked the red carpet of the 2008 film festival to promote her movie "Kung Fu Panda" while very pregnant.
At 5, Vivienne Marcheline is starting to take after her actress mother and grandmother. The budding star will perform alongside her mother in the 2014 live-action retelling of "Sleeping Beauty," "Maleficent."
Now 5, Knox Leon is already a world-traveler. He and his family visited Berlin in the summer before his fifth birthday, and after Labor Day touched down in Australia, where Jolie will reportedly film her next movie, "Unbroken."
Every so often, all eight Jolie-Pitts are caught on camera, as they were here in 2011 in New Orleans.
HIDE CAPTION
Brangelina's kids: Then and now
Maddox Then
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
