<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 19:32:22 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Surprising celebrity flings</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/09/11/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/surprising-celebrity-hookups/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/VHpNflNM8uk/index.html</link>
<description>&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/VHpNflNM8uk" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 18:33:12 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/09/11/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/surprising-celebrity-hookups/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Sharon Osbourne, Jay Leno and more surprising celeb hookups
By Breeanna Hare, CNN
September 11, 2013 -- Updated 1435 GMT (2235 HKT)
The next time Sharon Osbourne sits down on "The Tonight Show with Jay Leno," as she did here in 2006, the world will know what these two both knew then: Osbourne says she and Leno had a "flingy-wingy" when she was 25. (It was before her marriage to Ozzy Osbourne.) Osbourne and Leno may not be the most obvious match, but they're in good company. Click through to see other stars who have found affection in surprising places, too:
Ted Danson and Whoopi Goldberg famously dated in 1993 . The two played on-screen love interests in the comedy "Made In America," and were soon moving the romance off-screen as well.
Cher dropped a bomb during an interview with Bravo's Andy Cohen in June 2013: Not only had she hooked up with Tom Cruise when he was just a budding young star in the early '80s, but she could report that he was one of her top five lovers of all time. Cher, do tell!
Before Britney Spears, Cameron Diaz and Jessica Biel, Justin Timberlake was attached to another star: Fergie pre-Black Eyed Peas.
Whitney Houston and Ray J had an affectionate bond that fueled endless rumors that they were a pair following Houston's 2007 breakup with Bobby Brown.
Let's time-travel back to 1989, when New Kids on the Block wasn't an aging boy band but rather the hottest thing on, well, the block. At the time, it did make sense that Danny Wood would fall for another rising star: Halle Berry.
Perhaps it's because of the timing -- Matt Damon's career was just taking off with "Good Will Hunting" when he hooked up with Winona Ryder-- but it's easy to forget these two were a serious couple between 1997 and 2000.
Yes, before Kanye, Kris or Reggie, Kim Kardashian apparently had a little something going with Nick Lachey after his 2005 divorce from Jessica Simpson. Lachey told Details magazine that they had a date in 2006, but he thinks it was a ploy for Kardashian to be seen with an MTV-famous boy band member.
John Stamos has fond memories of dating Paula Abdul in the late '80s, just as he began starring on "Full House." "She was so adorable, she was America's sweetheart," Stamos told Ellen DeGeneres in 2009 . "She was the biggest star in the world ... and we had the time of our lives."
Glenn Close and Woody Harrelson are said to have become romantic partners for a spell in 1991 , when they performed in the play "Brooklyn Laundry" together.
When Billy Corgan and Tila Tequila got cozy on the red carpet in 2009, the best word to describe most people's reaction was "confused." For whatever reason, the Smashing Pumpkins star seemed to be enjoying the company of reality minx Tequila at Bravo's 2009 "A-List Awards."
In the case of Lisa Kudrow and Conan O'Brien, it seems that like attracted like. According to Kudrow , she and O'Brien dated for a bit prior to her acting career before realizing they were better off as friends. But O'Brien's apparently been a great pal to Kudrow -- she's credited him with helping her launch her career.
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
