<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 18:31:40 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Miguel Angel toasts vintage ace!</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/13/sport/golf/jimenez-wine-hole-in-one-golf/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/LjjchqLRY5E/index.html</link>
<description>If ever there was an appropriate prize for a hole in one, the organizers of the Portugal Masters certainly found it when fun-loving Spanish veteran Miguel Angel Jimenez struck it lucky on the eighth at the Oceanico Victoria Course on the Algarve.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/LjjchqLRY5E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 11:31:19 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/13/sport/golf/jimenez-wine-hole-in-one-golf/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Cheers! Fine vintage is reward for Miguel Angel's hole in one
October 13, 2013 -- Updated 1649 GMT (0049 HKT)
Miguel Angel Jimenez's last win on Tour came at the Hong Kong Open last year and he celebrated in typical style.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Miguel Angel Jimenez claims hole in one at Portugal Masters
Spanish veteran achieves feat with seven iron to 168-yard 8th
Wins 100 bottles of red wine from the organizers
David Lynn claims title after final round 63
(CNN) -- If ever there was an appropriate prize for a hole in one, the organizers of the Portugal Masters certainly found it when fun-loving Spanish veteran Miguel Angel Jimenez struck it lucky on the eighth at the Oceanico Victoria Course on the Algarve.
The Ryder Cup star's seven iron approach to the 168-yard hole proved perfect -- and his reward? -- 100 bottles of red wine to restock his cellar.
The 49-year-old Jimenez is known for his trademark cigars and a love of the grape as well as his outstanding play and was immediately presented with a bottle from his considerable haul by sponsors, the cheekily named SEXY wines, after his round.
The return of golf's 'Mechanic'
Can Presidents Cup survive?
Jimenez came close to extending his own record as the oldest European Tour winner when beaten in a playoff for the Dutch Open by home player Joost Luiten last month but has been off the pace in his latest event.
One of the early morning starters in the final round, Jimenez eventually carded a one-under-par 70 for five under 279, some way off the pace in the $2.71 million tournament.
He has made a fine recovery from breaking his leg in a skiing accident last winter and currently lies 17th in the Race to Dubai standings with nearly a million dollars in prize money to his name.
Read: Jamieson so close to record 59
Jimenez's early heroics proved the perfect backdrop for a battle royale for the honors in Portugal.
Scott Jamieson, who shot a brilliant 60 in the third round, saw his chances disappear after a disappointing back nine, as did overnight leader Paul Waring.
It left the way clear for England's David Lynn to claim the title after an eight-under-par 63 left him one shot clear on 18-under 266.
South African Justin Walters was an emotional second just two weeks after his mother passed away, finishing with a lengthy birdie putt on the testing 18th to seal the runner-up spot.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
