<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 18:31:40 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Motorsport: Marquez closes on title</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/13/sport/motorsport/pedrosa-marquez-malaysia-motorsport/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/BtE8U87fo1g/index.html</link>
<description>Dani Pedrosa repeated his 2012 success at a sweltering Sepang Sunday but his Honda teammate Marc Marquez took another big step towards the MotoGP world title by finishing a fine second.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/BtE8U87fo1g" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 09:50:11 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/13/sport/motorsport/pedrosa-marquez-malaysia-motorsport/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Dani Pedrosa denies teammate Marc Marquez in Malaysia MotoGP
October 13, 2013 -- Updated 1652 GMT (0052 HKT)
Dani Pedrosa sprays his Honda teammate and title leader Marc Marquez as he celebrates his Malaysian MotoGP win.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Dani Pedrosa wins Malaysian MotoGP in Sepang
Honda teammate Marc Marquez in second place
Marquez extends lead in title race over third placed Jorge Lorenzo
MotoGP legend Valentino Rossi in fourth
(CNN) -- Dani Pedrosa repeated his 2012 success at a sweltering Sepang Sunday but his Honda teammate Marc Marquez took another big step towards the MotoGP world title by finishing a fine second.
The 20-year-old Marquez won a thrilling battle with defending champion Jorge Lorenzo for Yamaha to increase his lead over his fellow Spaniard in the championship standings to 43 points.
Marquez can wrap up the title next week at Philip Island in Australia, the first rookie to win the MotoGP premier crown in 35 years.
He admitted that getting the better of Lorenzo, moving ahead for the final time halfway through the 20 lap race was satisfying.
"It was a nice battle with Jorge. I enjoyed it a lot," Marquez told the official MotoGP website.
Lorenzo: Motorcycling is like dancing
Remembering fallen MotoGP star
"The target of this weekend was to finish in front of Jorge," he said,
It left Pedrosa to go unchallenged to the finish for this third win of the season and to close within 11 points of second placed Lorenzo in the title standings.
He took command in 40 degree Celsius temperatures, taking the lead from polesitter Marquez early in the race.
"It's a great feeling to be back... I came back strong," said Pedrosa, who suffered a crash in the last round in Spain after a coming together with Marquez.
Read: Rookie sensation Marquez set to make MotoGP history
The incident earned Marquez a penalty point, his third of the season and a warning.
Lorenzo's teammate, seven-time world champion Valentino Rossi of Italy, finished fourth followed by Spanish Honda rider Alvaro Bautista.
Britain's rising star Cal Crutchlow, who started third on the grid, eventually finished sixth, just ahead of compatriot Bradley Smith.
Malaysia is the 15th race of the 18 round season, with Australia next, followed by Japan and the final race in Valencia.
Marquez is likely to be celebrating the title in front of his home fans in the finale after a remarkable debut season, replacing the retired Casey Stoner in the Repsol Honda line-up.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
