<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Feuilleton - FAZ.NET</title>
<link>http://www.faz.net/aktuell/feuilleton/</link>
<description>F.A.Z. Feuilleton: Meldungen aus den Bereichen Kunst, Kultur und Musik. Kritiken und Rezensionen. Veranstaltungen, Kino, Oper und Theater.</description>
<copyright>Copyright 2001-2013 Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung GmbH. Alle Rechte vorbehalten.</copyright>
<category>Feuilleton - FAZ.NET</category>
<language>de-de</language>
<docs>http://www.faz.net/hilfe/services-newsletter-widgets-rss-feeds-mehr/</docs>
<generator>FAZ.NET</generator>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 5 Oct 2013 17:03:50 +0200</lastBuildDate>
<atom:link href="http://www.faz.net/rss/aktuell/feuilleton/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<image>
        <title>Feuilleton - FAZ.NET</title>
        <url>http://www.faz.net/img/fazlogo_ressort.gif</url>
        <link>http://www.faz.net/aktuell/feuilleton/</link>
    </image>
<item>
    <title>Against Bashing Greece: The Greek Utopia</title>
    <description>&lt;img width="190" height="107" border="0" title="Work in Progress: The Restoration of the Parthenon temple on the Athenian Acropolis is supposed to be finished in several years." alt="Work in Progress: The Restoration of the Parthenon temple on the Athenian Acropolis is supposed to be finished in several years." src="http://media0.faz.net/polopoly_fs/1.2579322!/image/1678177570.jpg_gen/derivatives/article_teaser/1678177570.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bashing of Greece needs a response with the rationality of Greeks: An encounter with greek entrepreneurs who are attempting to achieve in their country what the Germans did after the war. They believe in a Greece 2.0—a new, improved, and more socially aware version of their country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <link>http://www.faz.net/aktuell/feuilleton/against-bashing-greece-the-greek-utopia-12579323.html</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 13:47:00 +0200</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.faz.net/-gqz-7hm9n</guid>
<ExtractedText>Feuilleton
Against Bashing Greece The Greek Utopia
19.09.2013 ·  The Bashing of Greece needs a response with the rationality of Greeks: An encounter with greek entrepreneurs who are attempting to achieve in their country what the Germans did after the war. They believe in a Greece 2.0—a new, improved, and more socially aware version of their country.
Artikel Bilder (10) Lesermeinungen (0)
© F1online
Work in Progress: The Restoration of the Parthenon temple on the Athenian Acropolis is supposed to be finished in several years.
© F1online
Work in Progress: The Restoration of the Parthenon temple on the Athenian Acropolis is supposed to be finished in several years.
Our main question: Does the crisis help in a way for restructuring this country—so that it might be even positive? Or is it at this stage, in 2013, only a bad thing and doesn't help at all? And where are the obstacles?
Achilles V. Constantakopoulos: Greece is going through the 6th consecutive year of recession and people are suffering. I do understand your point that there are some positive effects too. The main one is that we are thinking twice before we make the same mistakes as we made in the past. I have seen legislation and mentality changes — If you would have asked me six years ago: Would I ever imagine seeing that in Greece? I probably would have said no.
For example?
Constantakopoulos: For example, flexibility in labour laws, much less red tape in zoning and permitting, but at the same time, implementation of more suitable environmental structures, going to the essence of things and not just to stop development. The other positive effect is a mentality change in many people. I grew up in a country where profit was considered a bad thing. You had to explain yourself if you were a successful businessperson.
(Deutsche Version von „Die griechische Utopie“)
Now the mentality has changed. People understand that businesses have to be viable and that the interest of entrepreneurs and the state are aligned. I have seen more trust between the public sector and the private sector. So I am a bit more optimistic and overall the sentiment of stability is growing in the country I believe that we reached the bottom and now start to rise. It is the first time in years I have seen so much interest from international companies, funds, investors spending a lot for studies, research, advisers and so on.
So you are optimistic?
Constantakopoulos: I am on optimist, yes. If every company in Greece could hire one or two more persons, then we are out of it.
Maybe you could tell us something about your own company.
Constantakopoulos: Costa Navarino is a new destination in the Mediterranean. We had a vision to create a sustainable prime touristic area in an undiscovered but easily accessible part of the world and place it on the global map. Our approach is following a new model of tourism based on holistic experiences, sustainability, quality, authenticity and close synergies with the local community. Costa Navarino comprises a number of distinct sites, featuring 5-star-hotels, residences, conference facilities, spa and thalassotherapy centers, golf courses and as a wide range of year-round activities for adults and children unique in the Mediterranean.
We have also developed in association with local producers a series of food products, olive and wines, that represent the local gastronomic heritage. An environmental observatory is located in Costa Navarino as well, dedicated to the research and education on the climate and environment in the Mediterranean region, in collaboration with Stockholm University and the Academy of Athens. At the same time, we have developed the Navarino natura hall, an interactive environmental exhibition center for the messenian nature. My late father started buying land back in the 80s, but we opened the first phase in the heart of the Greek crisis at 2010.
South West Peloponnese was one of the less developed areas in Greece and I was pleasantly surprised to see how guests, international media and opinion leaders embraced our vision and supported us from first day. Now it is probably one of a few regions with such a growth, were new hotels, restaurants and shops continuously open. We feel, that despite of the crisis we are heading towards fulfilling our vision – to establish a new sustainable destination in the Mediterranean.
How many people work there?
Constantakopoulos: At the peak we reach 1100 employees. But tourism is a product that has probably the biggest local effect than any other industrial product. According to the regional Panteion University, for every single person hired in Costa Navarino 0.8 jobs are created in the broader area. So we estimate that 2000 new jobs were created. Our goal is to operate all year long. We started flying in March directly from central Europe and we hope that next year the flights can start in February. I think tourism is definitely one if the most important industries that will help us get over the crisis. We shouldn’t forget: 2013 has been the best year for Greek tourism ever.
© Elisseos Kontis/AcePhotography
Achilles V. Constantakopoulos was born in 1971, he graduated from Ecole Hôtelière de Lausanne and is married with 2 children. Since 1995 he is leading Temes S.A. which is responsible for the development of Costa Navarino, a large-scale project in tourism.
Marco Veremis: I am the founder and CEO of Upstream. Upstream is a technology company, producing marketing software for companies who want to use the mobile phone to market to their customers. I was working in London, and my co-founder Alex, who is also Greek, was working in Boston. The reason we set up the business here, when we had the original idea to be one of the first global companies to work on this sector called ‘mobile marketing technology’; this was in 2001 when we started. Basically, the reason we set it up here was because we knew that you had pretty high quality engineering values in Greece.
We have three strong universities, before all Polytechnic in Athens. In Greece parents still potentially even over-invest in their childrens’ education. Not that we have excellent universities, but we do have certain excellent professors. Now, these professors pick the talent and almost always they send this talent off to some of the top universities, especially in the United States and the U.K. and some in Germany as well. You have a lot of Greeks in places like MIT, Stanford and Imperial College and places like that. Most of them study engineering. These guys are super qualified.
We use this kind of talent, which came, of course, at a much lower price than what you would pay in Silicon Valley or in Boston or in London, to set up an original development team. We attacked from day one a global market, because the product we were building was really addressed to companies like Nestle, Coca Cola, Vodafone, Deutsche Telekom—big companies wanting to use mobiles to sell their products to their customers. From the beginning this was 100% export oriented, but the development and the headquarters were here and remain here.
To give you a sense, the company now is among the five largest in this particular space. We employed 250 people of which 80% are engineers. We have nine offices around the world, we sell in 40 countries, and 99% of our revenues come from abroad. Really, the interesting thing is that since we started an eco-system of companies producing similar technology solutions, i.e. mobile related, has grown in Greece to a size that today is about one billion dollars, which are almost exclusively exports, which is actually bigger than olive oil. They employ about 3,500 people, if you put all these companies together. They are growing at the base—that is over 50% a year.
Are they affected by the crisis?
Veremis: The answer I would give is that the crisis changes the situation, because you are getting people who were stuck in non-productive technology companies who were not really innovating. They were not exporting. They didn’t have any prospects of success in the long term. These guys are relocating either to smaller companies that are becoming bigger but are export oriented and innovation oriented—or they are starting their own business. So, my perspective is: I am certainly optimistic about what I am seeing compared to ten years ago. There is no comparison.
So, for example, you now have venture capital money available, which is in the region about 100 million today in Greece from four funds. Ten years ago you had zero. 100 million is a lot. In the U.K. in 2012, I was reading that the total amount of venture capital invested, which is the strongest place in Europe, was one billion. So, it is a good start here. Where I am pessimistic is obviously the popular psyche that is lagging behind.
You have a class of people who are beginning to build companies, or transforming existing companies in a far better way. I think it is a result of the crisis. You have huge advantages in terms of skill in personnel. Nevertheless, this nice world that is developing is still operating on the edge. It is not in any way mainstream. It is not reflected in the way that still the government works or even the popular psyche works. You can see this in the electoral polls still. So, there is disconnect, which is extremely depressing for these few people who are optimistic but then really pessimistic, because they look around and they see that the critical mass is not there yet.
© Elisseos Kontis/AcePhotography
Marco Veremis, born in 1973, is the CEO and co-founder of Upstream which is among the largest mobile marketing companies in the world with presence in over 40 countries. Veremis, who holds a Master’s Degree from Oxford University, is an experienced marketing strategist who worked at leading advertising agencies like Grey Advertising, McCann-Ericsson and DDB London.
Yiannis Retsos: I am the managing director of Electra Hotels and Resorts, a family company operating and owning six hotels in Greece since 1963. I am also the president of the Hellenic Hotel Federation and the first vice president of Sete, which is the association of Greek tourist enterprises. Company-wise I think that this crisis was a major opportunity for actual reconstructions in terms of everything: operation-wise, cost-wise, and debt-wise. in 2008 when the international crisis started,  politicians in Greece were telling us that our country is very well protected and „crisis-proof“. Because of that many people remained confident that nothing would touch us.
On the contrary, whoever started back then, reorganising his business against the inevitably upcoming crisis, today is in a much better shape. By acting in such way my company, since 2008, remained profitable, even in 2012 – despite a severe decrease in our revenues during the last four years. We never had losses during the crisis, though. Now, getting back to your initial question, I think by definition a crisis cannot be perceived well by anybody. It is the actual meaning of the word. In Greece, in 2008 we were talking about 300 billion of GDP, and in 2012 we are talking about less than 200 billion GDP. In four years almost one third of your GDP evaporated. We currently have 1.5 million people unemployed (the highest unemployment rate in the E.U.), which is about, you can say, close to one third of your total active workforce.
So, you understand that the situation and the climate in society is really bad. If you live in Greece, and you stay with this perception, then you see everything in a negative way. But, I think, again by definition, crisis creates opportunities, and this is what you should look at and find ways to capitalise on that. Maybe the biggest advantage so far is this: we see less of the public sector and a more active private sector. Greece was actually depending on his public sector practically in everything: creating new jobs, increasing revenues. We used to borrow money cheap, especially after 2001, when we entered the Eurozone. Instead of investing this money in new projects or innovative ideas, this money went to consumption and basically to the public sector which kept growing enormously.
Now for the first time, as a result of the crisis, we see the private sector getting stronger. The way of doing business is changing. Our government so far, for many years now, was talking about reforms, and politicians were talking about implementing new policies. But they did not have a clear vision and they were acting without any strategy. Today the private sector has a vision; the vision for us in tourism is that in 2021, eight years from today, having Greece among the ten most important countries in the world tourist-wise, in terms of arrivals and in terms of revenues. That is our vision. We have a clear strategy of how to do that. And we are proceeding to the necessary reforms and the implementation of this strategy. That is why we are very confident that we are going to be successful.
So there really is a change.
Retsos: This is a good moment to create new kinds of products. This year we expect to have more than 17 million arrivals. This was a target set by the beginning of the year. Actually now I am pretty confident that we are going to exceed this target. I expect close to 17.5 million arrivals this year. We expect about 11 billion direct touristic revenues. If you multiply that by 2.5, which is about the effect to the rest of the economy, you are talking about 25 billion Euros of revenues related to tourism. This is a huge number.
It is one eighth of the whole economy.
Retsos: Even more than that. We expect this number by 2021 to reach 54 billion Euros and create 300,000 more jobs, which will be huge. The biggest problem we had in the tourism sector, which is already mentioned as a country problem, is that we never had a strategy; we never had a clear brand about our country. In the perception of the potential visitor, Greece was, and still is only, sun and sea. So there was only one product. This product was offered to the tour operators. And they were selling most of the time unbranded.
If a similar “Sun and Sea-Product” was offered by Turkey or by Cyprus but cheaper, then the traveller would rather go there. However, we know that we have many different kinds of products: Sport, adventure tourism, religious tourism, cruise, conventions etc. Our current goals as an industry is to identify these products, give them their identity and then show them abroad in order to sell them. To do so we are trying to cooperate with our public sector, which is represented by the Ministry of Tourism and the national tourism organisation.
The public sector loves the tourism administration - At this moment, is it simply being restructured or is it really improving?
Retsos: Well. (Laughter). It is very easy to talk against the public sector. Everybody, if you ask any Greek, would speak negatively about the public sector. We know that it is very difficult to change something that for many years was built very solidly, but in a wrong way. We see in some aspects that the public sector is trying to change, but it will take many years and a lot of effort. It will also take a lot of willingness from the government.
And it is not getting worse.
Retsos: It cannot get worse. It reached a point that it cannot get worse. But the change in process will be very painful, and it will take a lot of time. We as a private sector are trying to help this process by assuming responsibilities and duties, for example we recently formed a company, which is alive since March under the name “Marketing Greece”, a 100% privately owned company. It is actually the first company like this in the whole world. We have a mutual agreement with the Ministry, and the memorandum of understanding, but we have no relationship in terms of funding or in terms of obligation towards the Ministry.
What this company now tries to do is to create the new brand of the country and its sub-brands, create the marketing strategy in order to show these products abroad and to promote these products abroad. Then the Ministry will step in to advertise them and sell them. We don’t want to get involved in advertising. Now I am very positive about it. I saw how it works during these last four months and the amount of work that has already been done. It is enormous. For decades now we haven’t seen anything in this matter, and now in four months a whole new world is revealing itself in front of us.
Would this have been possible without the crisis?
Retsos: Not at all. This was a request, a dream since 1990 maybe—or maybe more than that: 25 years ago was the first time that the private sector asked or discussed the possibility of creating such a company. But eventually it was the crisis that made it possible! People today in Greece are desperate to see changes, something new, something to believe in. So this made our work easier and now we can present our new project, having people say: Ok, we like that, and we trust you. We are ready to invest in it. “Marketing Greece” is a non-profit-company and the private money invested in this effort will never receive a dividend. But we expect to get money back in our businesses by increasing our industry.
© Elisseos Kontis/AcePhotography
Yiannis A. Retsos was born in 1969  and received his M.P.S. in Hotel Management from Cornell University, with concentration in Hospitality Real Estate Finance. He is the Managing Director of Electra Hotels &amp; Resorts S.A., a hotel company that owns and operates five hotels in Greece. Furthermore, Yiannis A. Retsos is the President of the Hellenic Hotel Federation and the First Vice-President of the Association of Greek Tourist Enterprises (SETE).
So that’s tourism. What about the rest of the greek society?
Retsos: I am positive that the mentality in Greece is changing. Of course, you cannot see that happening really fast. As long as you have people who cannot even satisfy their basic needs. You cannot ask a person to be positive who has a problem of paying rent or getting food for his or her children. Such a citizen cannot have a strategical vision in order to see Greece in five or ten years. But I think that the ones who can do that should do it more actively. And they should be more positive in order to change things so that the person that I described before sees a better day even in a shorter time period.
Aris Kefalogiannis: I am CEO of Gaea and also the vice chairman of the Confederation of Greek Olive Oil industries. I should speak about optimism? Now, I wake up very optimistic in the morning by nature. I become less optimistic when I get into my car and I hear the news on the way to the office. Then I get very optimistic in the office because we are doing very well as a company. Then my optimism drops a little bit when I get back to the car to go back home, and I avoid hearing the television in the evening; that makes me sleep much better in the night.
You sleep well because you feed yourself with excellent Greek products...
Kefalogiannis: Gaea has a vision of being a Greek brand internationally known. The best Greek brands, unanimous with the tradition of antique quality, and Greek food products to internationally promote our cultural culinary heritage: the way we eat at our Greek table, sharing things and enjoying life—which is our eating culture. At the same time, also promoting the Greek Mediterranean diet, which is a very healthy diet, with wellness being a state of mind, where you are healthy, and food is preventative medicine.
You enjoy life, and again, tasty food like the Greek Mediterranean food is part of the joy of life. We are very successful with that vision. Our values are reflected in our products, are reflected in our relationships with our consumers, with our clients, with our suppliers—even with our own team; our team, because we are a company that is a little bit different than the traditional Greek company in the sense that we are not family-owned or run. We are a company that is based on a broader shareholder base and that is also based on a team of people that believe in this vision. So, the third pillar of success for our company is our people.
How many people work for your company?
Kefalogiannis: Right now we are 54 people. We are a small or medium enterprise. But we have hundreds of partners for our products from the agricultural sector. We are spotting the absence of Greek quality products from the international supermarkets all over the world. That was the reason.
I see your products everywhere in Germany now.
Kefalogiannis: Well, Germany is 22% of our sales. It is our most important market. This is how Germany became our number one market in the world: Stiftung Warentest does random tests on the shelves of German supermarkets twice in a period of five years, and we were always the best-bottled olive oil in the German market.
The same tests that proved that the Italians betray us with their olive oil.
Kefalogiannis: Well, the first test was the most important for us. That really changed our destiny in Germany, although we were already doing well. If you offer a real value for money to the consumer, Germany is a market where  you can get long-term success. But generally, behind our success stories are international sales. We are 82% export. The Greek market is 18%. So as a company, we haven’t been affected by the crisis directly. Of course, we have been indirectly because we operate here. What happens in this society around us affects us as much as everybody else.
You said that you are doing well. But as a citizen of this country, was there a time, or is there a time, when you awake in the morning and have the feeling that the whole society might crumble?
Kefalogiannis:  Absolutely. We have this feeling or at least I have it personally. I worry about it. No matter how well a corporation may be doing, you cannot survive in a society that is going down. Although I am an optimist because I see this change in mentality, which is by far the most important thing. At a slow pace but it is taking place. I saw the day before yesterday a very big survey about the trust of Greeks in institutions. I remember a few years back, before the crisis the last in this list was business, companies. Now it is number two. This is a stunning change. So, mentalities are changing, even not as fast as we would like it to, but they are changing; I think this is very important.
© Fotos Elisseos Kontis/AcePhotography
Aris Kefalogiannis, born in 1960, is founder and CEO of Gaea, a Greek Brand working internationally in the field of authentic and innovative Greek Food Products. Additionally, he serves as Vice Chairman of the Greek Confederation of Olive Oil Industries. Prior to that, he was CEO of Proton Marine Services, a London based enterprise offering shipbuilding and shiprepair solutions, and he held the position of financial adviser at the Merchant Investors Group, London.
I think what is also changing is a perception of values. the Greek economic crisis is the result of a society that lost vision in the values. This is what brought the economic crisis as well. We need a new vision, and we need to reinstate values in our society in order to start the real recovery. But I believe this is happening, and once it starts I think it will get an accelerated pace. Because I like marketing, I think all this bad publicity these last few years about Greece has created an awareness. Now that we have stopped being the first bad news all around the world, I think if we accelerate a little bit the reforms and we start growing, this awareness can be turned into a positive thing that can help further the growth of the country—the transformation of the country.
Nobody would believe us that a Greek entrepreneur would say this.
Kefalogiannis: The last thing, but also extremely important, is innovation. Although we are in a sector that nobody would think of that innovation would be important.  We did a great research with Athens Polytechnic. We launch a new product now, which is a worldwide innovation—thanks to the strong research department and the professors there. So, there are some good brains here that can help Greece. We just launched a bar, a fruit and nut bar, which is based on the ancient Greeks, which is a combination of figs, walnuts, sesame. It is a modern product.
An ancient Greek energy bar, legal Olympic doping so to say.
Yiannis Olympios: I am CEO and joint owner of V+O Communications. We are a group of companies in the marketing communications environment. At our headquarter in Athens we are 140 people of eight nationalities, working for about 150 clients across six countries. We started 3 years ago in Athens and now have offices in Tirana, Sofia, Belgrade, Bucharest and Nicosia. I have never lived in such a time of accelerated change as in this period in Greece. As the state receeds, a more activist and articulated consumer demands more from the corporate world and civil society and less from the government. Policy makers and regulators are now externally policed and pushed to bring down the final barriers for entry that had kept oligopolies in place and robbed consumers of choice and competition.
Corporations now must regulate themselves and grow into a virtuous cycle of smaller margins, transparent production processes and a more honestly articulated offer. Media—for years a stagnant pool of political and business interest—is evolving from being on the side of stasis to being a catalyst for change. As the traditional and often corrupted mediating filters of media and government change in scale and influence, so does the new Greek citizen start to hope for a different narration.
Finally, much is written in the Greek and Global press about the “enormous, corrupt and costly public sector” and not much on the private sector corruption that incentivised or even created it. Many sectors for decades enjoyed profit margins unheard of in any other European economy.
The economy had cartel-like characteristics where many International companies and Greeks enjoyed immunity from regulators. Its exciting that as the Central State shrinks, Greece is becoming more creative—and capital will follow creativity, it always does. A new, more daring country will emerge. We do much transactional work and Greece’s expansive privatisation plan has placed the country in the global investment shop window. Two years ago there was a slightly carniverous underlying taste to investor interest. Anonymous, impatient money was hovering over Greece and driven by the possibility of fast returns. This government has devoted time and effort to convince serious long term investors with patient capital to focus and invest. The first signs are there and I am sure it will continue.
But how do you perceive this? The average perspective is, for example, a headline in Greece from two weeks ago: People cannot even pay for their medicine anymore. How is your perception? Is this common? Or are we over-exaggerating?
Olympios: There are two issues that your question raises. The first is that Greece is on the edge of a humanitarian (in European terms) crisis. The insensitive and fiscally focused Troika program has destroyed the social safety net and is pushing tens of thousands of Greek citizens into a downward spiral with no bottom. We are talking of perfectly normal and decent people that had nothing to do with the Greece of yesterday, did not profit from the crony capitalism and did not work in the public sector. It’s un-European and unjustifiable. It's simply wrong.
My second point is that the social/humanitarian issue is one side of the crisis. It's overly portrayed by a blood thirsty international press corp looking for stereotypical images. They are like hoovers sucking the dust off a priceless carpet, just getting the dirt and ignoring the weave, which in this case would be the social fabric and its resilience in keeping a country—that many predicted would go “up in flames” altogether. I have never been more proud to be Greek. There is a new vibrant donor culture, volunteerism, grass roots alliances and patriotic consumption. Innovation and quality of Greek food products, new producers based in rural parts of Greece are increasingly evident, Greece 2.0 is starting to be visible. If you have the good will and interest to break through the media bubble then grass shoots are very visible!
Did transparency improve?
Olympios: Absolutely. The party is over, someone turned the lights on and we now know that the person, company, politician or product opposite of us is not as “pretty” or “attractive” as we thought it was. The gap between us and them has now been closed.
How about the strategic position of Greece? if you look at the European map, all these Balkan States who came to Europe much later, e.g. Bulgaria—or just not yet, like Albania or Kosovo—they all are in immediate vicinity to Greece which has been a EU Member State for a very long time already. Couldn’t that be a huge advantage for the Greek economy, to be like a ship in an ocean?
Olympios: Certainly. There is an obvious benefit since a large economic space is being created between these Balkan countries and there is also a great cultural advantage. Northern Greece is benefiting from second home sales, its cities are weekend destinations for many of the Balkan middle classes. Thessaloniki could be a melting pot of Balkan culture, this is its advantage over southern Greece but to straddle the energy, it needs open minds and liberal leadership. They need to continue the blue skies thinking of the current mayor, open up to the cultural richness of the area and create the first Balkan metropolitan city.
© Fotos Elisseos Kontis/AcePhotography
Yiannis Olympios, born in 1969, is CEO and Founder of V+O Communication, the largest Communication and Public Affairs company in South Eastern Europe. It advises many of the region’s companies on reputational, operational and strategic Decisions. He started his career at The Ministry of Foreign Affairs where he acted as Special Advisor for the international Media.
In my mind Greece has to be able to celebrate subjectivity and become a less homogenous and more international and welcoming environment for people and ideas, otherwise any discussion concerning the economy, growth or creativity and expression is by default undermined.
And in Greece itself—Did the climate also change?
Olympios: It did. My favourite example is Greek culture. For many years the state through its policy of subsidies controlled expression in the arts. Apart from the few behemoths of Greek post dictatorial culture, the sacred cows that remained in control of expression and opinion, there where not that many opportunities for many others. Censorship of ideas and expression was normal through the acceptance of one central mainstream and homogenous moral space in the ugly relationship between politics and expression. Now both our political and ecclisiastical leadership is much more liberal and cosmopolitan. They have moved to the back seat and seem to understand that creativity cannot be controlled.
A bold recent example is the Prime Minister’s decision to allow a mosque to be built in greater Athens. It is a disgrace that Greeks that for so many years have enjoyed freedom of religious expression in four corners of the world and who pride themselves for their hospitality have never allowed even Muslim Greeks a place of worship in the capital! The Prime Minister understands that progress can only come through tolerance.
Let's listen to someone who earns his money on the countryside.
Stellios Boutaris: Indeed, I am in the wine business. I will come back to your first question, whether the crisis has been good to Greece or not. Well, at this table, yes, we can say that it has been good. However, this is a qualified answer, since socially it is a huge problem. If you really look down and what has been happening in Greece, I am surprised that not everything has collapsed. Maybe we have touched the bottom but still, unfortunately there is a lot of money being wasted. And out of these 1.3 million unemployed people, most of them will never get back to the workforce or they will come to the workforce in completely different terms than the one they used to have. This is something that is not going to be easy. It is really our responsibility to take care of this whole situation.
On the other hand, the crisis is good in a sense that it made us all think twice about what we had been doing, for example in the wine sector. Greece having been on the frontpage of every newspaper for such a long time has been great, because for every bad story people will start looking for a good story as well. Wine has been a good story for Greece. The paradoxic results: Our sales in Germany have tripled in the last two years. It doesn’t make sense but it has grown. There is a wine club in Mexico asking for a greek wine. We never experienced this before. There are people who are selling greek wines in Thailand. This is all new, and I think this is all because of the crisis.
Suddenly, there is something of a greek advantage: we are very quick in reacting. In our sector, most of the winemakers looked overseas very quickly, started exporting, traveling, cutting costs and inventing new products. People who did not innovate quickly enough were kicked out of the market. Coming back to your question about the public sector, my experience is that it is working better. I work with three different public sectors. One is customs. For six months now, customs has been all electronic and everything is better. 
So, customs is more efficient?
Boutaris: Yes, much more efficient. The second one is tax office. I have to say that closing the local tax office and moving it to the capital of our country—it is definitely better for the government, and it is definitely better for me who is paying taxes. Maybe not so good for the local tax evader. The third one is the Department of Agriculture, suddenly they want to work with you. They want you to do well. They ask you, “How were sales?” or the bring the papers to your place and help you to fill them in. It's unbelievable.
You know how that sounds? We experienced this, in a way, when there was the reunification, when the East German way of governance was confronted with capitalism. Suddenly and out of the blue they started to be interested in the people.
Constantakopoulos: There was a very ineffective person responsible for granting visas. A minister, I don’t want to say the name, asked him, “Why don’t you issue more visas?”, and he said, “I thought I was here to protect the borders and have less people come.” (Laughter) That’s how it worked before.
Boutaris: Unfortunately, for the last 20 years, we had this subsidy culture in agriculture that has completely ruined the whole sector. I mean, it is the most normal thing to do it—to grow crops. Everything grows. We are blessed by that. But these guys just waited for subsidies.
From Brussels.
Boutaris: From Brussels or from the local government. This has changed a lot now. We have ambitious young farmers who are really understanding the final product. They are growing grapes. I can say now: “If I buy your grapes, if you want price, I need the best quality.”
© Fotos Elisseos Kontis/AcePhotography
Stellios Y. Boutaris, born in 1965, is serving as Managing Director and shareholder of Kir-Yiannis S. A., which is one of the top 10 Greek vineries in Greece with sales worldwide. Additionally, he manages W. S. Karoulias in Athens, the leading independent national wine and spirit distributor in Greece. Boutaris is a graduate of the London School of Economics and of INSEAD in Fontainebleau.
They understand perfectly that the final product is connected to the crop they grow. It used to be “I demand a good price at any quality, and I don’t care what you are going to make with my product.“ All of this was a wrong product of the “subsidy culture”. It could not survive.
How is the atmosphere on the countryside?
Boutaris: If you go there, you think it's a regular place. This is one of the crazy things in Greece. When you go out at night, everybody is happy. Also, they own their houses. Everybody lived together, having as little as five hectars of peach trees that would supplement to the income. So it is still this simple way of live that has glued together the greek community, especially on the countryside. However, we still have Bulgarian and Albanian workers. Still, the Greeks will not come to work on the farm.
I was in Peloponnese, and there was the citrus-crop. Buses with workers from Romania and from Albania on every hook. I did not see one Greek on the fields, and that is difficult to explain to Germans.
Boutaris: Although I have to say that this year was the first time that I had like three greek guys in their 50s, they came and started doing day jobs, because they really needed the 35 Euros wages. Young people still won’t come though, and this again is a mentality coming from the family - the father, who is a worker, who is a farmer, doesn’t want to see his children being farmers. He wants to see his kid being a lawyer. This has changed lately as well, now the father is proud to see his son working on the farm.
It really seems that you all agree in one thing: there is still an incredible power hidden in this country. That is what I sense.
Boutaris: I always say that we are going to be the next booming economy but my friends think I am only joking.
Stergiou: When I returned to Greece as a physician and entrepreneur in 2011, my favourite quote was from Louis Pasteur: Change favours the mind that is prepared. I am born and raised German and I have lived almost all my life in Hagen, Germany. It was only later that I studied science and medicine in the USA. So I am used to change and like to think I am prepared for it as well. I think it is important for Germans to understand that Greeks are not „bad Germans“. This is an erroneous label.
Greeks belong to a  completely different culture. You might ask why not more Greeks are working on the farm, or why do they spend money on the island of Mykonos, when they should worry where they are going to find money tomorrow to pay their bills and for their medicine. Most of the time they don’t worry so much. It is just our culture; we are different. Although I think with the crisis, this side of the greek personality is changing as well because the crisis has taught us not to trake things for granted.
Are you doing business with this mentality?
Stergiou: The group, I foundet in 2012, Sellas Life Science, and Sellas clinicals is a unique business model in itself. We have the only dedicated clinical trials facility here in Greece. The whole notion started in 2011. I returned from the USA as the vice president of a big pharma company there; as a matter of fact, I returned for two romantic reasons. One reason was because my fiancee, who is my wife now, lived here. The second reason was: I really wanted to do something good for Greece. So we went into the health care sector, where we do clinical research and development.
We work on behalf of pharmaceutical companies such as Janssen, Cilag, Amgen and others, as well as for medium size companies. When they want to launch a product and clinical research has to be performed, it has to be tested in humans. We basically have this niche market in Greece, being the only dedicated trial facility. We provide patients access to innovative and unique treatment options in severe and debilitating diseases where they would have otherwise no access to—under strict EU-guidelines. So new drugs become available to patients in need.
In contrast, last year the pharmaceutical industry spent €80 million in Greece on research and development. We wish that number to increase by 500% by the year 2017. This would be a €400 million market. So Sellas is a service provider. In 2011 we started with a staff of two. Today we are a staff of about 30 people, including full-time and part-time personnel as well as consultants. We are also a company that not only does work for other clients; we do our own research and development.
For example, we started developing an innovative and promising drug against Parkinson’s disease, particular in the more severe form of the illness. This sort of investment, just as an idea, is about €4 million. And we see that investors, Greeks and from abroad, trust in this business endeavour. Did we succeed in what we wanted? So far, we did. We combined innovation and entrepreneurship of the so called “undisciplined Greek” with hard work and efficiency. The result are solid products and potentially high profits.
Our management team is composed of Greeks, Germans, Swiss, Canadian, and Americans. It is a multi-cultural team from different cultures who have experience in the field. We have this open freethinking approach in advancing the industry. For business reasons, we also have a foot in Switzerland. Obviously not all Greeks with business in Switzerland are looking for tax shelters. Switzerland is the Mecca of the pharmaceutical world. We had to attract business there and it is working. The bad thing was that due to being greek we carried a negative stigma and the first question often was: do you do “greek statistics”. But let me point it out: that's something that politicians may have done—it does not reflect today’s business mentality in Greece.
Goldman Sachs co-wrote the greek statistics.
Stergiou: Exactly. Greeks did not do that alone. And it came to an abrupt end now. The other good development: Germans want to work with Greece. In my personal humble opinion: Germans are Philhellenes. They want to collaborate with us. Being here only for a few years I can say, there was a lot of dirt in Greece, but now with great pain and sacrifice, the dust has sort of settled. What we can see now are true diamonds that shine brightly.
One wouldn’t expect digital oder medical industry in greece.
Stergiou: Greece is not just about tourism and shipping, I am extremely proud that we have grown tremendously; huge companies out of the US, out of China, the leading pharmaceutical companies—we are now establishing business relations with them. Greece can position itself in a particular market of medical and research expertise. We are blessed with a considerable intellectual capital. We have a highly educated population with emphasis on mathematics and sciences. In the medical sector, Greeks of the diaspora have returned to Greece because they have been offered positions: what they have done outside Greece, we now do it in Greece.
Is medicine a crisis business?
Stergiou: We have noticed an increase in the rates of depression and suicide but we must look very carefully at all those numbers before we can make instant conclusions. As you may imagine, an increased rate of depression and a huge trade of sexually transmitted diseases are probably directly and indirectly related to the economic crisis. People are less careful. They literally are just not aware of these things. If you detect HIV, for instance, early enough, you can actually cure it. We have the European approved HIV kit that within one minute of the test allows with 99.8 procent accuracy to see if you are HIV positive or negative. Last year more than 200 prostitutes were detected with that kit of being positive. Especially during In a crisis you desperately need such innovations.
Do you regret that you came back to Greece?
Stergiou: Not at all. It took some time to understand the greek mentality even though I am greek myself. I think you need to be careful so you don't fall into the old trap of going with the flow and doing it—if I may say—the greek way. You really have to stick with the ethics that you have learned outside of Greece and run the business the way you are accustomed to—and then insert those things here into the culture. Once you do that, the sky is the limit.
What is the positive aspect of being greek then? Germans may not be creative enough; But what are the Greek? What do they have to offer in the sense of being somehow better Germans or better Europeans?
Stergiou: It wasn't by chance that medicine was born in Greece. The whole mindset and the whole DNA in the medicine is in us. We have this innovative thinking. We are more creative in many ways, I really admire Greeks for that. Even if there is a problem, we will find three, four or even five solutions.
© Fotos Elisseos Kontis/AcePhotography
Angelos M. Stergiou, born in 1976, is an MD and Founde, CEO and Chairman of Sellas, Life Science Group which specalized in Clinical Research and Development. He is a graduate of Kentucky Wesleyan (USA) and for many years, he has held leading positions in pharma and biotechnology companies as well as Clinical Research Organizations in the United States and Europe.
Veremis: As a point of reference, I encountered quite a few sales guys from different nationalities, in more than 40 countries. Without any prejudice—Greeks are by far the most adaptive.
In Germany, if there would be a similar situation like in Greece now, we probably wouldn’t have a democracy anymore. What german politicians didn’t explain is that not only Greece is restructuring itself, but all of Europe is being restructured. So Greece would be a pioneer—not, as we think right now, lagging behind. Instead, it could be a role model. So the question is: what did Europe do wrong? 
Veremis: Politically, Europe is, compared to ten years ago, a far more introverted set of countries and has a far more chauvinistic set of citizens everywhere searching for differences rather than communality. If you ask me, the key question is not what the Germans think of the Greeks or the Spanish, but what do the Germans think of themselves? What do they want to be in ten years? The crisis basically put the entire construct under serious stress. The reaction was one of introversion more than anything else. In a situation with introversion, it is clear that the most powerful party, i.e. Germany, would have the responsibility and also the very difficult task of offering leadership.
I don’t think Germany was prepared for this kind of thing. As you say, in a situation like that the bureaucrats can make an awful lot of decisions. Now Europe needs to decide whether it needs to develop into a federation, or if we all go our separate ways. At least the rules of the game need to be set, because otherwise it is impossible to join any kind of policy.
This new chauvinism, I think, from a political level is the big mistake of Germany—the way it actually, the German media—I don’t know about the citizens—but the way it portrayed the southern part of Europe, and especially the Greeks. This stirred up memories of the war. It stirred up a lot of nasty history, and it basically created the polarisation and animosity—all what had been mended with a lot of care and a lot of wisdom from 1945 onwards. On a political level, monsters have been awakened.
Kefalogiannis: I would only add one more factor that has to do with the timeframe. I think that from the beginning, trying to implement such a program that has to do with political, social, and economic aspects, and requiring so many reforms in just 1.5 – 2 years and promising to the people that in 2012 we will go back to the markets and everything will be as it used to be; this was a huge mistake.
The shock was very big but if greek people had known that, ok, things will change, we will suffer, but there is a ten-year plan—that in ten years we will have this solution and that result… the mentality would be much different. I think people would be more willing to comply with the requirements. From the beginning there was a big lie from mostly the EU and from the greek government; promises were changing from one week to another. Greek people were and still are totally confused. They don’t know what to expect. The timeframe was a huge mistake, and we pay for that now.
We are slowly approaching the problem of the public sector. We all agree: less state obstruction, less state control, less unnecessary bureaucracy is good. But e.g. if you take away the police, the hospital and the infrastructure, the economy cannot flourish either. How can you find a balance?
Kefalogiannis: You don’t want the government to be a businessman. You want the government to assist the businessman. Here in Greece, the government has been running everything for many years. The most important problem until recently—and still to some extent— is that dealing with the greek state means face-to-face. So you have to go yourself and you have to meet someone. Things are not done electronically. And as soon as you have to do everything face-to-face, then it starts to be a personal deal. And when dealing starts it goes to corruption and after that it goes a step further. You cannot eliminate the state. What we have to eliminate though is the face-to-face way of dealing with the state. It needs to become impersonal.
After the whip there should be some sugar now?
Kefalogiannis: I think not even the whip. There should be a clear vision from the beginning. This vision was not provided because unfortunately Europe doesn’t have this vision. We all know that the economical elite was 100% related with the political elite because it was created by dealing with the greek state. It is still there. It is still resisting change and it is an obstacle for the new Greece.
Olympios I believe that there should be a clearer and more honest discussion about responsibility. The Brussels elites talk of the greek civil service and stereotype the average Greek as a tax avoiding and lazy non-European citizen, they avoid talk of their own responsibility and that of the Greek politicians and business elites. The Greek politicians accuse their opponents and the Troika. They still hide the truth from the public in order to protect the patriarchal society that allows them to make decisions for the public rather than with the public!
For over fifteen years, Greece surfed on a wave of materialism. Awash with money that wasn't earned yet with a feeling of entitlement. It was probably one of the least hellenistic places on earth. On a personal level I have felt the corrosive force of a surrounding where the worst most materialistic side of your character is applauded rather than isolated. I have done things that I regret and I could definitely have been a better and more responsible citizen. The fact that “everyone was doing it“ is no excuse for ethical elasticity. I believe that there is a collective and independent sense of guilt which is the underlying reason for the lack of serious social eruptions.
Could the European community have done anything differently? Or is that a systemic mistake?
Olympios: Of course. It cannot by default be a uniquely Greek failure. This is a European accident, a systemic failure as well. It was an accident that took place in slow motion but many saw it coming years ahead. But to be fair it has still been made in Greece. Just because Eurostat did not catch Greece it still means that by manipulating greek statistics, you were effectively stealing and when you are caught stealing you still deserve to be treated like a thief.
But there must have been people in Brussels who knew about that.
Olympios: Of course they new. But once again change does not only have to be institutional and reform must be personal, communal, corporate and political. It cannot be on just the one level for us to create a new citizen.
Is there something that could be of immediate help?
Boutaris: As long as specialists come into the greek economy and really do understand the greek economy and taking the best practices from Germany or Europe and adjust them to Greece, that could help very much. But the whole bureaucracy in Brussels is unbearable, for all of Europe. This is where the problem lies.
© Henning Bode
If people talk about Greece, Athens and the Acropolis, most of the time it’s only a small part of it: the Parthenon temple which is dedicated to the maiden goddess Athena.
Olympios: They must build a security net. Bring other principles and moral directions into the mix of measures and policy. Acknowledge that the social fabric cannot be shattered at all costs. Despite Greece meeting many more targets than it has missed, why is the Troika panicking at even the smallest set back in tax revenue from an already financially exhausted public and not equally alarmed by the social crisis? Why do we need special help with our finances but not for our social needs? How European is it that the program does not have social benchmarks in place? Checks and balances regarding the suffering it creates. We need to factor in the learnings and acknowledge the hardship. 
Boutaris: Only the real growth can bring real jobs. No matter if you go to any company and you tell them, “Listen, you can have five people for free. I will pay you to have them.” It will not work.  We must create real sustainable jobs.
Did all of you—during the crisis—build new jobs? Or did you have let go of people?
Kefalogiannis: As far as we are concerned, we have increased our staff.
Boutaris: Have you dropped the salaries?
Kefalogiannis: No, we didn’t drop salaries and we didn’t fire anyone.
Constantakopoulos: We had to let some go but we hired some others, too. Now we are already developing a second site in a huge area—where we anticipate that we will create more job opportunities in the immediate future.
Retsos: You are mostly talking about newly established companies. But being in a 50-year company, I can surely tell you that we might have changed the persons but the workspace remained the same and in some cases was even increased.
Are there other people from the private sector who actually profited from the old way of state business in Greece, and are they still powerful?
Veremis: There are the guys who benefitted directly from running the show. But there is a whole class of people who make significant sacrifices, they started in good jobs, had a family of three or four kids, went through the ranks of management in these companies, and at some point found themselves in the past four years without a job. These guys are a different case of the unemployed underclass. These are highly educated, upwardly mobile managers of five years ago, with their kids in private schools, everything going well, and suddenly their world has collapsed from here to zero. There are plenty of people like that. I personally know quite a few.
Boutaris: And businessmen also, who have had a healthy business… having like 40-50 employees, doing like €10 million turnover, and suddenly this is gone. Construction and everything around construction is gone.
Veremis: Some of them are moving to Kathar or to Dubai, because these are highly qualified engineers, architects.
Constantakopoulos: We need growth. But you cannot cut your way to growth. there has to be some growth. If you cut an old ladies’ pension, that €20 or €50, the propensity of that going to consumption was probably 98%. So actually you are cutting from the economy.
Boutaris: A lot of time was lost.
Constantakopoulos: A lot of people have lost their jobs, lost their income, lost their household, what are we doing for them? I think that we, as a country, as a sector, as a society, the best thing we can do is create sustainable jobs. In the meantime and until we reach a stage that all people can live with decency everybody must do their share in helping. I know NGOs, that you can call from your house and say, “I have ten apples left over.” They can hook you up with somebody who needs that. It is incredible ingenuity—on how on a detail level they can do that. I have a half of a loaf of bread that is left.
And you can use it… it has been a tremendous move and thought of how we can help each other.  Or for example, the church and some other institutes: you go in the supermarket and buy something, and then you can put in a special basket, by every cashier in most of the Greek supermarkets, They tell you: We are in need of pasta, or milk, etc. They use a tremendous amount of volunteer ingenuity. The hunger in Greece is minimised.
Society is really sticking together. That has also to do with the Greek values. The families support their own. The villages embrace their most vulnerable members, the neighbourhood the same, the church plays an important role. On the other hand, the rules of the market are put by the biggest player. The biggest player used to be the state. That is not the case anymore. Economic problems can be resolved, but if the economic crisis turns to a social crisis it can throw us back 30 years.
How thin is the surface of civilization?
Constantakopoulos: I don’t know how thin it is, but it is definitely ice. We need structural reforms, but on the other hand we also need growth. Now it is the sixth year of recession  - or should I say depression?  too much.  A recession is when your neighbour loses his house. A depression is where you lose your house.
Does Greece need less austerity?
Stergiou: What I am really personally worried about is the European pragmatism. That is if the people in Brussels could not foresee the problems of over-indebted countries? Had we caught the problem earlier, as in the case in preventive medicine, we would not be where we are today. If Brussels with all its controls and regulations was unable to do foresee what was going to happen, then I am deeply worried about what is going on in Brussels.
The second piece is: Just like if one has cancer, and I think right now Greece has been diagnosed with a cancer - so, what do you do? You turn to the best doctor. he gives the right treatment, and assures a good prognosis. Again, all that Brussels has not made sure of. What is going to happen with Italy? Greece right now has been sort of a trial and error approach of austerity. But speaking medically, the treatment plan had dire, severe side effects. So the stage was set for extremists. You have the right-wing party „golden sunrise“ with roots in the Greek junta and ideals from Germany’s dark age of fascist Nazism.
That is gaining momentum - not because Greeks are right-wing, but out of despair. This is something that frightens me a lot, because things can get out of hand very quickly. You can also have extreme left-wing-groups, also tingled with nationalism. It can very quickly turn into turmoil. Things will not improve if Brussels doesn’t get a wake-up call—unless we really find the right treatment plan. What Greece needs is sufficient time for adjustment and a realistic financial plan to overcome this cancer. Give US some more time to implement changes. We Greeks are a proud people and do not like the idea relying on bailouts and political decision-making while our economy is devastated. Support us with dignity.
Germany is not in the position to teach. Germany won’t evolve like Greece at all, but it will have the same symptoms. Our society doesn’t stick together—we don’t have these family ties or strong churches. Our whole identity comes from the wealth the nation had in the 1960s and 1970s.
Stergiou: What we need in Greece are less government bureaucrates making those hard decisions. If someone has not woken up during the night, because he is afraid that the Budgets is out of balance, or he cannot pay his bills the next morning as a businessman... it is those sorts of people you want to run a country, because they really understand the frustration. I would rather see successful entrepreneurs who really come up with some solutions, run the things and decide what is possible and what is not. Instead today we have politicians who never have run a business in their life.
© Elisseos Kontis/AcePhotography
Pragmatism and Optimism First: Entrepreneurs at the F.A.Z. Round Table in Athens.
Constantakopoulos: Greeks have felt the pain. They took the loss. They took a huge pride loss as well. We saw politicians going to jail. we saw business people going to jail. It is not theoretical. There were some people that thought to be untouchable. This is not the feeling anymore. this fear by itself is very good for the system. 
Do politicians seek your advice, for example?
Olympios: Politics and business—the distance is a lot smaller. 
Kefalogiannis: Overall, we could see a future where the corporations, where the companies will be taking actions supporting local societies and societies in if we forget Greece for a second, I think that the whole Western World is in a crisis; the capitalistic world is coming to a dead end. We need a new model. I think the new model is going to come out of the corporations, out of the companies. The companies are a molecules of the modern society. They operate in the society, but they understand that the success depends on the healthiness and the success of the society general.
I believe the very successful companies will be the ones that will be the most successful ones in taking care of the society. This will also be the strongest in the end financially in the long run. Through this model, I think we will have the rebirth of social responsible capitalism and a change in the mentality. We should stop expecting everything from the politicians, we must take the situation in our own hands. Each one of us should do his own part in helping resphape the society of the future.
Olympios: I think that the politicians have a clear role to play.  What we are lacking is a cosmopolitan way of thinking about things, which is over and beyond Greece, Germany, and France, Italy, and it is a more holistic European approach. We have been discussing in Greece the last 30 years about building a Mosque, for example, in Athens. This is a disgrace; we don’t have a place of worship for the Muslim community in Athens, despite that the Greeks have their lovely churches all around the world.
But just now a lot of politicians have a lot to offer.  There are good cases around Greece, but these are  small politicians, town counsellors, mayors, who clean up their town, who have completely recyclable goods, who are energy efficient. I am very confident. Even if you would say that the Greeks have an issue with Germans, but if you look at consumer indexes, there is no issue with Germans whatsoever. In fact, all through this crisis, the consumer facing companies haven’t taken a hit whatsoever. So, that has not been expressed in any way: in tourism, in consumerism. Lets not feed the dragon.
Constantakopoulos: One of the major problems: Very few serious young men or women wants to become a politician. Would you want your son or daughter to go to politics? If I ask that in my neighbourhood, I am not sure how many yes I would get. If we bring down the politicians into the eyes of our peers and future generations, who is going to run our country?
It is the same in Germany. We have a negative selection of some sorts. Nobody wants to be a politician anymore.
Boutaris: You know, the politician, if he doesn’t hear some, well done, bravo, why would he do it? If you are not going there to make money, he has at least to hear some well done.
Retsos: Stelios, your father is mayor of Saloniki - he must have some experience. (Laughter) I read a lot about him  - very good things.
Boutaris: He is trying. It is taking much longer than he ever expected. If there is one thing that he has a problem with, it is the procedures and structures. This is the biggest problem. The processes are slow and so difficult to overcome; they are made for you to do nothing, unless there is somebody, a politician, who moves things forward. That is how the whole public system is structured.
May I ask you one last historical question, which is very much discussed in Germany? When in the Summit was in Cannes, Papandreou went back and said that he wants to have a referendum about the euro. Do you remember that?
Several together: Of course … (Laughter). Who could forget?
So, my question is, because we have Habermas who then intervened and said, because Schäuble said, “This is ruining the market” And then we had a vivid debate: are not the society and democracies more important than the market? My question to you is: Was Papandreou right, or was he wrong?
Olympios: With my hand on my heart I believe he was a hundred percent correct. Yes the timing was wrong and the execution was awful but I have not heard of any other idea that would have stabilized Greece, aligned Europe, erased the fear of GRexit allowing Greece cheaper money and privatization to race ahead without the country risk. Also keep in mind you would have had a 70 to 80 percent majority for the Euro which in turn means acceptance of the austerity measures.
Most importantly the referendum would have individuals, politicians, business leaders, media and other elites individually responsible for the future, no more bluffing and no more utopian promises that corrupt the public debate. I was shocked by the European response and to this day cannot see the fiscal/political or social advantages of not holding the referendum.
Veremis: But, the execution was atrocious. Even if the thought might have been interesting; to win a referendum, you need to prepare it, phrase it correctly, and mark it.
If you would have done a referendum, because at that time the whole European Union was shocked by the imagination that Greek would switch… So, the Europeans and the Germans would have had to find ways to convince the Greek. This would have been a kind of rationalising.
Retsos: You never draw your gun unless you are ready to use it. Papandreou proved that he drew his gun, but he never thought that he had to use it. from the first moment, we knew that it was just a bluff, and I think it was a disastrous bluff.
We thank you very much for this intense discussion. Evcharisto!
Weitere Artikel
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
