<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 14:54:36 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Kenya mall attack</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/07/world/africa/kenya-mall-attack/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/07/world/africa/kenya-mall-attack/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>At least six people have been singled out for their involvement in last month's Westgate mall attack --and that number is expected to double once the investigation is complete, a senior Kenyan government official said. </description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 06:07:30 EDT</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Source: 6 suspects behind Kenya's Westgate mall attack, including woman
By Nima Elbagir and Lilian Leposo, CNN
October 7, 2013 -- Updated 0953 GMT (1753 HKT)
Smoke rises from the Westgate mall in Nairobi on September 23, 2013.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
The six include four men who died in the mall and have been identified
Official: A female attacker, found dead with a gun, is believed to have killed 30 people
Another attacker changed clothes and left the mall with the crowds, the official says
Nairobi, Kenya (CNN) -- At least six people have been singled out for their involvement in last month's Westgate mall attack --and that number is expected to double once the investigation is complete, a senior Kenyan government official said.
The official declined to be identified due to the sensitivity of the information.
Read more: It's not over, Somali terrorists say
Previously, a spokesman for the Kenya Defense Forces identified four terrorists who took part in the mall attack, which left at least 67 people dead. Those four are Khattab al-Kene, an American Somali; Abu Baara al-Sudani, from Sudan; Omar Nabhan, from Kenya; and a man identified only as Umayr.
What did Westgate mean to Kenyans?
Video shows gunmen inside Kenya mall
U.S. forces capture al Qaeda leader
Kenya's Counter-Terrorism Office said Nabhan was related to former senior al Qaeda in Somalia operative Saleh Ali Nabhan, who was killed in a U.S. strike in southern Somalia in 2009. Both men were from Mombasa, Kenya.
The four died when the part of the mall they were in collapsed, Maj. Emmanuel Chirchir said. The charred bodies of the four are undergoing DNA verification.
Zain Verjee: I I can't get image of Westgate out of my mind
Other suspected attackers either seen in security footage or described by eye-witnesses are not yet counted because their bodies have either not yet been positively identified, or their whereabouts are unknown.
The senior government official said in addition to the four men who have been identified, there was also a woman identified as Somali whose body was found with a mounted gun. The official said the woman is responsible for single-handedly killing more than 30 people.
The official said a sixth attacker changed clothes and left the mall with other hostages.
Read more: Al-Shabaab backed by money from U.S.
In short, five attackers are dead, and one escaped, according to the official.
Separately, security footage newly released by Kenyan police shows two men withdrawing money at a Barclays bank in Nairobi, and police believe they are connected to the terror attack.
These men are at large, and police say there is a bounty on their heads. It was unclear if either of the two men could be the same as the attacker who fled the mall.
CNN's Christabelle Fombu contributed to this report.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
