<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 14:54:36 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Indy driver, crowd hurt in crash</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/06/us/texas-indycar-crash/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/06/us/texas-indycar-crash/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>Three-time Indianapolis 500 winner Dario Franchitti was injured in a serious crash that also left 13 spectators hurt during Sunday's Grand Prix of Houston, authorities reported.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 14:45:56 EDT</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Indy winner Dario Franchitti, 13 others hurt in Houston race wreck
By CNN Staff
October 7, 2013 -- Updated 1700 GMT (0100 HKT)
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Franchitti suffers concussion, fractures to spine and ankle in the wreck
Franchitti's car bumped, careens into fencing at Houston Grand Prix
The crash hurt 13 spectators, 3 of whom were taken to a hospital
The three-time Indy 500 winner and wife Ashley Judd announced divorce in January
(CNN) -- Three-time Indianapolis 500 winner Dario Franchitti was injured in a serious crash that also left 13 spectators hurt during Sunday's Grand Prix of Houston, authorities reported.
The wreck occurred in the last lap of the race, when Japanese driver Takuma Sato bumped Franchitti's car, sending it airborne into the protective fencing. The car spun multiple times against the fence, sending shards of debris flying toward the grandstands and shearing off part of its side. Read more from Bleacher Report
Three spectators were sent to a local hospital, where they were listed in good condition Sunday night. The rest were treated at the scene, according to Senior Capt. Ruy Lozano of the Houston Fire Department.
Dario Franchitti is a three-time Indianapolis 500 winner.
My way or the highway: Niki Lauda's Formula One creed
Franchitti, 40, suffered a concussion in the wreck and fractures to his spine and ankle. The spinal fracture does not require surgery, according to Dr. Michael Olinger, director of medical services for IndyCar. Franchitti will be kept overnight at Memorial Hermann-Texas Medical Center in Houston.
Danish driver Simonsen killed in high-speed crash
Witness thought driver would be dead
The Scotland native won IndyCar racing's top prize in 2012, 2010 and 2007. He was married to actress Ashley Judd for more than 11 years, but the couple announced in January that they were ending their marriage.
Judd tweeted Sunday evening that she was on her way to Houston, thanking fans for their prayers.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
