<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 14:54:36 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Beautiful bookshop -- in a car park</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/09/02/travel/nanjing-book-shop/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/09/02/travel/nanjing-book-shop/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>No glamorous chandeliers, no extravagant façade -- to find the most beautiful bookshop in China, travelers just have to follow the yellow-striped road to an underground car park.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 12:04:25 EDT</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>China's most beautiful bookshop ... in a car park
By Hiufu Wong, CNN
October 7, 2013 -- Updated 0126 GMT (0926 HKT)
The most beautiful bookshop in China is hidden in an underground car park. "Here in Librairie Avant-Garde, reading is our religion and this place is the heaven for readers," says Zhang Xing, manager of the shop beneath Wutaichan Stadium in Nanjing.
Librairie Avart-Garde has "turned something rotten into a miracle," says owner Qian Xiaohua, 50, quoting an old Chinese maxim to explain the unusual location.
Being a staffer is no small task. "Some are poets, some are writers, but we all love books," says manager Zhang. "We always kid that if all of us gather our own collections of books, we can open another book shop. We have a 30-minute staff meeting every morning -- to share a movie we saw, a book we read or other things that inspire us."
You may not find best-sellers or latest releases here, but the shop boasts the widest range of humanities books in China.
"Avant-garde people are the most forward, most innovative, with a strong opinion and are not easily influenced," says owner Qian.
Librairie Avant-Garde includes a creative workshop where local designs are sold. Some compare Librairie Avant-Garde's diversified cultural experience to the Taiwanese creative book shop, Eslite.
There are no windows, nor many colors in the bookshop, other than book spines. Yet customers queue in front of the store every morning. "One of our readers who came here all the time applied for a security guard position in the shop," says Zhang. "Just to stay close to the place."
The bookstore provides hundreds of seats where people can read and spend their days. "Where can you see a bookshop with readers waiting in line before the shop opens?" asks Qian. "I don't worry about selling books. We believe if people are willing to come and stay, we will eventually make business."
A corner that honors global intellectuals, not something you see in a normal bookshop in China.
The shop has a permanent section for beautiful books. "We don't just sell books, we want to sell a lifestyle," says Qian. "I like to consider it 'bookshop neo-aestheticism.'"
Qian's open office inside the bookshop has no computer -- it's a room full of packed bookshelves. Even the desk is made of bookshelves.
Pipes and fluorescent lamps combine for an unlikely beauty.
Photos of bookshops around the world adorn the walls. Qian takes the pictures when traveling. "I have visited 46 book shops in the U.S. and 36 in the UK," says the founder who tracks his travel life through books. "I'm currently in Anhui and I have to read eight books here before I come home [to Nanjing]."
The coffee shop stocks a shelf of books that aren't for sale. Some are from Qian's private collection.
HIDE CAPTION
Hotter than designer clothing shops
Intellectual corner
When a real reader travels ...
More books in the coffee shop
&lt;&lt;
Voted China's most beautiful bookshop, Librairie Avant-Garde is in an underground car park
The shop's owner believes reading is a religion
The bookshop is also a coffee shop, exhibition space and public forum
(CNN) -- No glamorous chandeliers, no extravagant façade -- to find the most beautiful bookshop in China, travelers just have to follow the yellow-striped road to an underground car park.
Before Librairie Avant-Garde owner Qian Xiaohua, 50, obtained the 4,000-square-meter underground space beneath Wutaishan Stadium in Nanjing in 1999, it was a government car park and, earlier, a bomb shelter.
"We chose this car park because it borders Nanjing University -- it has become the second library for university students," says Qian. "There is an old saying in Chinese -- turn something rotten into a miracle."
Instead of a shelf for best-selling books, visitors are welcomed by a replica of Rodin's "The Thinker" sculpture.
The cashier counter is built from thousands of old books.
"You walk up the slope that still retains its yellow traffic stripes on the ground between two rows of shelves," says Qian, as though he'd just opened the shop a week ago. "After that, look back and you'll see a big shining cross that shines upon you, as well as many others that came here before you."
Librairie Avant-Garde owner Qian Xiaohua sees his book store as a kind of public library.
Reading as religion
Qian converted to Christianity when he quit a job with the provincial government to open the first Librairie Avant-Garde, across the street from the St. Paul Cathedral.
It was a tiny store -- 17 square meters.
"I listened to the hymns coming from the church every day and I felt so peaceful," says Qian. "Then I became a Christian."
That explains the large crosses in all of shop's branches.
But it's not simple Christian faith Qian is promoting.
"We aim to be a humanities bookstore as well as a religious store," says Zhang Xing, manager of the Wutaichan shop.
"Here in Librairie Avant-Garde, reading is our religion and this place is the heaven for book lovers."
The main hall of the bookstore serves as a forum for talks and concerts.
It also houses a homey coffee shop, permanent exhibition space for beautiful book designs and a retail area for creative works by Nanjingers.
Qian's favorite artworks hang from the ceiling.
Pillars in the store are etched with famous verses and poems.
Book shops reflect city's well being
The beauty of Qian's bookstore lies in its unique way of operating.
Qian sees his shop as a kind of public library.
Two long reading tables and more than 300 seats are available for readers who are encouraged to stay and read in the shop's main hall.
"I come here very often because they stock a wide range of books and they don't discriminate against readers who just want to read," says Robin Wang, a recent graduate from a local university.
She says she came to the store twice a week during her years in the university.
"A good bookshop should provide space, vision and nurture the city with its humanitarian spirit," says Qian. "It's a place for people to have dreams in the city."
As Chinese cities undergo rapid development, and e-books chip away at the market for traditional books, many independent book stores are facing financial difficulties across the country.
"Independent book shops represent the well being of the city," says Qian. "When a city is losing its bookshops, it's actually losing something in its soul."
Librairie Avant-Garde operates two other stores in Nanjing, including one inside the Presidential Palace. Its latest store is its first outside of Nanjing; it's located in the old town in Wuxi.
But it's the special car park location and design that's made the main shop a tourist landmark of the city.
"Librairie Avant-Garde has unintentionally become the city's tourist spot," says Qian. "Tourists come here to observe the culture of a city, to exchange cultures and it's also become a new meeting spot in Nanjing."
Librairie Avant-Garde, 173 Guangzhou lu (next to Wutaishan Stadium), Gulou District, Nanjing; +86 25 8371 1455; open daily from 10 a.m.-9 p.m.
CNN Travel's series often carries sponsorship originating from the countries and regions we profile. However, CNN retains full editorial control over all of its reports. Read the policy .
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
