<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 14:54:36 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Taliban: Malala still a target</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/07/world/asia/taliban-malala/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/07/world/asia/taliban-malala/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>The Pakistani Taliban would again target 16-year-old Malala Yousafzai, an advocate of education for girls who survived an assassination attempt last year, a spokesman told CNN on Monday.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 11:00:15 EDT</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Taliban says it would again target Malala Yousafzai, who pushed girls' education
By David Simpson, CNN
October 7, 2013 -- Updated 1225 GMT (2025 HKT)
Malala Yousafzai, the 16-year-old Pakistani advocate for girls education who was shot in 2012, is still a Taliban target.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
NEW: Malala tells BBC she wants to return to Pakistan someday, and run for office
Taliban spokesman: the attack on the teenager was about propaganda against Taliban
Malala survived the shooting and spoke at the United Nations on her 16th birthday
She had resisted a Taliban order against girls in schools in Swat Valley
(CNN) -- The Pakistani Taliban would again target 16-year-old Malala Yousafzai , an advocate of education for girls who survived an assassination attempt last year, a spokesman for the militant group told CNN on Monday.
Spokesman Shahidullah Shahid said the teenager was targeted because she was used in propaganda against the Taliban.
The Taliban would target her again if given the chance, he said, just as it would target anyone who opposes the group.
He denied she was targeted for promoting education for girls.
Taliban pen letter to Malala
Malala Yousafzai wins children's peace prize
Malala asks women to fight for rights
Malala was 15 when gunmen jumped onto her school bus in Pakistan's Swat Valley on October 9, 2012, and shot her in the head. She survived and underwent brain surgery in Britain.
She recovered and addressed the United Nations in New York on her 16th birthday, July 12.
"They thought that the bullets would silence us, but they failed," she said. "And then, out of that silence, came thousands of voices."
The Taliban's actions sparked large protests in Pakistan and condemnation worldwide.
In a BBC interview published Monday, she said the Taliban are "misusing the name of Islam."
"Killing people, torturing people and flogging people ... it's totally against Islam," she said.
Taliban to Malala: Why we shot you
The Taliban banned girls from schools in the Swat Valley in 2009. Malala anonymously blogged for the BBC in opposition to that order and became an open advocate to girls' education, telling CNN in 2011, "I have the right of education. I have the right to play. I have the right to sing. I have the right to talk. I have the right to go to market. I have the right to speak up."
This year, the Malala Fund has been created to support education for girls around the world.
Malala's name has been mentioned in speculation about the Nobel Peace Prize, due to be announced Friday. Her memoir, "I am Malala," will be published Tuesday. And On October 18, she is expected attend a "Youth, Education and the Commonwealth" reception hosted by Queen Elizabeth at Buckingham Palace.
In the BBC interview, she said she wants to return to Pakistan someday and continue her fight.
"I will be a politician in my future," the told the BBC. "I want to change the future of my country and I want to make education compulsory."
Malala at U.N.: The Taliban failed to silence us
CNN's Max Foster contributed to this report.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
