<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 14:54:36 EDT</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Team out when 'live capture failed'</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/07/world/africa/us-forces-africa-terrorist-raids/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/10/07/world/africa/us-forces-africa-terrorist-raids/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>U.S. Navy SEAL Team Six pulled out during a raid to capture suspected Al-Shabaab leader Ikrima when it became clear that he couldn't be taken alive, a senior U.S. official told CNN.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 13:11:57 EDT</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Official: Navy SEAL team pulled out when it couldn't capture suspect alive
From Barbara Starr and Holly Yan, CNN
October 7, 2013 -- Updated 1837 GMT (0237 HKT)
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
NEW: Somalia's foreign minister says the country approved the U.S. raid
Commander decided to withdraw after an intense firefight, senior U.S. official says
The U.S. Navy SEAL team's mission was to capture Ikrima arrive
That's why the team was used instead of a drone, the official says
(CNN) -- U.S. Navy SEAL Team Six pulled out during a raid in Somalia to capture suspected Al-Shabaab leader Ikrima when it became clear that he couldn't be taken alive, a senior U.S. official told CNN.
"Their mission was to capture him. Once it became clear we were not going to able to take him, the Navy commander made the decision to withdraw," said the official, who has direct knowledge of the entire Somalia operation but declined to be identified publicly.
The official said the SEALs faced heavy opposition and an intense firefight broke out, leading to the withdrawal.
The mission's aim -- to capture Ikrima -- is the reason the team went in rather than using a drone to attack the heavily guarded seaside villa, the official said.
Somalia approved the U.S. raid, Somali Deputy Prime Minister Fawzia Yusuf Adam told CNN's Christiane Amanpour Monday.
"We accepted it; we welcomed it," said Adam, who is also the country's foreign minister.
It was one of two U.S. military operations in Africa over the weekend targeting what officials called high-value terrorism suspects.
In the other raid, members of the elite U.S. Army Delta Force captured Abu Anas al Libi, an al Qaeda operative wanted for his alleged role in the deadly 1998 bombings of two U.S. embassies in Africa.
U.S. target in Somalia: An inside story on an Al-Shabaab commander
Next stop, New York?
The special forces took al Libi to a U.S. Navy warship after his capture, a U.S. official said.
The Pentagon said the U.S. military was holding al Libi in a "secure location" outside Libya. There, a team of officials from the FBI, the CIA and other intelligence agencies are grilling him for intelligence on al Qaeda.
His next stop could be the United States, where authorities have long wanted al Libi to stand trial in an American court for his alleged role in the embassy bombings in Kenya and Tanzania that left over 200 dead and thousands wounded.
The Libyan interim government called the U.S. capture a kidnapping and wants an explanation from Washington, the country's state news agency reported Sunday. There's no extradition treaty between Libya and the United States.
Opinion: Good thing U.S. terrorist hunters weren't furloughed
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry disputes that. He described al Libi as a key al Qaeda figure who is a "legal and an appropriate target."
Kerry said Monday that al Libi "will now have an opportunity to defend himself and to be appropriately brought to justice in a court of law."
A federal grand jury in New York has already indicted al Libi for the embassy attacks.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
